Chapter 1: One Small Thing

"ON THE LONGEST DAY OF THE THOUSANDTH YEAR, THE STARS WILL AID IN HER ESCAPE, AND SHE WILL BRING ABOUT NIGHTTIME ETERNAL"

Prophecy spoken by Anstice Trelawney near the newly constructed Hogwarts School for Witchcraft and Wizardry, December 21, 992 C.E.

Somewhere
April 16 1992

Hermione Jean Granger was dead.

Or at least, she reasoned that she was dead.

She last remembered drawing in a breath and whispering to Harry, "Not your fault." She exhaled, and closed her eyes, and distantly heard his voice say, "Don't do this." But she did, and now she was here.

Where was here?

Her legs were chewed off by a troll. It was terribly painful at first, but once she began losing enough blood, the shock overrode the physical pain, and she knew she was going to die. And now she was dead. There really wasn't any other rational explanation.

She was alone now, cut off the world, devoid of sensory perception, a singular consciousness simply existing, capable of one thing, and one thing only: thinking.

I think, therefore I am.

She was thinking, therefore she was. But simply being is not the same as being alive, at least in the sense that she was used to thinking about things.

She tried to think what Harry would do in a situation like this. Science. He would do science, of course. Step 1: Form a hypothesis. Step 2: Do an experiment to test your hypothesis.

The problem was, how exactly does one go about falsifying theories like, "I'm in the afterlife" or "I'm just having a bad dream"?

She supposed she could falsify the Dream theory by never waking up? But she didn't want to not wake up. She could imagine Harry's somber face reminding her that reality was indifferent, that her wants would have no bearing on the results of the experiment. But she wasn't so sure that was the case in this world. This world was hers, this world was her.

She had the nagging feeling that, if she so chose, she could simply fade away into oblivion, abdicating her mind to a blissful eternity of nothing. After all, her entire "self" only persisted through the active, conscious act of thought, which she could deliberately cease at any moment.

But she didn't want to, so she didn't.

Instead, she decided to do bad science. Her new hypothesis was, "I am NOT in a dream." If she could do something that she could only do in a dream, she would falsify that hypothesis, and therefore prove that she was in fact, dreaming.

She was fairly certain that science didn't actually work like that, but she didn't have any better ideas at the moment.

She thought about the few times she had lucid dreams. What was it like? She could see, hear, feel, smell, taste… There was a world, albeit one of her own making, to interact with. It may have been a paper-thin veneer of a world, but it was a world nonetheless. This, on the other hand, was emptiness. It was nothing.

If she was dreaming, she could make something out of nothing, and so she tried. She thought about a ball. Just a simple toy ball, to start with. At first, she considered it too abstractly, she was envisioning the concept of "ball", and got nowhere. She tried again. This time, she tried to actually visualize what this specific ball would look like in reality. She defined its size, its color, its material. She imagined it close up, what it would have felt like if she had a sense of touch, the smell of the rubber against her fingers, the sound it made as she ran her hands across it. She fixed those values in her mind.

This was her ball. Baby steps, she told herself.

She now tried to think about the ball in relation to another object: a floor. A simple, floor of polished metal with no detail besides its preternaturally smooth surface. How would the ball interact with the floor if she, for example, dropped it? What about if she bounced the ball? She played over various scenarios in her head, sketching out in excruciating detail the behavior of the ball.

After nine or ten different scenarios, she noticed something interesting. She was the one playing with the ball. Her. Without even deliberately trying to, she was imagining herself, her own mind giving herself Form without conscious direction. The form had no details, it was just an edgeless mass of shadows, but it was unmistakably her.

She looked down. She now had a persistent form in this world: fractal black shadows, roiling and twisting, undefined and yet concrete. This was her, and she held her ball, and she was bouncing it against her floor.

Baby steps, indeed. So, she thought to herself. This is a dream, after a fashion.

But a dream of what? Her brain had ceased to function, presumably. And the patterns of information that made up her identity, those patterns were represented by a physical brain when she was alive. That brain took those patterns and gave them weight and meaning and a means of interacting with other patterns, and it was still. Lifeless and fading.

But her brain was simply the medium. Her brain was not her. When she was in school before Hogwarts, one of her maths professors had scrawled the first seven or so iterations of the Fibonacci sequence upon the blackboard. When he eventually erased the writing, that did not remove the Fibonacci Sequence from reality. Once established, the Sequence would persist, iterating on into the infinite, regardless of whether some professor manifested those iterations on a blackboard, even if no one was there to observe it.

She figured that this was the case with her; she was simply a pattern of information. An enormously complex, self-referential pattern that happened to be aware of itself, but she was a pattern nonetheless. Once established, that pattern would persist, iterating on into the infinite, regardless of whether some collection of protein and fat manifested those iterations in the world or not, even if no one was there to observe her, besides herself.

It was a reasonable enough explanation, although at the moment she hadn't the slightest idea how she might go about testing that particular hypothesis. But it didn't really matter much, did it? If her theory was wrong, it was wrong, but there was nothing to lose.

Now that the had a vague concept of how things might work, she needed a plan. She knew what she wanted: she wanted to return to the real world, to go back to being a flesh and blood girl, to see her friends, her family, her teachers again. She also knew that she had a friend in that real world who would likely stop at nothing to make that happen.

She had heard Harry talk ad nauseam about cryonics, the science of freezing a body upon death in order to preserve the brain until a future era in which it would be possible to reconstruct the damage caused by death and restore someone to the world of the living. She had seen the wisdom of his suggestions, but had never quite gotten around to having the "Hey mum and dad, I want you to freeze my corpse if I die" conversation.

She suspected that Harry would likely take matters into his own hands. He had once sought her assistance in learning the Glacius charm, a third-year spell. He never told her why, and she never asked, although she had her guess, which was most likely accurate.

It would be completely in character for Harry to steal her body, freeze it, and then stash it away somewhere. He probably had a walk-in freezer somewhere in the depths of the extended space in his trunk, procured specifically for this purpose. She wondered how he would provide it with power, since it wasn't like Hogwarts had an electrical outlet anywhere. She recalled from the instruction manual of her parents' chest freezer that it used around 400 kilowatt hours.

She did the quick mental math. 2,000 kilocalories a day was what an average person consumed. At four thousand joules per kilocalorie, that was 8 million joules per day. Watts were joules divided by seconds, and there were 86,400 seconds in a day, so that was a little bit less than 100 watts. Multiply that by 24 hours in a day by 365 days in a year and you had more than enough power to run a freezer.

She wondered how many calories a house elf consumed?

She noted that, as her conscious mind focused on this digression, she could "see" abstract representations out of the corners of her "vision". As she was thinking, she witnessed herself crawling into her chest freezer to see if it had enough space; she observed Harry eating toast just to make sure he actually consumed calories like a normal person; she watched, bemused, as a woebegone house elf pedaled laboriously away at a bicycle generator.

Whenever she tried to focus on these abstract visions, they flitted away as easily as they came to her. But she found that if she gave them weight, specificity, deliberate boundaries and identities, they would persist.

Harry had told her once that if there was an outlandish solution to a problem that required little to no effort, you may as well try it, on the off chance that it would actually work. If it didn't, well, then you haven't really lost much. It was for this reason that Harry had pledged allegiance to the deities of a hundred or so gods of various, mentioning that he was willing to bet thirty seconds of his life on Pascal's Wager, and that was it.

So, she built herself a Harry.

He stood before her. She studied its face. It was a formless mass, devoid of specific details, and yet she knew it was him. It was like looking at the night sky, how you could see the stars clearly from the corners of your vision but when you tried to look at them directly, they faded into darkness. When it spoke, it sounded like Harry, at least when he was saying things she remembered him saying in the past.

It didn't reply when she asked it if it was alive. She tried to think what Harry would say if that same question was asked of him. The simulacrum replied in a voice that wasn't-quite-Harry's: "I certainly feel alive, but that doesn't really say much, does it?"

She decided to try carrying on a conversation with her not-Harry, filling in what she thought the real Harry would say. "Am I dead?" She asked it.

The concept of FROWN splashed across its face. "Yes, but I'm working on fixing that."

"Do you think you'll succeed?"

"Yes. Eventually."

"So, is there an easy way out? Is there some pathway you can you lead me down that ends in a door that I can open and walk back out into the real world?"

It considered for a moment. "You're trying the outlandish solution aren't you?"

She smiled. "Of course."

"Well, I applaud you on that, but I don't think that will work. After all, you know this isn't really me. It's just your expectations of what I might do or say. You'd have to be able to contain two whole brains worth of information in your one brain for it to really be me, and that seems like a contradiction in terms. It's interesting that I'm the avatar for your inner monologue when it comes to science-y type things. It's not weird, I don't think. I told you once that I have simulations of lots of my friends in my head. If I think something might be unethical or wrong, I try to ask my not-Hermione what she would do."

As it spoke on, its voice sounded less like Harry, and more like Hermione trying to speak in Harry's voice.

Oh well, it was worth a shot.

Instead, she thought back over the multitude of books she had read, trying to think of any magicks capable of translating dreams back into reality. One particular entry came to mind, "Extremities of Particular Importance" by Alexander Phaethon. It detailed the history and descriptions of several magical locations and artifacts, many of which were considered little more than myth. The depth and breadth of its research led many to consider it a sequel of sorts to "A History of Magic", including Bathilda Bagshot herself. However, many others were left unsatisfied by its frequent forays into the world of unfamiliar mythology and the fantastic.

One of those fantastic places it described was the dreamscape of Tír inna n-Óc. Chapter twenty, page four-thirty-six, her near-photographic memory helpfully provided:

"The town of Ipswich often claims to be Britain's oldest town, since it is known that the community has persisted unbroken since the early seventh century. The wizarding world knows better – Diagon Alley is the oldest continuous community in Britain, surviving since the fourth century before Christ, when it began as a single cottage built by a Greek wizard, a wanderer who had abandoned his century-long journey in search of the legendary Cup of Midnight in order to create a home in this distant land of savages. In one shape or another Diagon has existed ever since, rebuilding homes and shops as needed. It is because of this antiquity that, when Merlin wrought the stone of the Wizengamot and made himself the leader of the magical world, he did so in London. He may have also been honouring the long-ago Greeks who brought wands and high magic to Britain for the first time, although he said nothing of this.

Tír inna n-Óc is older.

That fact no longer means much, truth be told. Tír inna n-Óc was woven from nightmare before Ελαολογος even left in pursuit of the Cup of Midnight, and by the time that Cup was broken in the tenth century – woe be upon the breaker of that precious cup! – the hellscape of Tír inna n-Óc had already been abandoned by the Tuath and the Unseelie, and no creature called it home.

The realm persisted, regardless. It had been crafted from the horror-dreams of nameless beasts of the sea, creatures no longer known to man or wizard that lie still and breathe salt and do not die, and Tír inna n-Óc would endure as long as they."

It further explained that the place transcended physicality and could be accessed from anywhere on the planet using a dark ritual that had, unfortunately, been lost to time. She decided that if the dreams of these nameless eldritch horrors could be used to build an alternate plane of existence, then so could hers.

And so it was that she set about the task of building the kingdom of her dreams.

The Forbidden Forest
June 3rd, 1992

Harry had checked the books, had learned that since he was too young to have sexual thoughts he would be able to approach a unicorn without fear. The same books had said nothing about unicorns being smart. Harry had already noticed that every intelligent magical species was at least partially humanoid, from merfolk to centaurs to giants, from elves to goblins to veela. All had essentially humanlike emotions, many were known to interbreed with humans. Harry had already reasoned out that magic didn't create new intelligence but just changed the shape of genetically human beings. Unicorns were equinoid, were not even partially humanoid, didn't talk, used no tools, they were almost certainly just magical horses. If it was right to eat a cow to feed yourself for a day, then it had to be right to drink a unicorn's blood in order to stave off death for weeks. You couldn't have it both ways.

So Harry had gone into the Forbidden Forest wearing his Cloak. He had searched the Grove of Unicorns until he saw her, a proud creature with a pure white coat and violet hair, with three blue blotches on her flank. Harry had gone over, and the sapphire eyes had stared at him inquisitively. Harry had tapped out the sequence 1-2-3 on the ground several times with his shoes. The unicorn had shown no sign of responding in kind. Harry had reached over, taken her hoof in his hand, and tapped the same sequence with the unicorn's hoof. The unicorn had only looked at him curiously.
And something about feeding the unicorn the sleeping-potion-laced sugar cubes had still felt like murder. At least, it would have, if not for the curious barking noise.

He looked up from his grim work, trying to identify the source of the noise in the dark. It seemed to come from a ways off in the distance, and something about the high pitched, wheezy noise suggested that its source would not pose much of a physical threat. It wasn't a low, rumbling sound that Harry might have expected from a large dog, nor was it an aggressive growl. It sounded frightened, possibly even wounded.

The thought crossed Harry's mind that whatever had wounded the dog could easily do the same, if not worse, to him. But upon logical consideration, (combined with a fair bit of wishful thinking), Harry concluded that the non-sapient creatures that lived within the Forbidden Forest would never actually harm a student. Dumbledore would know that the Forest was a honeypot even more enticing than the third-floor corridor. Harry was quite certain that there would be beasts that were frightening, creatures that may threaten harm. But to actually follow through? As insane as Dumbledore was, he still valued the safety and well-being of his students.

At that particular thought, Harry felt a brief twinge of dark anger, but quickly suppressed it, and resumed his task with renewed resolve.

He had almost put the sound out of his mind until it returned, this time more insistent, and troublingly, closer. Aware that he was likely projecting intent where there was none, Harry thought that the bark carried with it hints of anger and frustration in addition to fear.

Warning signs that he had trained himself not to ignore began flashing in the back of his thoughts. He may have been safe from the creatures in the forest, or so he hoped, but his experience with the centaur served as a stark reminder that intelligent beings lurked within those woods. What if the incessant barking drew their attention? Harry was far from sure that he could rely on another deus ex machina from Professor Quirrell; it was due to his failing health that Harry was even here in the first place.

Even if harm did not come to him, it would be quite inconvenient if he were to be caught hunched over the body of an almost-dead unicorn. Although his justification was reasonable, he doubted that others would see things as he did. His anger began to creep back up as he imagined himself arguing with well-meaning idiots, pointing out the hypocrisy of their carnivorism and being met with looks of consternation.

The noise roused him from his angry thoughts, close enough now to where Harry realized he had to make a decision. He silently cursed himself as he acknowledged that he should have been thinking of a plan this entire time rather than reassuring himself that he was safe. He decided, rather impromptu, to simply hide and observe. He removed his broomstick from his pouch and placed it between his legs, ready to mount in the event he needed to beat a hasty retreat.

In a few short moments, the creature emerged into the clearing, and immediately began frantically barking upon seeing the collapsed body of the unicorn. It was, as Harry suspected, a dog, but one of the oddest dogs he had ever seen. It was small, no bigger than a Pekingese, mind you, and its fur was a pale violet, with green ears a tuft of darker green hair on the top of its head. It wore a darker purple spiked collar around its neck, and there was a clearly visible tag attached to the collar. Harry could see from the distance that the tag was embossed with an image of a heart, but couldn't discern if there was writing or not.

Either way, the implication was clear: this was someone, or something's pet. And judging by its reaction to seeing the almost-dead unicorn, Harry had an idea of whose it might have been. The implications of this had Harry feeling suddenly ill.

The dog let out a mournful, wailing howl, and loped over to the unicorn, pawing at her flank, sniffing around her ears. Tentatively, it poked the side of her face with its snout, and began howling again in earnest. It collapsed against her, curling into the crook of her neck and whimpering softly.

The unicorn's leg jerked slightly, immediately silencing the whimpers and moans, and the dog excitedly jumped up and paced around, unsure of what to do. It paused momentarily, then stiffened slightly as if it had an idea, and ran to the unicorn's snout, putting his ear against it. After a few short moments, it excitedly leaped into the air and shouted.

"HERE! She's over here!"

Harry blinked.

He had brief flashes of his "Snakes are sentient?" moment, but reminded himself that people don't eat dogs, or at least people in his culture don't. He considered the possibility that humans were waging systematic genocide and slavery against an entire sentient species. His inner Slytherin drowned out the other voices that began to come to life, shouting, "You won't be able to do anything about it if you're killed or thrown in jail, you prat!"

That seemed to do the trick, and Harry snapped out of his moment of contemplation to focus on the problem at hand. He could now hear voices, human voices from far off in the distance, but not the direction of the castle.

It was time to leave. Now.

He adjusted his footing in order to hop onto his broom, and as he did so, he stepped on an exceptionally poorly placed and inconveniently brittle fallen tree branch, which broke the silence with a resounding SNAP.

Immediately, the dog's head snapped up in the direction of the noise, stared straight at Harry, and began to charge.

Crap.

Harry fumbled with the broom, forcing it between his legs, but before he could launch, the dog was upon him, gripping the corner of the invisibility cloak in its teeth and ripping it from him, revealing all of Harry's head and most of his torso.

The remainder of the cloak was pinned between Harry's legs and the broomstick. As Harry tried to rise into the air, the broom pitched upward as he struggled to free the cloak from the curiously strong grip of the dog's jaws. The dog clamped down resolutely upon the fabric, stepping slowly backwards, dragging the broom backward in midair along with him.

Harry's mind raced. If he shrugged off his Cloak of Invisibility, he would free himself and could escape to safety. But it was his quest item, and he really didn't want to lose it. Besides, there were no guarantees that he would even escape if he were to free his broom. And what if this dog-who-talks could be reasoned with?

Harry was about to come up with yet another brilliant rationalization for not leaving behind his Cloak when the decision was made for him: with a resounding SMACK, someone had crashed into him in a flying leap, knocking him from his broomstick to the ground.

"What'd you do with her, egghead?"

He was pinned down a witch who looked to be no older than a teenager, maybe a fifth or sixth year? She had short-cropped hair that he could have sworn was rainbow in color, and was wearing a jean jacket over her school skirt. Harry breathed out a sigh of relief; an angry student was, objectively, loads better than an angry centaur. She did not seem to appreciate his apparent relief, and shouted again.

"Answer me! Say something!"

"Uhmmm… What did I do with who?" Harry stammered.

"Our friend, dummy!" The girl shouted.

He had suspected as much. He hadn't considered that the unicorn may have been someone's pet. It seemed a bit of a stretch to call it a "friend", but he knew other people tended to be much fonder of animals than himself, so he didn't press the point. "I'm sorry. I didn't realize. I really didn't."

"Didn't realize what? What did you do to her?"

Harry didn't think now was the best time to mention that he fed the unicorn poisoned sugar-cubes, nor that he intended to eventually have its sweet, life-giving blood drained and consumed in what he could only assume was a ghastly ritual, unpleasant to behold. So instead, he said something that was true from a certain point of view: "I… I put her under an enchantment. In order to keep her safe."

At this, the dog, who had been lurking back a few paces and was now closer to the unicorn than Harry, perked his ears up and spoke. "What do you mean, keep her safe?"

As the dog spoke, Harry could hear other students making their way through the woods, although oddly enough, they weren't coming from the direction of Hogwarts. As he squinted through the darkness to try to make out their forms, the dog spoke again.

"Hey! You! What were you keeping her safe from?"

This one was easy enough for Harry to answer truthfully, "Something in this forest has been killing unicorns and eating them."

At this, the rainbow-haired girl and the dog exchanged dark, knowing glances, and the witch spoke. "Yeah… we know."

She stood up, still above him but no longer pinning him to the ground. As she did, several more students emerged into the clearing. It was three more witches, all around the same age as the rainbow-haired one. He was immediately stricken by their odd choices of wardrobes and hair colors. The first into the clearing was a blonde witch wearing boots and a cowboy hat, who immediately ran over to the unicorn upon seeing her and kneeled down.

The second to emerge had hot pink, curly hair and wore a ruffled skirt colored a similarly intense shade of pink. She didn't seem to walk so much as bounce, and she seemed more interested in Harry than she did the unicorn. "OoooooooOOOOooo. You look like us!" she squealed as she peered down, wide-eyed over him.

Lastly, a timid-looking witch with pale pink hair and a blue dress emblazoned with butterflies peeked out from behind a tree, looking like she would rather be almost anywhere in the world besides a dark, scary forest populated with unicorn-eating monsters.

The girl standing over him looked to her friend in the cowboy hat. "We caught him casting a spell on her. Says he was trying to protect her, protect her from some kind of monster that's eating unicorns," she indicated down to Harry with one hand.

"Well, I'll be hogtied," the witch in the cowboy hat drawled. She had a curious accent; it reminded Harry of the female detective in an American movie his father had taken him to see last summer, The Silence of the Lambs, much to the consternation of his mother when she found out. The accent stood out to him then because he had never heard anything like it before, and it stood out to him now.

The girl with the pale pink hair shivered a bit and spoke in a voice barely louder than a whisper, "You don't think the monster is anywhere near here, do you?"

Harry spoke up, louder than he probably should have. "No, it's not. The last time I saw him, I… well, I scared it off." At this, the rainbow-haired girl and the bouncy pink witch who had been staring at him both seemed impressed.

"So, what's this enchantment you put on her?" the rainbow one asked.

"It put her to sleep. It's not permanent."

"Well, take it off, then!" she demanded.

Harry wasn't sure that a Finite would actually do anything against the effects of a potion, but he figured he may as well give it a shot. Rainbow Witch, which Harry had begun to call her in his mind, stepped off of him, and he stood up, brushing branches off of his robes before pointing his wand at the unicorn.

"Finite Incatatem!"

The unicorn's equine features began to melt away into those of a human female with pale white skin and purple hair. Harry suddenly felt the urge to vomit.

His eyes grew wide as he consider just how incredibly short-sighted and stupid his tests for sapience had been. Tapping 1-2-3? That's it? Because she failed to ape his pattern, he was prepared to drug her and present her almost-dead body to Professor Quirrell to feast upon. He wasn't sure which thought scared him more, the fact that he almost took part in murder, or what Professor Quirrell's reaction would have been upon drinking the blood of a transfigured Animagus instead of a unicorn. Either way, he vowed to be much, much more careful about this sort of thing in the future.

"She probably should get taken to a healer, just to be safe…" Harry started.

"Are there any nearby?" Scaredy-Cat asked. In absence of knowing their actual names, he had assigned them nicknames. In addition to "Rainbow Witch", he had nicknamed the timid one "Scaredy-Cat", the blonde witch "Clarice", and the pink one "Pinky".

Harry was a bit confused by her question. "Closer than the hospital wing? I doubt it… The centaurs might have one, but I don't think they're particularly keen on helping me out right now. I can bring her there on my broom, I think that would probably be fastest. You all can find your way out, right?"

"I'm coming with you, then!" the talking dog yelled.

Amidst fearing for his life and his momentary moral crisis, Harry had totally forgotten about the purple-and-green dog. Given that the girl he had poisoned was obviously an Animagus, the fact that the dog could speak like a human suddenly made a lot more sense.

"You should be small enough in that form for me to carry you. Are you an Animagus, too?" Harry asked.

"No, I'm a dragon!" the dog replied in an indignant tone that Harry mistook for sarcasm.

"Sure. Just, don't transform while we're up in the air, okay?"

At those words, Rainbow Witch's eyes immediately snapped up. "Did you say, 'up in the air'?"

Harry looked at her, curiously. He swung a leg over his broom and kicked off the ground, hovering a few feet over the forest floor to demonstrate. Rainbow Witch's jaw dropped.

"That. Is. AWESOME! Where can I get one?" She demanded.

"Jeez, you're acting like you've never seen a broomstick before… Look, just, meet me at the hospital wing and we can talk about it then. Will one of you help me get her," he indicated with his head towards the unconscious, purple-haired girl, "up on the broom?"

With a dull POP of an Appartion, yet another newcomer appeared in the clearing. Harry almost fell off his broom at the site of… whatever it was. At first, Harry though it was some kind of Satyr, as it stood on two legs and had the head of a horse. But upon closer inspection, he saw it had deer antlers, the arm of a lion, a lizard's leg, the claw of an eagle and the leg of a goat. It also had something that looked like a unicorn horn on the top of his head, and mismatched wings.

"Now you wait just a hot moment," the creature demanded.

Harry had immediately shifted into a defensive position on his broom, ready to fire a curse at a moment's notice.

"Oh, come now, little one. What are you going to do, curse me with that fish?"

Harry's eyes darted back and forth as the wand in his hand had apparently transformed into a small haddock.

"Who, or what, are you?"

"Why, the elemental spirit of Chaos, of course! Pleased to meet you, my general."

Harry said nothing, staring back, nonplussed.

"Of course, I go by other names as well. Shiggoth of the Spire? Aforgomon? Yog-Sothoth, Lurker at the Threshold? He who knows the gate, he who is the gate? The key and guardian of the gate? Ringing any bells at all? No?" The creature sighed dramatically. "You summon me from across the multiverse and this is the welcome I receive?"

Harry was again nonplussed. "Summon? Don't tell me that 'shuffle duffle muzzle muff' is actually a real incantation." At those words, the creature threw its hands up defensively and shrieked. Indignant, Harry asked, "Are you serious?"

"No, I'm Peter Pettigrew!" The creature waited for a reaction. "Nothing? Is this thing on?" It tapped on a microphone that was not in its hands a moment earlier. "Gee, tough crowd. No, I'm not being serious. That was just a ridiculous rhyme. Anyway, I suppose you can just call me Discord."

"Okay, Discord. What… what do you want?" Harry wasn't sure what he was supposed to say.

"The same as you, I'm sure."

Harry let out a humorless chuckle, "I highly doubt that."

"I'm here to help out a friend," Discord declared.

Rainbow Witch scoffed, and rolled her eyes. "Uh huh."

"Oh Dashie, you wound me to my core," Discord turned to her. "As it so happens, I heard of your little predicament. Your little bookworm friend got in above her head, now she's gone, and you're trying to find her and bring her back. I'm going to help."

"How?" Rainbow Witch and Harry both asked in unison, and then briefly glanced at each other, somewhat confused.

"Well, sadly, we creatures of god-like powers have certain silly little rules we have to abide by, especially when we're in other realms like this one. I cannot interfere directly. So don't go expecting any deus ex machinas at the end of your little story. In fact, I don't think I can interfere at all. Sorry, chum." He placed one of his paws on Harry's shoulders as if to illustrate, and it passed through him as if he, (or Harry) was little more than air.

Clarice spoke up, hands on her fists, "It doesn't sound like you're being honest with us, here."

"Et tu, Jackie? Well, I have to admit, I'm not acting completely altruistically, there's something in it for me." Discord conceded.

"Uh huh, that's what I figured." Clarice replied, and they all stared at Discord expectantly. Discord put a single talon to his chin, stroking his goatee while leaning over and examining Harry intently.

"How much do you know about Heat Death?"

Harry was taken off-guard by the question. He suddenly was much more interested in what this "Discord" thing had to say. "More than most, but not as much as I'd like. Why?"

"You might say it's the opposite of chaos when you think about it, isn't it? Everything in perfect, pristine equilibrium? It all sounds terribly dull. Fortunately for me, the so-called laws of physics are just optional guidelines, and with a little hard work and elbow grease, I could probably get things moving again, but it would take a really, really, reaaaaaaallllllllly long time." Discord emphasized.

"You're saying you could single-handedly reverse the heat-death of the universe." Harry said, flatly. "How long are we talking here?"

"What's the biggest number you can think of?"

"Um, three to the power of… three to the third power of three, to the power of itself?"

Discord paused for a moment, apparently working out the math in his head. "Yes, that seems suitably absurdly high. Let's say that many years, give or take. Not that I mind the work, of course. I'm nothing, if not hard-working." At that, it was Clarice's turn to scoff, "Never mind her. No, what I'm not particularly looking forward to, as much as it pains me to admit it in front of them, is making new friends. I rather like the ones I have."

At that, Scaredy-Cat Apparated into his arm, and he mussed her hair with his knuckles. Judging by the perturbed look on her face, Harry did not think she Apparated herself willingly. Nonetheless, she gave Discord a weak smile. "Well, we like you, too."

"Speak for yourself…" Rainbow Witch muttered under her breath. Scaredy-Cat gave her a withering glare, and she begrudgingly conceded, "Yeah… We like him."

"This is crazy." Harry's checklist of things-to-do-using-the-newfound-science-of-magic included, near the very bottom, figuring out how to circumvent the inevitable accumulation of entropy, so it was at least nice to know he had a resource he could consult in that department. But there were a lot of steps between here and there. "So how DO you plan to help?"

"Oh, it's not going to be me that helps you. Really, these girls are going to do most of the hard work. I'm just going to kick things off, so to speak, like a Greek chorus delivering the Prologue. You see, as you may have guessed, we're not from here, and these girls will need a place to stay."

With a flourish, and a puff of smoke, a massive woman stood in place of where Discord had been not moments earlier. She was a handsome, olive-skinned older woman, wearing black satin dress robes. She was the tallest person he had ever seen, taller even than Hagrid, though not nearly as wide.

He… or she, rather, leaned down into a low bow. Even when her head was perfectly level with her torso, she was still taller than Harry. "Madame Olympe Maxime, charmed, I'm sure." Discord spoke in the voice of the woman, with an exaggerated French accent that bordered on comical. "I shall tell zee 'eadmaster, Dumbly-dorr, zat we are visiting students from Beauxbatons. I 'ave, of course, seen to it zat zee true 'eadmistress of Beauxbatons will be blissfully unaware of my impersonation,"

Pinky giggled and clapped her hands together. "You sound so cultured!"

"Now of course, zese 'orrible outfits of yours simply will not do." Discord snapped her fingers, and the witches were suddenly clad in identical periwinkle dresses, shawls and sleeves, and each had a matching hat sitting at a jaunty angle atop their heads. Fortunately, Harry could still tell them apart by their hair color, if not their mannerisms.

"And of course, names, we will need names. 'Oo would believe you to be students with those ridiculous names of yours? You!" Discord snapped her fingers at Rainbow Witch. "What shall we call you?"

"Uh… Manebow… Smash?"

Discord turned to the other witches in turn, snapping his fingers at each.

"Maudileena!" Pinky giggled, clapping her hands. "This is exciting! We're like spies!"

Clarice stammered when put on the spot, trying to think of a name that would sound normal, whatever that meant. "Babs?"

Scaredy-Cat looked down and kicked at the dirt lightly with her toe while she spoke in barely more than a whisper, "Jane?"

Discord considered this for a second. "'Orrible. Zey are all 'orrible names, except for yours, of course," she nodded at Scaredy-Cat. "Tisiphone, Megaera, Alecto," he pointed at Rainbow Witch, Clarice and Pinky, respectively. "Zat is what we shall call you."

"Tisiph-i-what?" Rainbow Witch cried, indignantly. "Those names aren't any better than ours."

"Oh, I think you will find them more than appropriate, my little 'umans. Now come. You, zee chosen one, 'op along on your little broom and fly to zee 'ospital."

"What about me? What's my name going to be?" The purple dog piped up.

"Ah, but you are used to being an afterthought, no? We shall simply call you Spike."

Spike wasn't sure if this was an insult or not, but didn't want to waste any time. He loped over to where Harry was floating on his broom, and Harry lowered himself enough so that Spike could hop into his arms, and then nuzzled up to the unconscious body slumped over the broom.

As Harry raised himself up, he paused for a moment. "I know that beggars can't be choosers… but you mentioned something about helping me bring back Hermione?"

"I said nussing of zee sort, 'Arry Potter."

Harry frowned. "You said you were going to help me find my 'bookworm friend'."

"Oh, silly boy. I was talking about zee uzzer bookworm friend, ZEIR bookworm friend." At that, Discord's voice changed back to its original rather than that of a French cartoon. "What a delightfully unlikely and totally not-intentional misunderstanding!" Discord tittered, and then resumed the French accent. "I only told you I would help you stop zee eternal night."

Harry rolled his eyes. "Right. Well, like I said, beggars can't be choosers. See you all back at the castle. It's that way," he pointed, and launched upward as Tisiphone stared longingly.

"So… awesome…" she whispered under her breath.

"'E is taking zis all in stride, don't you sink?" Discord asked, as he watched Harry fly away into the distance.

"Well, if he can help us find Twilight, then I don't really give two darn toots how he takes things," Clarice, now called Megaera, muttered.

"Yes, zat is the spirit! Now come, we have an 'eadmaster to meet!"

Chapter 2: Reflections

CHORUS:

Oh, I'm all alone now No love to shield me

Trapped in a world That's a distorted reality

Happiness you took from me

And left me alone With only memories

SHADOW:

How lucky am I to have something that makes saying goodbye so hard?

"Sunlight and Shadow", by S. Leigh, as staged in the 1981 Diagon Alley Production

Sometime

It had been days. It had been weeks. It had been years. The flow of time, without a fixed point of reference, had little meaning.

She had deduced a few things by this point. When she was alive, Harry had recommended that she read a book by an American professor entitled Gödel, Escher, Bach. It was long, it was obtuse, but it was a book, nonetheless. It took roughly four read-throughs before she was relatively confident that she had the majority of it memorized.

When she "read" the book now, it appeared precisely as her mind remembered it. There was no way of independently confirming whether the wording was exact, whether she misplaced a preposition here or there or swapped out one synonym for another. Her mind simply decided on a value, filled it in, and that was that. She mulled over a particular passage from page 3 of the preface:

The Gödelian strange loop that arises in formal systems in mathematics (i.e. collections of rules for churning out an endless series of mathematical truths solely by mechanical symbol-shunting without any regard to meanings or ideas hidden in the shapes being manipulated) is a loop that allows such a system to "perceive itself", to talk about itself, to become "self-aware", and in a sense it would not be going too far to say that by virtue of having such a loop, a formal system acquires a soul.

She was quite certain of her original theory, that her mind was nothing more than a formal system, a collection of rules and data for churning out an endless series of output solely by symbol-shunting. Both her past and present consciousness was tangible face-value evidence that this formal system had looped upon itself and was capable of self-perception, talking about itself, becoming self-aware, and ipso facto, having a soul. That formal system being physically manifest gave her "soul" a means of interacting with other similar patterns, but it was not strictly necessary, just as how a blackboard was not strictly necessary for the Fibonacci sequence to exist in concept.

So she had deduced that she was an isolated strange loop, persisting on in a purely conceptual capacity, fated (or doomed) to continue persisting on forever. When she had come to that conclusion, she had despaired for a few brief moments, because it really did seem like quite a bleak future, not just for her, but for others as well, others who might not be able to entertain themselves as effectively as she could.

But she quickly came to another conclusion based on one simple observation: she still remembered. She remembered quite clearly the chain of events leading from her death until the present moment. The end result of her exile could not be mere oblivion, due to the simple fact that she was present, remembering, conscious after a fashion. If that were a possible end to this scenario, why would she be remembering now?

She was also quite certain that the end result of this was not eternity, either. Although it needed no outside input to function, per se, her mind as-is was a finite structure with a finite data set upon which could be operated with a fixed set of rules. If she persisted long enough, something had to give. Regardless of how efficiently she could write memories, at some point, there was a hard stop. As of the present moment, she had clearly not overwritten the memories of her own death, nor had she done so with her initial exploration of this conceptual afterlife.

At that moment, she decided that she never would. She committed herself to the following course of action: if that time ever came, if she continued to fall and reached that sudden stop, she would not overwrite these memories. She would not overwrite any memories. She would remember.

She produced an empty book with an arbitrarily large number of pages, and on the cover scrawled the title: "The Diary of Hermione Granger", and began writing down her thoughts as she could remember them.

"It had been days. It had been weeks. It has been years. The flow of time, without a fixed point of reference, has little meaning.

I have deduced a few things by this point. When I was alive, Harry recommended that I read a book by an American professor...

...

...

...

...and I began writing down my thoughts as I can remember them.

By committing myself so, my internment here has only two possible ends: escape, or oblivion.

And since I already know that it cannot end in oblivion, there is only one realistic possibility to consider.

I am going to escape.

And I have a pretty good idea of who is going to help me."

May 13, 1992

"Diffindo!" Harry had aimed at a branch this time, and it plummeted to the ground with a sound of twigs and leaves.

There didn't seem to be any tears inside him, only pressure with no outlet.

"I shall leave you to it," Professor Quirrell said quietly. The Defense Professor rose from his tree stump, the unicorn's blood still moonlit on the black cloak he wore and drew his hood back over his head. He began back to where he had left the unicorn in a state of near-death. It had not died in the drinking, Harry's interference had seen to that. Quirrell had torn a large chunk from its side, carefully choosing the location so as to present the best possibility of incapacitating the beast without killing it.

He reached the rotten log against which he had left the unicorn. Good news, bad news, good news. Good news: the unicorn was still alive. Bad news: the unicorn was no longer where he had left it. Good news: there was a telltale trail of blood smeared across the ground, leading twenty or thirty meters in the direction of the castle. Smiling, Quirrell followed the trail, and found the unicorn, laboriously dragging its broken body across the ground, trying in vain (but trying nonetheless) to escape.

"So nice to see you again, my little unicorn." Quirrell grinned wickedly. The unicorn stopped and turned up towards him, staring at him with dark black eyes run through with flecks of purple around the edges. Its mane was thoroughly disheveled, and for a moment it appeared that human blood was running down its scalp, but Quirrell realized that this was nothing more than its natural color: there was a shock of red hair through its tail and mane.

The unicorn watched him, expectantly, and tears began to well in its large, sorrowful eyes. Quirrell was quite sure that they were tears, as he was not one to project human emotion onto anything, much less a magically modified horse. It stood up, defiantly, on four shaking legs, and looked up into the air as Quirrell approached it. It closed its eyes, and without warning, the air around its horn began to shimmer, matter coalescing from the ether into a single dot.

Heart quickening. Wand out. Ready.

The dot expanded, like an ice crystal forming suddenly in water, and built itself into the form of a tiara of sorts. It was golden, studded with nine blue gemstones along its face. Atop the tiara was finely wrought gold wiring crafted into an ornate design, holding in place a large blood-red gemstone cut into the shape of a six-pointed star.

Quirrell had already built six varieties of shields, not only around himself, but around the unicorn in the event it tried to run, charge, or attack. He prepared the ground around the creature with an enchantment that would transform the dirt into a quagmire of living roots, ready to release his magic at a moment's notice to complete the spell.

The unicorn opened its mouth, and to Quirrell's surprise, it began to speak. "You are here... The one who will tear apart the very stars in heaven. You are here... you are the end of the world." When it finished, its eyes began to fill with brilliant white light, so bright that it illuminated the clearing and beyond, casting harsh black shadows as the light hit the trees.

And just as quickly as it started, the light winked out and the unicorn dropped to the ground, the tiara clattering away near Quirrell's feet.

Quirrell's own rule nineteen stated that one should never simply sit and watch as an enemy begins to charge their ultimate attack, and so he acted accordingly. He would need to have a little conversation with this creature. Of course, it meant that he could not kill it, which meant he would need to find another unicorn upon which to feast, but that could be easily arranged.

He walked around the fallen tiara, making sure not to brush against it, as Rule twenty-two stated that one should never touch, wear, attempt to use, or otherwise meaningfully interact with an unknown magical object until its function has been identified with a reasonable degree of certainty. He approached the unconscious body of the unicorn and quickly Transfigured it into a small, violet pebble, and dropped it into his pocket, mentally adding it to the list of Transfigurations he was required to maintain.

He then turned his attention towards the tiara, thoroughly examining it without touching. It emanated a palpable magic power, and so he was hesitant to draw too close without casting the proper oracular charms. However, the writing on the inside of the tiara drew enough of his interest to merit a closer inspection. Given the non-zero chance that the object would react to magically-produced light, he decided that mundane fire would be a better tool for this particular task. He took a small stick from the ground and drew from his pockets two objects: a box of waterproof matches and a small tub of pitch. He stuck some of the pitch on the end of the stick, lit it with the match, and held it close to the tiara to read the writing.

Oon whit biyonde mesure is menn's gretest þresur.

Well, wasn't that just something?

He had known that the Sword of Gryffindor could present itself to a worthy Gryffindor in a moment of dire need, having witnessed that very phenomenon himself not a few short weeks ago. He also knew that Slytherin's Monster would obey the command of any worthy Slytherin if the circumstance arose, and was living proof of that fact. So it wasn't unreasonable to assume that the Diadem of Ravenclaw could also present itself to a worthy Ravenclaw given the proper situation.

Given the absence of other theories, he began to consider the implications of this one. If this were the Diadem of Ravenclaw presenting itself to a Ravenclaw, then this unicorn must be a Ravenclaw. Which obviously meant that this was not a unicorn, but an Animagus, which also explained how the creature could talk. Among available theories, the advantage is given to one that is both plausible and explains multiple mysteries at once.

He would soon find out what this creature knew of the prophecy, along with the circumstances enabling it to summon the Diadem of Ravenclaw, which had never in recorded history presented itself to a Ravenclaw (which was not altogether unsurprising, given the penchant for Ravenclaws for risk-aversion). He may have to delay his plans for a few days, but that was no matter. Information about the prophecy was of greater importance than any single aspect of his plan.

As long as Potter's friend remained dead, he would stay at Hogwarts until they physically removed him from the premises. The stone was going nowhere, and Quirrell was capable of mounting a distraction that would temporarily require the Headmaster's presence. Once the Headmaster was gone, Quirrell needed only to blackmail, threaten, or convince Potter to accompany him to the Mirror. Once the stone was retrieved, he simply needed to give the boy sufficient motivation and opportunity to make an attempt on Quirrell's life, his true life, in order to break the protections preventing Quirrell from killing the boy. Given that the boy was sentimental, reckless, and staggeringly naive, this would not be a particularly difficult task.

He briefly considered the fact that he felt the telltale signs of functional unicorn blood as he had consumed it earlier that night. If terminating an Animagus transformation counted as "dying" for the purpose of utilizing the life-extending properties of unicorn's blood, it could be a very useful fallback option in the event that his plans did not unfold in the manner of his choosing. He added that to his mental list of "things to try on a disposable minion", and spent a moment to examine the Diadem.

"Ra eset", he whispered, casting a standard oracular charm that had a spectacularly low chance of negative interaction. The structure of the spells infusing the Diadem began to unfold themselves, revealing the general thrusts of its function. He poked and prodded at the abstract blobs of color that were laid out in front of him. Interesting, very interesting. It seemed to match the descriptions of lore: it isolated a certain mental quality within the wearer, and built upon it, expanding exponentially outward, using the wearer's own magic to power the expansion. So it couldn't work on Muggles, and it couldn't work on animals...

...or could it?

Credible legend had suggested that Salazar Slytherin had used the Crown of Serpents in order to grant snakes a measure of sapience in order to bestow the Parselmouth Curse upon himself and his descendants. It was not out of the question that the Diadem of Ravenclaw could grant a similar degree of intelligence to magical creatures, sufficient intelligence, for example, to allow a unicorn to talk. If that were the case, then this creature could be a true unicorn rather than an Animagus. It would certainly explain why he had felt the true effects of the consumption of unicorn blood, but it did not explain how the Diadem would have presented itself to the beast.

No matter. He would solve that riddle soon enough. Either way, he was completely confident that whatever the effects of the Diadem, they were not negative. Dark magic left traces, and this object was pristine. Gingerly, he took the Diadem and placed it upon his head.

Nothing.

It was entirely possible that the object could not be unlocked except by a Ravenclaw, or perhaps required the solving of a riddle of some kind. If the former, this could prove useful if he needed to enhance the Potter boy, although that would be a dangerous gambit and not one he would use unless as a last resort. If it did happen to be the latter, the problem did not need to be solved now. Besides, Potter was alone in the Forbidden Forest, and he could no longer hear the sounds of trees being torn apart. If the Professor knew the boy well enough, he probably had found himself in some kind of trouble by now and needed a deus ex machina to extricate him from his dilemma.

He placed the Diadem into his robes and set off in the direction of where he had left the boy.

June 4, 1992

Once he had seen to the safety of Girl-Who-Used-To-Be-A-Unicorn-But-Now-Was-Unconscious-In-The-Hospital-Wing, for lack of a better name, was safe, the growing list of questions in his head had reached critical mass, and each new question forced old ones out of his mind. There were questions of mere curiosity, like where they came from and why they were here, and how they even got here. He had theories that he was seeking confirmation for, like thinking the Girl-Who-Used-To-Be... No, Purple Hair. Purple Hair it was. Like thinking Purple Hair was an Animagus, or perhaps a Metamorphmagus.

But mostly he was curious about Discord, and his claims of nigh-omnipotence. It wasn't often that a giant "Easy Button" plopped directly into one's lap, even in the magical world (considering that Magic was basically one big "Easy Button" unto itself). So far, Discord hadn't actually done anything that was outside the realm of possibility established by the existing magical rules with which Harry was familiar. He appeared out of nowhere, but that could be easily explained by Apparition. His initial form was that of a dragon-goat-snake-lizard-horse-whatever hybrid, and then he effortlessly transformed into a massive woman that he could only assume was half-giant or something. But that too could be relatively easily explained if he was a Metamorphmagus. He turned Harry's wand temporarily into a fish, had forcibly transported the pink-haired witch into his arms, and had transformed all of their clothes into new, matching uniforms.

Wordless, wandless transfiguration, non-self-Apparition and summoning? It was all possible, but each observation required a separate, discrete, unlikely explanation. He had heard that house elves possessed such magic, but he had always assumed that their temperament was a bit less... dramatic and ostentatious. Even if the explanation was relatively mundane, it was still worth exploring what was possible. He would be kicking himself if he found out years from now that this creature could have just snapped his claws and resurrected the dead if only Harry had asked, but the window of opportunity had closed and now Hermione was gone forever.

He had asked around the castle for more information about where these five guests were residing for the time being. The response from the students was universally useless, with the boys giving him knowing winks and nudges, assuring him that they too were very interested in the answer to that question, before conversing among themselves as to which of the witches they wanted to "meet" first. And the girls rolled their eyes and gave chilly responses, inquiring pointedly why he seemed to care so much about those witches with the ridiculous hair, like having rainbow streaks or pink hair made them oh-so-cool or something because what was wrong with the girls here at Hogwarts?!

Useless. All of them.

The teachers were similarly worthless, giving him a reassuring smile and assuring him that he'd find out soon enough, but that he really, really didn't want to miss dinner tonight. It had occurred to Harry at that moment that he had been skipping dinner... and, well, lunch and sometimes breakfast several times a week recently. Now that he thought about it, he was pretty hungry.

The secrets of the universe would have to wait until dinnertime, apparently.

As he found a spot in the Great Hall, he saw that the tables were uncharacteristically devoid of food. He noticed a few surprised glances from other students directed his way.

"Yeah, yeah, I know, I know. I'm hungry today," he remarked, to no one in particular.

He sat down and looked around the Great Hall as students filed in and sat down. The Defense Professor was absent, as expected, and Dumbledore was nowhere to be seen. Harry braced himself for whatever suitably dramatic entrance had been prepared. As if on cue, all the torches in the Great Hall extinguished and were replaced with flames of a brilliant blue roughly the same shade as the witches' new uniforms. The students collectively gasped and began chattering among themselves excitedly.

"Greetings, students, teachers, and newcomers alike," boomed the voice of the Headmaster, who had apparently entered and walked up to his podium in the din of excitement. "I have received word last night that we have a sextuplet of visitors from our sister school, Beauxbatons!"

Polite applause mixed with stifled giggles from some of the older Gryffindor boys. Dumbledore raised an eyebrow at them in a silent "Really?", and resumed.

"May I present to you, Headmistress of Beauxbatons, and the fine witches of Beauxbatons Academy of Magic!"

The door to the Great Hall opened, and Discord-Slash-Half-Giant-Headmistress walked imperiously down the aisle towards the podium, with the four witches in tow. Rainbow Witch and Pinky regarded the spectacle with excitement, whereas Clarice seemed quite skeptical. Scaredy-Cat, as expected, clung as close as possible to the false Headmistress and kept her eyes fixedly forward.

When they reached the front, Dumbledore extended his hand to Discord, who politely declined. She whispered to him in a sidebar, "I am sorry, Dumbly-dorr, but one of our students has contracted an 'orrible case of zee Draconequus Pox, so she shall not be joining us. I fear as 'zo I may have also come down with an 'int of zee illness myself, and I would 'ate to pass 'ziss terrible ailment on to you, 'eadmaster."

Dumbledore smiled politely, "I think you'll find it will take a bit more than an aggressive case of Dragon Pox to keep me from taking part in the festivities, but I agree that it would be best to avoid an epidemic," and lowered himself into a dramatic bow, to which she responded with an awkward curtsy. He turned and addressed the crowd.

"As is our custom, students who wish to stay in Hogwarts as more than guests must be Sorted according to Hogwarts' values, so that they will be allowed entrance into the various common rooms. And so, without further ado, would you do the honors, Professor McGonagall?"

She gave him a curt nod, and from behind the Professor's Table, she withdrew an old patchwork hat, which despite being an inanimate object, looked thoroughly displeased to be here. She walked out from behind the table and stood next to Dumbledore, who casually flicked his wand and produced a cushioned stool from thin air. Harry couldn't help but notice it looked decidedly more comfortable than the stool that he and his classmates had sat upon.

With a swift motion, McGonagall pulled a small length of parchment from her robes and cleared her throat.

"When I call your name, you will come forth, I shall place the Sorting Hat on your head, and you will be sorted into your houses. Tisiphone Erinys!"

No one moved. The four witches looked around awkwardly until Rainbow Witch caught sight of Madame Maxime giving her a withering death glare. "Oh! Yeah, that's me!" She bound quickly over to the stool, and sat down, unsure of what to do. McGonagall placed the hat upon her head, and the crowd in the hall went silent.

"Hmmmm..." The fold in the hat split open as it began to speak. "Hmm...difficult, very difficult. Plenty of courage I see, not a bad mind, either. There's talent, oh yes, and a thirst to prove yourself. But where to put you? You could be great, you know. It's all here in your head. And Slytherin will help you on your way to greatness! There's no doubt about that! No? Well...better be...GRYFFINDOR!"

Rainbow Witch shrugged as the Gryffindor table erupted into applause. Judging by some of the high fives going around, several of the Gryffindor boys were quite pleased. She sat down next to the Weasley twins, who both commented in unison: "Nice hair."

"Uh, yeah, you too! So, um, which one of you is the real one?"

Without missing a beat, they both replied in unison, "He is."

"You know, my friend had a similar problem. We put all of her into a room and Twi- I mean, one of my other friends did this test to see which one was real. I kinda got bored after the first ten minutes, but the whole thing worked. I think."

"If you believe Professor McGonagall, two of us is two too many," Fred remarked.

"And if you catch her on a bad day, she even says two of us is three too many." George deadpanned.

Rainbow Witch laughed a bit, "You guys are all right."

They were interrupted by Professor McGonagall loudly clearing her throat again, "Mr. Weasley and Mr. Weasley, you will have plenty of time to charm and subsequently disappoint this young witch over the next week, so I see no reason to further interrupt this ceremony. Megaera Erinys!"

Clarice hopped up and trotted up to the stool, and waited as the hat was placed upon her blonde hair. She looked up, expectantly as it spoke. "Hmmm... Another Apple, eh? I know just what to do with you! HUFFLEPUFF!"

She smiled, leapt down from the stool, and walked towards the cheering table of students in the black and yellow robes. As she passed by, the portly Professor Sprout leaned over to her and spoke, "We're the House of the honest, hard-working, and loyal, you know!" Clarice beamed at that.

"Sounds right up my alley!"

Harry found Professor Sprout's tone somewhat odd; it was almost perfunctory despite her beaming expression. He didn't have much time to think about it further, however, as Professor McGonagall wasted no time in announcing the next student's name, "Jane... Plein." She spoke the last name with the slightest hint of rising inflection, which by Professor McGonagall's standards was tantamount to dramatically rolling her eyes and declaring, "Seriously?"

Scaredy-Cat timidly approached the stool, looking around at the throngs of students eagerly eying her. McGonagall held the hat in her hands and began to place it down, but the moment the barest loose thread of the hat brushed against Scaredy-Cat's pale pink hair, it shouted at the top of its lungs: "SLYTHERIN!"

Scaredy-Cat clapped her hands together once, and in a small voice, no louder than a whisper, said, "Yay."

The entire Great Hall looked immensely skeptical, but perhaps none more so than Professor Snape and the whole of Slytherin House, who were tepidly applauding out of politeness rather than excitement. Draco caught Harry's eye from across the room, and Harry spread his arms in resignation and shrugged. Content, she walked over to an empty seat on the Slytherin table and sat down.

"And lastly... Alecto Erinys!" called Professor McGonagall, breaking the somewhat awkward silence. Pinky had her fists to her mouth, shaking with excited anticipation. When her name was called, she leapt out of her chair and squealed. She skipped up to the stool, plopped herself down, and immediately began asking the Hat questions.

"What do you think, Mr. Hat? I knew a Griffon once, but she was kind of a meanie. She didn't like pranks, not ONE BIT. I bet I would be good in Pufferstuff, I bet they like parties." She craned her head over to the Hufflepuff table and asked them directly, "Do you like parties? I LOVE parties!" The Hufflepuffs nodded and grinned, several of them laughing.

Professor McGonagall cleared her throat. "Ms. Erinys, I can assure you that the Hat will answer all of your questions. In silence."

Pinky gave her an exaggerated frown, and when the hat was placed on her head, she began thinking all of the questions that came to mind.

What's it like being a hat?

Do you eat?

Where does it go when you eat?

Do you like to eat?

Do you like to eat CAKE?

I love cake.

Oh wait, that wasn't a question.

Neither was that.

OH NO THINK OF A QUESTION WHATS A HEFFALUMP?

What house was that creepy boy in the forest sorted into?

What does he know about Twilight?

Do you think he likes to eat cake?

I wonder who likes to eat unicorns.

I made a unicorn cake once.

OH NO THAT WASN'T A QUEST-

Her inner voice was cut off by the Hat speaking in a slightly dazed voice. "Oh dear. This has never happened before."

Pinky's eyes went wide. "OOOooo. What?"

"Your voice..." the Sorting Hat managed weakly.

"What about it?"

"...has chased away all the sanity in me." As it continued, its voice rose in inflection, almost melodic.

Pinky touched the brim of the Hat as she looked upward at it. "That doesn't sound good."

The melody in the Hat's words became more pronounced. "These wounds won't seem to heal. This pain is just too real. There's just too much that Time cannot erase!" There was a brief pause, and then without warning, the old Hat's brim opened wide and it began crooning at the top of its non-existent lungs.

"WHEN YOU CRIED, I'D WIPE AWAY ALL OF YOUR TEARS!"

Pinky's eyes lit up. "OOOO! Are we singing now?" She clapped her hands together and began signing alongside the hat, albeit in a completely different rhythm and tune.

"Come on everybody, smile smile smile, fill my heart up with sunshine, sunshine!"

"WHEN YOU'D SCREAM, I'D FIGHT AWAY ALL OF YOUR FEARS!"

"All I really need's a smile, smile, smile!"

"I HELD YOUR HAND THROUGH ALL OF THESE YEARS!"

"For these happy friends of mine!"

"BUT YOU STILL HAVE ALL OF... Wait. No. Nope. NOPE. No more of this nonsense. RAVENCLAW!" The Hat shouted in terror.

The post-sorting Quietus charm had triggered, yet Pinky continued to sing silently, completely oblivious to this fact, her expression animated and joyful. The entire Hall was silent, looking at each other in bewildered disbelief. McGonagall was glaring, eyes narrowed, directly at Harry, who desperately and emphatically mouthed the words, "It wasn't me!" and was met with little more than a skeptical huff.

Dumbledore was smiling pleasantly, waving his wand like a conductor in time with the silent song that Pinky continued to belt out. Apparently, she was reaching the grand finale, because she stood up and threw her arms into the air and held a silent note for a solid five seconds before stopping, clapping her hands together and giggling manically. Dumbledore politely clapped for her, which the rest of the Great Hall mimicked, unsure of what else to do.

McGonagall briskly removed the hat from her head, and Pinky squealed, "Great job, Mr. Hat! We should do that again!"

Harry could have sworn he saw the hat desperately shake itself back and forth, as if to scream, "NO".

Chapter 3: I'll Be Your Mirror

"Pooh, when I'm -you know - when I'm not doing Nothing, will you come up here sometimes?"

"Just me?"

"Yes, Pooh."

"Will you be here too?"

"Yes, Pooh, I will be really. I promise I will be, Pooh."

"That's good," said Pooh.

"Pooh, promise you won't forget about me, ever. Not even when I'm a hundred."

Pooh thought for a little.

"How old shall I be then?"

"Ninety-nine."

Pooh nodded.

"I promise," he said.

Still with his eyes on the world Christopher Robin put out a hand and felt for Pooh's Paw.

"Pooh," said Christopher Robin earnestly, "if I - if I'm not quite -" he stopped and tried again - "Pooh, whatever happens, you will understand, won't you?"

"Understand what?"

"Oh, nothing. He laughed and jumped to his feet. "How lucky am I to have something that makes saying goodbye so hard?"

So they went off together. But wherever they go, and whatever happens to them on the way, in that enchanted place on the top of the Forest a little boy and his Bear will always be playing.

Hermione put down her book, "The House at Pooh Corner", by A.A. Milne. She was once again thankful for her almost-photographic memory, as it made it much easier to keep herself entertained. She had realized quite some time ago (although she was unsure if it was days, weeks, months or years) that the key to keeping herself sane was structure. She started her day off with building things. It was much easier than building something in real life; she simply thought it, and it was. The difficult part was the permanency. At the corners of her thoughts, she often saw flickers of grand structures, wisps of faces, hints of things she had seen before, but trying to hold onto them was like trying to grab smoke. It was only through conscious volition that she could commit the structures to memory, and with enough practice and detail, create something reproducible.

She used the metaphor of the physical act of creation to aid her in this process, like a complex mnemonic device. It forced her to focus on the reality of the objects she was working with, how they fit together with each other. Of course, she skipped over the mundane, because things just worked. When she had laid down the polished wooden flooring of her library earlier that day, the beams just fit into place and stayed there. She didn't need to concern herself with every single minute detail of construction, only the ones necessary to complete the abstraction. As she laid each beam in place, she forced herself to focus on that beam's spatial relationship with the rest of the room, committing it to memory as best as possible.

What had begun as a single featureless room had expanded into a house, which had grown into a palace. Many of the rooms were empty shells, placeholders with no permanency beyond the size and shape of their boundaries, and even then, those were mutable. She had initially dedicated a rather large section of the first floor to a grand ballroom, and it occurred to her shortly thereafter that she was not expecting guests anytime soon.

Once she was done with her building for the day, she would begin studying. Her subjects were unfortunately limited: the social sciences were purely worthless, and the physical sciences were of little use beyond purely theoretical applications. She was not accomplished enough of a physicist, chemist, or biologist to recreate reality with even the remotest degree of fidelity. So she mostly focused on maths and logic, two things that did not require the laws of physics as a prerequisite. She worked with the information she had learned from her studies in the non-Magical educational system, and although that wasn't best-in-the-world level by any stretch, she still counted herself as lucky. After all, she was handed on a silver platter mathematical equations, theories, principles and concepts that it had taken her forebears decades if not centuries or millennia to derive.

Even still, there was much that she was not taught and was forced to reverse engineer, a process that was at times painstaking. She remembered quite clearly the feeling of giddy excitement when she discovered that rate of change of the function "y=x^2" was equal to "2x", and that she could apply a similar transformation to find the areas of even higher-order exponentials. She was not, of course, arrogant enough to believe that she was alone in this discovery, especially given how quickly she was able to come to it. But she was also not well-studied enough to know that this was nothing more than basic Calculus 101.

When she tired of studying, she would then move to more creative pursuits. She found that she quite enjoyed painting. She painted places she knew, places she had read about, places she imagined. She was a master of light and shadow, of form and space, crafting photorealistic dreamscapes of otherworldly beauty. She conveyed the beauty and emotion of life through the rich violence of detail. Even in her abstract works, there was violence; her thoughts flung paint across the canvas of her mind in angry splotches, a silent rebellion against the chains that held her. She lovingly hung each work in its proper place in the gallery that she had constructed and often visited for inspiration.

Finally, at the end of her day, she would re-read her journal, write of the day's events, and then retire to her impossibly comfy chair to read a few chapters of whatever book had come to mind. She was not quite sure why she had chosen Winnie the Pooh, but chose it she had, and had finished the entire book before it was time to sleep.

Hermione dreamed, which in and of itself was not odd. One's mind, regardless of physical instantiation, could not keep going at a dead run forever. It needed time to catch up with itself, to process what it had experienced. The first time this occurred, she had not even noticed the encroachment of her subconscious; she simply found it increasingly difficult to force her volition upon the world. She became easily distracted by the sights and sounds that crawled out of the corners of her mind, watching in wonderment as they moved about seemingly with minds of their own.

The process of beginning to dream was much more seamless than when she was alive and constantly inundated by a stream of outside input. She simply stopped trying to consciously direct the action and instead observed what her subconscious had to offer. Oftentimes it provided inspiration for her conscious mind, synthesizing new ideas from unique permutations of existing concepts. Other times it unlocked doors that she had forgotten existed, doors she was able to then enter and explore. But most of the time, it was simply soothing mental white noise that relaxed her until she decided she was ready to begin her routine anew.

What was odd about today was that she was dreaming someone else's dream. She first noticed the peace. It was all wrong. She knew her own mind intimately. It was a constant vortex of activity, conscious or no. A swirling miasma of thoughts, a Pollock in conceptual form. But this was calm. Measured. Thick, bold lines, serene swaths of uniform color, pleasant to behold, but not at all a reflection of the life or reality she knew. It was childlike, innocent, serene. The voices that floated from in between the pools of color and sharp dividing lines were not echoing fugues, voices layered upon voices in endlessly rising canons. They were words, simple, pure words, and that was so quite unlike her.

The disorientation was so profound that she had difficulty following; she was not used to experiencing input in this fashion. She stared into a mirror, a golden, inviolate oval, observing the twisted reflection of her thoughts. As she searched for herself in the reflection, she saw dark, roiling shadows coalescing. Almost pure black, just like her own form, but with a subtle undercurrent of a deep twilight violet. She knew beyond any doubt that what was staring at her from within the mirror was not her own reflection. For the first time since she had arrived here, she was truly frightened, because whatever it was that stood within the mirror stared back at her, and spoke.

"Who... who are you?"

June 5, 1992

Harry had been lurking outside the kitchens for quite some time, ignoring the suspicious glances of students and professors as they walked by. He was waiting for someone who could answer his question. He had tried asking a few professors where "Madame Maxime" had taken up residence but had received nothing more than blank shrugs. Hogwarts was a large place, with far more rooms and quarters than seemed strictly necessary for its current size. It wasn't until somewhere around lunchtime that the doors opened and a diminutive house elf wearing a faded pastel toga emerged from the door carrying a platter of steamed vegetables.

"Um, excuse me. Pardon me, sir? May I ask you a question?"

The house elf froze and stared at Harry, wide-eyed. It looked up at him, and Harry could see its eyes trace slowly upwards from his face to the top of his hairline. Harry braced for the inevitable, and the elf's wide bulbous eyes began to fill with tears.

"You wouldn't be... Harry Potter?" It asked in a high-pitched croak.

"Yes, I would. Would you mind answering a quick question I have?"

The elf began to blubber loudly. "'Sir'! The great and honorable Harry Potter has called Posey 'sir'! I have heard tales of your generosity and kindness but never before has Posey been called 'sir' by a wizard!" It fell to its knees, the platter clattering to the floor. At the noise, a handful of other house elves appeared and began to clean up the mess, regarding Harry with a mixture of curiosity and fear. The elf turned to one of its companions, "That is the wise and sage-like Harry Potter! And he... he called Posey 'sir'!" and promptly began wailing again.

One of the other house elves whispered to Harry, "But Master Potter, Posey is not a 'sir', she is a 'ma'am.'", and Harry quickly rectified his mistake.

"I'm sorry, ma'am. Posey, would you mind answering a question or two?"

Posey began sobbing with renewed gusto, barely managing words between the gasping wails. "The benevolence! The kindness! Never before in Posey's life could I imagine to be called 'Sir' or 'Ma'am'!" She ran forward and gave Harry a gangly hug, before noticing Harry's wide eyes. Worried that she may have been overstepping her bounds, she quickly separated herself, falling to her knees and kissing the hems of Harry's robes. "Sorry, Master Potter. A thousand apologies, please forgive Posey's familiar manner. I did not mean to offend such a noble and honorable wizard!"

"No, no, Posey, it's okay. Jeez, wizards must not treat you with very much respect..." He muttered. Fat tears again began to fall from her eyes as she shook her head weakly. "No, please, don't start crying again. Posey, I just had a few questions for you."

"Anything for you, King Potter, the One Who Lived And Shall Rule The Stars in Both Heaven And Earth!"

Harry felt that was a bit dramatic, but ignored it. "Do you happen to know where Madame Maxime, the visiting Headmistress of Beauxbatons is residing?"

Posey looked excited. "Yes, yes sir, I do. On the seventh floor corridor, do you know the place?"

Harry frowned. "Not well, but I can find it. Where on the seventh floor?"

"There is a portrait of Barnabas the Barmy, training trolls for the ballet. Across the hall from that portrait is the door, but..." She lowered her voice to a whisper. "Please make sure you are looking for Madame Maxime and nothing else!"

"Thank you, Posey. May I ask another question or two of you?"

"Of course, Kindly One."

"House elves... What kind of magic can you do? For example, can you transfigure yourself into a different form, make yourself look like something different?"

Posey considered the question, unsure how best to answer. "Not since before the days of Merlin could the fae perform glamours, sir."

"What do you mean?"

"When the wise, the powerful Merlin locked away the darkest secrets of Magic, he also locked away many of our powers as well. Not that Posey is complaining, sir. Posey rather likes how she looks."

Harry thought back to the Dungeons and Dragons manuals he used to read as a child. "These glamours... Could your ancestors turn themselves into anything they wanted?"

"Oh, no sir. We're elves, not wizards. We could change our appearance, but no more. We could not grow, nor shrink."

"Were your ancestors taller? Like, taller than me? As tall, as, say, Madame Maxime?"

"No, sir. As big as Posey, they were."

Hm, well there went that theory. "Okay, well, thank you very much, Posey. You've been very helpful."

Posey swept into a low bow, her nose almost touching the floor. "Yes, Master Potter. Anything for the One With The Power to Defeat the Dark Lord!" Posey's bow was interrupted by the steadily increasing stream of house elves flowing from the kitchen, one of whom had handed her a replacement tray for the one she had dropped. "Pardon me, sir, but Posey must be going now, it is lunchtime. But I would be glad to help you further, simply ask for me within the castle."

"Yes, I will. Thank you again."

Harry made his way across the castle up to the seventh floor, his mind distracted by other thoughts as he idly scanned the portraits until he found the one he sought. The wall across from it was empty, so Harry walked up and down the corridor again, peeking into doors and finding nothing but empty classrooms and supply closets. Frustrated by the inaccurate directions, he went back to the portrait to confirm he was looking at the right one. There really could be no mistaking it: eight trolls wearing garish pink tutus arranged around a single wizard, who looked terribly frightened. He furrowed his brow in concentration, remembering Posey's instructions.

They were fairly straightforward, and yet, here he was with nothing to show. He considered calling her again but was surprised as he turned around to see a door across from him that he must have overlooked during his first walkthrough. The door was cracked open slightly, and he could sound, from inside. He peered into the crack, and saw Discord in his original form, laying down on a rug in front of a fire. He was playing with a pair of dolls, having them dance with each other while humming and singing a little tune.

"Doo do dee doo, jumping on, the train that goes to the Kingdom, de do dum de do de do dum, be doo be doo imagination..."

Harry knocked tentatively upon the door, and Discord jumped up, tossing the dolls into the fire and feigning embarrassment. "Why, you snooping little so-and-so!"

"Hello, Discord."

"To what do I owe this dubious pleasure?"

"Well, we never really got a chance to talk after we first met. I had some questions for you. Well, a lot, actually."

Discord folded its mismatched arms behind its head and stretched back into a chair that did not seem to be there moments before. "I figured you might. What did you want to know, you curious little kitten? You know what they say about curiosity though..."

"For starters, what ARE you?"

Discord grinned. "You really swing for the fences, don't you? I'm the original General Chaos, the primordial embodiment of randomness. I was here before the beginning and I'll be here after the end. It's really quite lonely, you know. I have my brothers and sisters of course, but they're always busy. And of course, Destruction decided to go off and retire a few hundred years ago..."

Harry's initial reaction was disbelief, but he quickly checked himself. He didn't want to be one of those daft protagonists in a fish-out-of-water fantasy story that sees a thousand and one magical phenomena but then decides to be doggedly skeptical about one particular subset of observations, causing all sorts of contrived problems along the way. After all, was this really that much more unbelievable than the creation of pure mass-energy out of nothingness? Or the violation of every possible law of thermodynamics Harry could conceive of? "Okay, so we'll say your some kind of God. What kinds of powers do you have?"

"Here? Not much. See, look. Catch!" Discord detached one of his claws and tossed it at Harry without warning. Surprised, Harry held up his hands to receive it, but the claw passed right through him and clattered to the ground. "I can't really do a thing here. Your world is far too orderly for that, you've practically disproved my entire existence. In a decade or two, I bet I won't even be able to come here at all."

Harry considered this. "So you're one of those, 'the more you believe in me, the more power I have' type deities?"

"Oh no, nothing so simplistic. I'm more of a... hmm." Discord stroked his chin thoughtfully. "A shared hallucination, you might say."

"But you transformed my wand into a fish! And you changed those girls' clothes into those Beauxbatons uniforms!"

Discord held his hands together in mock innocence, and a glowing halo appeared above his head. "Me? I did nothing of the sort! You only thought your wand was a fish. And they were wearing those uniforms all along."

Harry stared at him. "No, they weren't."

Discord chuckled. "Prove it!" Harry stammered, trying to come up with an explanation for the type of fallacy that Discord was currently engaging in, but Discord continued before Harry could reply. "Your minds are so delightfully malleable. It's like shooting wands in a barrel."

"So, I guess that answers my next question," Harry replied, disappointed. He waited for Discord to ask what the question was, but it never came.

After a brief beat of silence, Discord finally spoke. "Oh, you were waiting for me to play my role. One moment, please!" Discord twirled around, and when he completed the revolution, he was wearing an all-black outfit, comprised of pants, a turtleneck, and a beret. He was holding a human skull in his hand, and spoke to it, dramatically. "Alas, poor Yorick, I knew him well... Oh, wait, wrong play. Let me try again." He threw the skull aside and asked Harry with all the false earnestness he could muster. "Whatever could your question have been, o' disappointed one?"

Harry rolled his eyes. "I suppose you can't bring people back from wherever they go when they die, can you?"

"Of course I can!"

Silence.

Crackle.

Fizz.

Pop.

Harry's next words were measured, because although sometimes things were this easy, usually they weren't. "So, what's the catch?"

"Catch? Me? You act like I'm some kind of trickster God and I've just given you a magical monkey's paw that grants you wishes that will inevitably backfire despite following the exact wording of your wish! Although..." Discord pondered briefly and produced a desiccated paw out of nothingness. "That does sound like the sort of thing I would do. Here!" He tossed the paw to Harry, who didn't bother to try to catch it, and it passed through him. "Oh, yes, sorry. I forgot. Well, who would you like me to resurrect?"

"Yeah, it definitely sounds like there's a catch, here."

Discord folded his arms. "You were the one who asked! Besides, now you've got me excited. I want to show off my talents. I'm nothing if not an incorrigible showboat."

"Um, fine. How about, I don't know..." He thought of the first dead positive role model that came to mind. "Nelson Mandela?"

"Hm... Mandela... Mandela..." Discord produced a large book and oversized pencil and began leafing through the pages. "K... K... L... L... Madras... Madrigal... Manetti... Ah, here we are. Mandela, Nelson. South Africa. Died in prison a year or two ago, no?"

Harry nodded. "That's the one."

Discord flipped the pencil on its end, erased something from the book, and scribbled something in its place, and then showed the book to Harry.

Nelson Rolihlahla Mandela, born 18 July 1918, was a South African anti-apartheid revolutionary, political leader, and philanthropist, who-

The next words were the ones that had been erased, and were replaced with sloppy handwriting that read:

-most certainly did not die in prison in 1990 and is still living a happy, healthy life."

"See?" Discord spoke. "Not dead!"

Harry sighed. "Great. Really helpful."

"No, really. It says so right here in this encyclopedia." Discord shoved the book closer, and Harry looked at the top of the page: Discordpedia, the free* encyclopedia.

"Let me see that." Harry reached for the book, but his hands passed through it. Despite this, the book turned its pages of its own accord to the section that Harry was going to try to find: an entry labelled "Potter, Harry James".

Harry James Potter (b. 31 July 1980) is a half-blood wizard, one of the most famous wizards of modern times. He is the only child and son of James and Lily Potter (née Evans), both members of the original Order of the Phoenix. He was raised by his Muggle aunt Petunia Dursley and her husband Vernon-

As he read, a large obtrusive page suddenly unfolded itself over the contents of the entry, containing a black-and-white glamour shot of Discord looking pensive. Bold, blue font implored: Please read: a personal appeal from Discordpedia founder, Discord.

"Hey! I was reading that!" Harry shouted, and reached for the book, but again, his hands could find no purchase. "Petunia Dursley? That's not her name-"

"You little peeping Tom, you! This is my private book! Besides, you have nothing to worry about, that's just some awful fan fiction written by some lonely woman on a train."

Dursley... Dursley... That name seemed so familiar.

Discord quickly shut the encyclopedia. "Anyway. I would try to bring back your friend Hermione Granger the same way, but I think you might not like the results. All sorts of time-space complications, you see. You and she would probably become friends with some dolt like Ronald Weasley who she'd end up marrying and having a whole brood of children with in order to escape the reality of her loveless marriage. Complicated stuff, messing with Time. I really hope I didn't break any continuity just now."

Discord reopened the encyclopedia and flipped through a few pages, scanning them carefully, and whispering to himself. "Q... R... S... Sandman... Sbarro's... Skip... 682." He paused, read the entry, and let out a relieved sigh. "Ah, phew." Satisfied, he tucked it back away from where it came. Meanwhile, Harry shuddered at the thought of "Hermione Jean Weasley".

"So, what are you here for, really?"

"I'm just here to watch the fireworks. I hear that you're supposed to have some climactic battle with He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named. It sounds titillating!"

Harry thought for a moment on how best to broach this subject. "Yeah, I kind of have my doubts about that. I have a pretty strong feeling that he's out of the picture. Besides, you can call him Voldemort."

Discord folded his hands together, thoughtfully. "You're right. I never liked 'He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named'. It's not a very credible threat, is it? Voldemort, Voldemort, Voldemort! See! Nothing wrong! You know, where I'm from, we have a real 'He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named'. A really wicked character, he created this awful basilisk that went around gobbling people up a little while back."

Harry cocked his eyebrow. "...are you sure we're not talking about the same person? Did this 'really wicked character' hide this monster in a hidden room? Perhaps, a 'chamber of secrets'?"

Discord burst out laughing. "My goodness, no. No, no, no. This isn't some silly snake-cum-book-of-living-knowledge. This was a real, honest-to-goodness memetic hazard. Even thinking about it would get you devoured. No one can say his name, otherwise, they'll get smitten from the face of the planet."

"Um, if that monster really works like you described, then that actually seems like a reasonable policy." But Harry paid attention to nagging note of confusion in the back of his mind. "But, then again, how are you thinking about it? I don't see you getting devoured."

"Because you silly goose. I am that monster!"

Harry took a step back. "What?!"

Discord looked very serious for a brief moment and then began laughing again, oversized tears pouring out of his eyes. "You should have seen your face! Ohhhh! I slay myself. Hoooo." He slapped his knee in an exaggerated manner. "Sorry. Couldn't help it. But seriously now. Do you really think such a thing could exist? How would that even work?"

"I, uh, don't think that's a-"

Discord then quickly thought better of himself and held a finger up to Harry's lips. "Shhhh. Now that I think about it, it's better you don't even try."

"That's exactly what I was going to say."

Discord nodded. "Good. Now let's change the subject before your mind inevitably wanders back and you end up accidentally creating a multiverse-ending destructive force."

Harry focused fixedly ahead on the crackling fire, willing himself not to think on the subject. "Okay, so what are your friends doing here?"

"You see, my old friends and your new friends are in a very similar predicament to you. If you just used that big ol' rational brain of yours, you could probably figure it out." Discord waited a few moments, while Harry stared blankly. "No? Nothing? Gee, do I have to explain everything?" He spoke with exaggerated slowness. "Your friend. Eaten by a troll. Their friend. Eaten by a morally ambiguous wizard. You like your friend. They like their friend. Get the picture?"

"...so Professor Quirrell killed one of their friends."

"It would appear so, wouldn't it? And he seemed like such a good guy, didn't he? Boy, I bet you feel like an idiot!"

Harry was immediately defensive. "He didn't know, obviously. I mean, I didn't know when I fed the purple-haired girl poison sugar cubes."

"No, no, of course not. At least you tried. After all, tapping 1,2,3 on the ground, a fool-proof test to see if a creature is intelligent."

Harry threw his arms out. "Yeah, yeah! I know! I've already vowed to be more cautious in the future."

Discord was nodding emphatically, "Oh I quite believe you. I'm sure your monomaniacal quest to end Death forever will result in no further unintended consequences. I mean, what could possibly go wrong now that you've vowed to be more cautious in the future?"

As Discord spoke, paper clips began flying out of the fire and pelting Harry in the head. Harry tried swatting them away, but after a few moments, they began gushing out in a torrent of tiny metal bits. "Can you stop?"

Discord snapped his claws, and the paper clips melted into a puddle of grey goo, which slowly filled the room to an inch deep in sludge. Harry noticed the fireplace belching out streams of the sludge, causing the level of liquid in the room to rise progressively faster. Discord noticed as well, "Hm, you probably should leave before this little problem gets out of hand."

Harry, however, was not ready to leave. "But what was the plan? You don't just barge into another world and... wait, how did you even get here in the first place?"

Discord looked down at the rising goo, which now was halfway up Harry's calves. "You really should make up your mind as to what questions you're asking. We came here through a portal, same way anyone travels through worlds. Honestly, I would have thought that much was obvious."

Harry tried to focus on what information he needed in the immediate short-term. "Fine. The plan. What was your plan."

"That's a better question. They planned to reunite the Elements of Harmony and use its world-bending magic to... do something? I'm not really sure, myself. Probably cross their fingers and hope that somehow its magic would do precisely what they needed it to do at that very moment. My guess is that it would make their eyes go all glowy and then their friend and yours would emerge in a glowing pool of light or something like that."

Harry's attention was slightly diverted to the disturbingly warm, tingly feeling of the goop, which had now risen up to his knees. "The Elements of Harmony? One, I've never heard of those, but that doesn't say much since I'm new to all of this. Two, what do they do? Three, what do you mean, you're not really sure what their plan is?"

Discord chuckled. "One, two and three: it doesn't matter because those silly old things are the king of all MacGuffins. I highly doubt that they function, much less are capable of resurrection, in this world. It saddens me to say that they're on a fool's errand." Discord didn't look sad at all.

Harry was getting exasperated. "So they're just... here? That doesn't make any sense!" He was practically shouting.

"No, they're not 'just here'" Discord spat, mockingly. "They're following the prophecies."

"The WHAT?"

"If you wanted to know about them, you should have asked sooner, silly! Now I'm afraid we don't have nearly enough time to go into all that detail." Despite being twice Harry's height, Discord was almost chest deep in the liquid. He held a drenched claw up to his chin and twirled his goatee as he looked up into the air. "Although I suppose you don't need to ask ME... After all, anyone about whom a prophecy is made can freely listen to it. They're all on record at the Ministry of Magic."

Harry was standing on his tip-toes now to keep his neck out of the sludge and was moving back towards the door. "And, what if the prophecy isn't made about you?"

"Oh, why, you'd need to Words of Power and Madness to unlock them! Too bad they were lost-"

"Seven centuries ago."

"That's right. Right around the time that the Philosopher's Stone was made. Coincidental, isn't it?"

Harry didn't understand in the slightest what the connection between the two-

Oh wait.

Who was it that was friends with Nicholas Flamel, the creator of the Philosopher's Stone and was likely hiding the Philosopher's Stone here at Hogwarts?

Who was it that made a joke at Harry's expense about the "Words of Power and Madness"?

Who was it that behaved exceptionally oddly at times, taking actions that make little sense in context and yet somehow seem to be to his advantage?

"Dumbledore," Harry said.

Discord's eyes lit up with glee, but then he quickly drew his claws across his mouth, which turned into a large zipper, through which he mumbled, "I've said too much!"

The goo was now up to Harry's neck, and he found himself checking the hinges on the door to double check whether the door opened inwards or outward. He was relieved to see that it was the latter. He cast Discord an annoyed glare. "Can you please just make this go away?"

"Sorry, wish I could. I really wouldn't stick around to see what happens if the room fills up if I were you." Discord said as he waded casually through the muck.

"Wait, but you said before that you wanted to stop Death, too. Well, Heat Death, at least. How do you plan to do that?"

"Oh, I've got a few plans. None of which I can tell you, of course. But don't worry, you and I are on the same side." He playfully splashed Harry with the viscous liquid, which throbbed disturbingly on Harry's face. "At least I hope so! Now go on, before you get gobbled up."

Harry, who had already backed up against the door by this point, sighed and opened it, expecting a torrent of liquid to rush out. None did, instead it just sort of stayed in place, like a gelatinous blob. As he made his exit and closed the door, he heard Discord yell, "Toodle doo!"

When the door was closed, Harry looked down and saw that all traces of the goo had disappeared. He heaved an exasperated sigh and spoke into the empty hall.

"Posey?" Harry announced to no one in particular, hoping that this what was she had meant when she had instructed him to call for her anywhere within the castle.

After a few moments, Posey appeared with a dull POP nearby. "Yes, Master Potter?"

"Does Hogwarts keep any Muggle newspapers? I know I've seen archives of the Daily Prophet."

Posey grinned widely, glad to be able to provide a helpful answer. "Oh, yes sir. Yes, sir. Headmaster Dumbledore does so love his daily crossword. And 'waste not, want not' he always says. Never throws away an issue."

"Would you be able to get those for me? Or would I be able to get them for myself?"

"Do not trouble yourself, Grand and Glorious Savior! The newspapers are in the library, Posey would be honored to fetch them for you!"

"I would be infinitely grateful. Could you bring me them to the Ravenclaw common room? Just the front pages, though, I don't want you to have to carry the entire paper."

Posey looked momentarily crestfallen. "Sir... there are over 10,000 issues... You want... all of them?"

Harry blinked. "Oh. No, um... How about just from 19... Let's see." He did some quick recollection. "Let's say 1988 until today?"

Posey's eyes brightened and she nodded vigorously. "It would be an honor, sir!" And with that, she disappeared.

Later

With the help of Roger Davies, an older Ravenclaw who seemed amused and intrigued by his search, Harry had arranged the newspapers along the walls of the Ravenclaw common rooms. They cast a mass shrinking charm, reducing them to about a quarter of their original size; large enough to still be legible, but small enough to where they could all fit on the three walls of the area that Harry had occupied. They hung in midair as Harry painstakingly reviewed the headlines of each, hoping for some snippet of information. He was frowning severely in concentration and was visibly annoyed when his concentration was broken by a high pitched voice.

"Cookie?"

He glanced over at the source of the voice; it was Pinky, or "Alecto" as she was called within the school. She thrust a large cookie roughly the size of a small child's head in his direction. "No thanks," he muttered, to which she shrugged and stuffed a portion of it into her mouth.

"Cake?" she asked, through chunks of cookie. She was now holding a square slice of elaborately decorated cake, which was of course, pink in color.

"I'm ok, thanks." This time, Harry didn't even look at her.

"Cupcake?" she asked again, waving a cupcake in front of him decorated in the same style as the cake that she was just holding not a moment earlier.

Harry's curiosity was briefly piqued, wondering where she kept producing these baked goods from, but it was quickly drowned out by annoyance. "I'm kind of busy right now."

"Ohhh." She leaned forward, staring at the newspapers. "You look sad and frowny. Why are you sad?"

He didn't respond.

"Is it because you ran out of cookies?"

"I'm not sad."

"Is it because you ran out of cakes?"

He shook his head.

"Is it because you ran out of cupcakes?"

"No!"

"Hm, is it because your friend got her legs chewed off by some horrible monster and now she's dead and you've transformed her body into something tiny like a ring or rock and are carrying it around with you and your only hope of saving her lies with a crazy and possibly dangerous person and you've got to rely on that crazy dangerous person to reach across the very abyss of oblivion to pluck her back from the great beyond and if that crazy person doesn't pull through then you'll just have to do it yourself because if magic doesn't make sense in every single other way then why can't it not make sense in a way that's convenient for this too?!" She was panting maniacally by this point, hunched over with heaving breaths, and yet she was still smiling widely as she looked up at him.

Harry stared at her, briefly silenced. "Why... What makes you say that?"

"Just a hunch." Pinky shrugged.

"No. No one's 'hunches' are that good. Why did you say that?"

Pinky looked up, thoughtfully. "You know, no one ever asks me that." She spent another moment in thought. "Well, Disco- I mean, um... Mrs. Maxim? When Mrs. Maxim said he was here because our friend got in over her head and needed help, you thought he was talking to you. And you said you were hunting the thing that was eating unicorns, and that thing probably ate my friend so I figured he probably ate your friend, too. And afterwards, you looked down at your foot a bunch of times and I thought, 'Hm, that seems like a strange place to keep looking', but then I realized that if someone was really, really hurt, you wouldn't want to just shove her in the ground or burn her up or whatever you people do here, you'd want to keep her safe, and I've already seen people transform things into smaller things here.

"Obviously you haven't figured out how to help her yourself, otherwise you wouldn't be walking around here looking like Mr. Frowny Man, which means you need help, but if it was just something anyone could help with you'd already be getting help, so that must mean you'd have to be crazy to think that what you're trying to do is even possible. Which makes sense because it sounds incredibly dangerous, you know? But you're not going to stop just because Mr. Crazy and Dangerous can't help you, are you?"

Although she spoke very quickly and was panting from speaking for such a long period of time without drawing a breath, Harry still followed her. Her chain of logic was riddled with questionable assumptions, and yet she had still gotten most of it right. "That was... impressive."

"Thanks!" She smiled, having caught her breath again. "So what are you doing? Wallpaper? I love wallpaper designs." She stared up at the wall of newspapers.

"No. You wouldn't by any chance know who Nelson Mandela is, would you?" Harry asked, not really expecting an affirmative answer.

"You mean the 73-year old deputy president of the African National Congress?" she asked, curiously.

"Wait, what? You have a Nelson Mandela where you're from?"

"No, silly! I read about him." She laughed.

"Where?"

She pointed at one of the newspapers, dated February 1, 1991. "Right there!" She began to read the article, "...plans for a march on Parliament by thousands of opponents of apartheid suffered a setback when Nelson Mandela, the Congress's deputy president, canceled a planned appearance and speech. Congress officials attributed the 72-year-old leader's withdrawal..."

Harry felt a cold wave of dread wash over him. He could have sworn that Nelson Mandela had died in prison. He remembered seeing the funeral march on television and hearing about a few riots that broke out in the days that followed. And yet, this was clearly not the case. Unless Discord has somehow tampered with the newspapers, which didn't seem consistent with the limitations he was bound by. Of course, he could have been lying about those limitations.

At that moment, another very pressing question popped into Harry's mind. "How did you find that article so quickly? You were only standing here for a minute or two, and I've been looking through these for the better part of an hour now. Did you seriously read them all that quickly?"

"No, of course not. I just looked at them."

"What do you mean, you 'just looked at them'?"

"I looked at them, and then filed them away in the big filing cabinet in my head. Then when you asked about Nelson Mandela, I went into the filing cabinet, looked for the 'N's, flipped through until I found the article, and there you go! Doesn't everyone have a big filing cabinet in their head?"

"Um, no." Harry thought that must have just made a lucky guess and was lying, and yet she seemed so earnest.

"That must make it hard to remember things. How do YOU do it?"

"Sometimes I use mnemonic devices, and I guess I've tried to make a memory palace before. It sounds like you've just done a really good job of it. But, if I'm being honest, I'm still not entirely convinced." He narrowed his eyes somewhat playfully. "Prove it."

She bounced up and squealed, "OOOO! A quiz! This will be fun!"

Pinky turned around, and when she had turned back, she was holding a large easel with a canvas mounted on it in one hand, and a blindfold and charcoal stick in the other. She wrapped the blindfold around her eyes and said, "Okay, don't move!"

Confused, Harry shrugged. "Okay."

Before he even finished speaking, Pinky's hand was darting across the canvas in a blur of motion. She initially spanned large swathes of canvas with back-and-forth strokes, and when she had finished covering the entire thing, her hand moved around in erratic patterns, varying the pressure and speed as she bit her lip thoughtfully. When all was said and done, the whole process took maybe thirty seconds, at which point she tore off the blindfold, considered the final work, and beamed.

"Ta-da!" She spun the easel around to face Harry.

Harry stared, open-mouthed, at the nearly photo-realistic drawing of him standing in front of a wall of newspapers. It was an almost perfect recreation of the scene, except for the fact that Harry was wearing a polka-dotted party hat, and there was a large table of various cakes, cupcakes, and cookies behind him.

"That... is really, really good. Like, unbelievably good. Like, I don't really even understand how you did that."

"Thanks!" she beamed.

"Okay, but now I have another question. Where do you GET all this stuff? Do you have a bag of holding, too?"

Pinky reached into her pocket and held out her hand. "You mean this?" In her outstretched palm was a small brown lump, no bigger than a ladybug.

"What is that?"

"It's my Party Bag! Top of the line!" She reached her other hand into it, at which point it expanded into a frumpy sack the size of her fist. Harry could make out sticking on the outside that read: Hammerspace Industries Bag 'o Fun, Model DWIM. "It's top of the line!"

Harry suddenly felt very jealous. "So, what all do you keep in there?"

"Oh, a little bit of everything. Baking supplies, baked goods, flour, sugar, powdered sugar, brown sugar, superfine sugar... Rubber chickens, whoopee cushions, fake noses..." As she spoke, she was pulling things out of the bag and tossing them on the floor. "Pens, pencils, snacks, tinsel, streamers, creepy latex skin masks modeled after people I've met, sausage links, a trumpet, a tuba-"

Harry picked up one of the masks off the ground that had clearly been modeled after Luna Lovegood. It was realistic enough that the effect was thoroughly disturbing, and Harry was uncomfortably reminded of the story of Yermy Wibble.

"Do you like it? Look!" Pinky had put on the Harry Potter-shaped skin mask and lowered her voice and spoke with an exaggerated accent. "Look at me! I'm Harry Potter! I'm always sad and frowny! Mmmrrrggg mrrrrggg mrrrggg," she stomped around a bit, mocking his slump-shouldered gait.

"It's... creepy. Do you have anything actually useful in there?"

"Everything is useful at the right time!"

"Fine. But what about things that are... useful in the general sense, not just in ultra-specific edge cases? First-aid, maybe?"

"Oh, like doctor things?"

"Sure. Doctor things."

Pinky began pulling all manner of medical supplies from her bag, including a blood pressure cuff, a stethoscope, a roll of bandages, a crate of syringes that was clearly labelled 'Morphine', a set of scalpels, and several jars of various creams with generic names that Harry didn't recognize. The bag quickly grew to several times its size to accommodate a full-sized defibrillator, which Pinky struggled to set on the ground.

Harry was duly impressed. "That is, wow. What else do you have in there? Do you have things that you can use for protection?"

Pinky looked puzzled. "Protection? From what?"

"Well, my friend was eaten by a troll. And your friend was-"

"A TROLL? But they're so friendly where I come from. And people usually eat them, not the other way around..." She paused for a moment. "And they're so small. That must have taken a long time."

Harry's eyes grew hard, momentarily. "Well, where I come from, they're big. And not friendly."

"Usually things stop being mad when I give them cake. And if that doesn't work, I can always throw cake at them. Or distract them with cake. Or make them slip on cake. Come to think of it, I solve a lot of problems with cake. Cake is great, don't you think?"

"Trolls don't like cake."

Pinky looked disappointed. "Oh. Well, I guess in that case, maybe I would use one of these."

She began removed a pocketknife from her bag, and then noticing Harry's distinctly unimpressed expression, began removing several more weapons, starting with small knives in various shapes, progressing up to a couple of larger hunting knives and machetes. Students began to look up at the clattering noise of metal against metal as Pinky continued to toss more things onto the ground, including a rapier, a longsword, and an executioner's axe.

She paused for a moment. "But if close combat doesn't seem realistic, we could always go with... hm..." She pulled out a small handgun and held it up in front of Harry, whose eyes went wide as she tossed it onto the ground carelessly. She removed two additional pistols, along with a large chrome-plated pistol that was bigger than Harry's head, and threw them aside with careless disregard. She reached her arm deeper into the bag and removed a pair of assault rifles, one with a matte-black finish and the other with a wood-grain stock.

"But if we're looking for general destruction and mayhem, we might want to use some of these." As Pinky spoke, the other students began to slowly pack their things up from the common room and move towards the exits, not wanting to attract unwanted attention. Pinky removed a bandolier filled with hand grenades, a claymore mine, and with some effort, a rocket-propelled grenade launcher.

Harry started waving his hands and hissed at her in a whisper, "STOP! Put those away! You can't have those here!"

Pinky was thoroughly confused as she stared down at the small arsenal that had accumulated between them. "Sheesh. You were the one who asked!"

"Well. That is impressive, even by my standards. You've got my seal of preparedness-approval." Harry smiled, despite himself. There was a bit of silence between them as she packed the weapons back into her bag, and Harry thought for a moment. "So... I'm going to ask you a weird question."

"I love weird questions! Wait, let me try to guess the answer. Garmonbozia!"

"Uh, no. Let's say you didn't have your Hammerspace bag with you. Could you give me ten unaccustomed uses of objects in this room for combat?"

Pinky looked around. "Well, sure. You could break the legs off of the chairs and use them as clubs. Same with the tables. Or the candle-holders. In fact, you could pretty much use anything in the room as a club."

Harry nodded. "Okay, let's just count 'bludgeons' as one use."

"You could give someone a fatal paper cut with the pages of your books, or you could crumple the pages into a very tight, very pointy shape and stab someone. You could stab someone with the corners of a book too, or stab them with the broken leg of the chair that we were using as a club."

"Stabbing and slicing, check."

"I'm sure if you looked around hard enough, you could find something that was poisonous. In fact, I bet anything is bad for you if you eat enough of it. You could make someone drink enough ink to where they filled up and popped like a balloon. Or you could make them eat a rug, I bet that wouldn't feel very good. Oh! You could wrap them up in a rug and stuff them in a closet and never let them eat."

"Alright, we've covered suffocation and poison. Now let's say that it was just you, me, and an enemy in the room with no decorations or furniture. What then?"

Pinky twirled one of her fingers through the curls in her hair while she thought. "Well... if I wasn't worried about hurting you, I could do all sorts of things. I could cut your hair off and use it as a rope to strangle someone. Or use your clothes to strangle someone. Or use your limbs as a club. I bet your bones would make a good club, too. You could even sharpen them to make something stabby!"

Harry was staring off distantly at this point, and Pinky had noticed that he didn't seem to be paying attention. After a time, Harry looked back at her. "What's your real name?"

"Pinkamena Diane Pie! But my friends just call me Pinkie Pie. So you can call me Pinkie Pie, too! Or just Pinkie."

Harry smiled at the word 'friend'. "Okay, Pinkie. Can I ask you something else?"

"Sure thing!"

"Do people think you're... dark?"

"No, I don't think so. I smile too much for that. See?" She flashed him a beaming grin.

"How? How do you do it? You're obviously smart. Like, really smart. You may even be smarter than me, at least in terms of raw abilities. Maybe smarter than Hermione too. So how do you stop your mind from thinking about all the bad things?"

"That's easy, I just think about all the good things, instead."

"But those good things won't stay good forever. Things fall apart, they wear out, people grow old. Friends and family... they die." Harry was getting a little choked up.

"They don't have to. But you know that." Pinkie Pie put her hand on Harry's shoulder. "People get sad, sure. That's why I try to make them smile. Things can break, but you just fix them. If you're smart enough to think about how something might be bad, you have to be smart enough to think of how it might not be bad. Know what I mean?"

Harry shook his head. "But some things can't be reversed. I don't mean that it's too hard or that we don't know how yet, I mean, fundamentally, the-laws-of-the-universe-say-so, can't be reversed. My friend is dead. Gone. Forever. And most likely, your friend is gone, too."

Pinkie shrugged. "Mmm, I don't think so."

Harry's voice was hot. "I know so. I was there, holding Hermione in my arms when she died. I literally felt the life leave her."

"Dead means that someone is gone forever, right?"

Harry was nonplussed by this seeming non-sequitur. "Yes..."

Pinkie clapped her hands together. "There! So, what's the problem?"

"What?!"

"You don't actually think she's gone forever. You're trying to find her. That means you think there's a possibility, and if there's a possibility then it means that you aren't 100% sure she's gone. And you won't stop until you're sure one way or the other. But if you're being really, really, truly, pinky-promise-with-yourself kind of honest, you think you're going to do it. You think you're going to bring her back."

"Yes. I do." Harry nodded, grimly.

"So you don't have to be sad! She's not gone forever, you're just playing hide and seek. She's hiding, and she's only gone until you find her again. Easy as that." As if to punctuate her point, Pinkie plopped into one of the nearby chairs.

Harry was still standing. "But no one else is playing the same game I'm playing. If I fail, that's it. It's done. She's done. Every moment I spend not trying to find her is a moment wasted. And what if at the end of it all, I'm thirty minutes away but I only have five minutes left and all I can think is, 'Why, why did I spend that twenty-five minutes in the common room with Pinkie Pie when I could have been researching!"

"Now you're just being silly. You don't have to do it on your own. You just need to find more people to play with!"

"Have you met the people here? They're idiots. They don't want to 'play the game'. They're okay with people dying. They've convinced themselves it's a good thing."

Pinkie rolled her eyes at him. "That's because you're not very good at making friends." She then leaned over and said in a sidebar to no one in particular, "I can see why."

Harry leaned back, defensively. "That's not true! I've been trying to teach people ever since I got here. But most people don't want to listen, they don't want to change!"

"I didn't say anything about teaching people, I said you weren't very good at making friends."

Harry held out his hands, exasperated. "What good are friends going to do me if they can't help?!"

Pinkie's eyes widened as she let out a dramatic gasp. "What good are friends? WHAT GOOD ARE FRIENDS?" She stood up, leaning over him and looking down into his eyes, jabbing a finger into his chest as she spoke in a soft, menacing tone. "I'll tell you what good friends are!"

The juxtaposition of her anger against her normally bubbly demeanor was disquieting. Harry took a step back, suddenly aware of the fact that she was a good head taller than him. Although she was apparently something of a genius, as she had demonstrated earlier, she was also clearly just a tiny bit unhinged.

Not unlike yourself... his inner Hufflepuff chimed in.

Pinkie continued, "Your friend is lost, and you're never going to rest or be completely happy until you find her again. Why? Because she's your friend, right?"

"Yes," Harry said quickly, but then decided to correct himself for fear of being dishonest. "Well, That's one of the reasons, at least. The main reason, I think. But there are other reasons."

Pinkie had ignored his addendum. "And she would do the same for you, right?"

Harry paused.

Would she, though? his Slytherin voice asked.

Yes, replied the Hufflepuff and Gryffindor in unison.

Hm... if she lived long enough, yes, I think she would, Ravenclaw replied after a few moments of thinking.

Fair enough, that's two and a half against one. Majority rules, Slytherin acquiesced.

"Yes, I think so."

Pinkie nodded and smiled, satisfied. When she spoke again, her voice had lost its hard edge. "You're my friend. Am I your friend?"

Harry was taken off-guard by the question and had to think again before he answered. He glanced at the small pile of bladed objects that still remained on the floor that had not yet been put away into her Bag of Holding +3. "Yeah. I'd call you a friend, now. Maybe not before we talked today. But it seems like you and I would get along."

At this, she clapped her hands together and squealed a bit. "If YOU were ever lost and couldn't find your way back, I would go looking for you and wouldn't be satisfied until I helped you find your way back. Because you're my friend! Would you do the same for me?"

Harry wasn't comfortable with the idea of outright lying to her, due in no small part to his worry at what kind of unstable reaction it might elicit. "I don't know. This hypothetical situation with has a lot of factors that you're just leaving out. How did you die, what kind of difficulties are involved, what are my own personal circumstances, things like that. I can't really answer the question honestly."

"Oh come onnnn. Are you really trying to tell me that if you magically unlocked the secret to making people not dead, and your friend was dead and you made her not dead anymore but you knew that I was dead, you would just let me stay dead?"

"Well... okay, obviously when you put it like that, no. I wouldn't. But I don't really see-"

Pinkie cut him off. "So there you go! Problem solved!"

"Yeah, I'm not really following you here."

"You're her friend, and you won't stop until you find her. If you were lost, I wouldn't stop until I found you. If I were lost, my friends wouldn't stop until they found me. If they were lost, their friends wouldn't stop until they found them. If their friends were lost, they wouldn't stop either."

She turned around, looking out at the window into the night sky. Her voice took on an air of wonder. "Where I'm from, we have people who look at the stars. And they say they the stars are far away. Really, really, really far away. And long ago, too. They say that some of the stars we see, they're from as far back as the beginning of time. I think that's pretty neat, don't you?"

She turned back to him. He nodded and smiled at their unexpected common interest, and she continued. "There's a lot of darkness between us and them. But even if there was only one star in the entire universe, even if it were impossibly far away, we'd still see its light.

"You might not believe it, but my friends and I have fought a lot of enemies where we come from. And we'll probably have to fight a lot more. You too, I bet... Everyone does, I think. But really, the last enemy to be destroyed is-"

"Death." Harry finished her sentence for her. Memories flooded into him, and with them came tears that formed at the corners of his eyes.

"That's what I was going to say!" She smiled at him. "It doesn't have to be you. And it doesn't have to be now, or today, or tomorrow, or this year or next year or the next thousand years. All it takes is one star shining in the darkness to cast the entire universe in light, from now until the end of time.

"So you see, it doesn't matter if you fail, even if you're the only one working to fix things right now. It's not just you who would have to fail. It's your friends. And their friends. And their friends. And all of their friends, too, now, and going on into forever. Life itself would have to fail. Friendship would have to fail. And... I just don't think that's going to happen. Do you?"

Harry stared at her through watery eyes, noting that she seemed serenely oblivious to the effects her words were having on him. Without really knowing what compelled him to do so, he wrapped his arms around her in a tight hug and whispered,

"No. No, I don't."

Godric's Hollow

Alone in a graveyard, a tall stone worn as though from a thousand years of age, upon it a line within a circle within a triangle, glowed brightly silver, clearly visible beneath the clear night sky to anyone who cared enough to look.

Chapter 8: Have You Heard, Pt 1

"Hateful Prism," Applejack drawled, the skepticism practically dripping from her words.

"That's what I said!" Rainbow Dash retorted.

Applejack crossed her arms as she looked around at the ivy-covered columns. "Are you sure you're being honest? That all sounds a bit... dramatic."

"Sure, but isn't everything that happens to us 'dramatic'?"

"Fair point," Applejack shrugged. "So, she threw off her cloak, grew wings, and floated up in the air?"

"Yep. And she looked mostly like I do now. So, pretty cool. But with more eye makeup and dangly jewelry. And her hair was longer. Oh, and she had wings. Did I mention she had wings?"

"About five times."

"So, she starts going into this spiel about how she is my dark reflection, the symbol of all my wasted potential, everything I could have been if I hadn't been held down..."

Applejack cocked her eyebrow, "Held down?"

Rainbow Dash waved off the concern. "Yeah, it was just another one of those, 'let me try to tempt you with dark magic more powerful than friendship' sort of things."

Applejack had to stifle a giggle. "And was it... tempting?"

"Oh, sure." Rainbow Dash oozed with false sincerity. "It told me I could have saved the world, been a hero to everyone. But instead, I chose to waste all of that on you," she barked out a coarse laugh. "It's like she thought I was Twilight or something. She should have known that I'm awesome enough to do both."

Applejack held her chin in her hand as she considered this. "So what happened next?"

Rainbow Dash shrugged. "Oh, the usual. I gave it a speech about friendship and why it's more important to love what you have than to focus on what might be." She moved her hands up and down in the universal 'blah blah blah' gesture. "Then my eyes went all glowy, I grew wings and some pony ears and a tail... Then I did whatever I imagine a Sonic Rainboom is here in this place." She planted her hands on her hips in satisfaction. "Then I blasted her to pieces."

"Sounds about right," Applejack remarked, completely unfazed by the bizarre turn of events.

"All that was left was a tattered black cloak, which Harry rolled up into a ball and threw into the lake. I can't believe he thought that thing was scary!"

"Wait a minute, are you saying he watched this whole thing?"

"Well yeah, it was all his idea in the first place. "

"You don't think… that maybe you weren't the one this 'Hateful Prism' was trying to tempt?"

Rainbow Dash gave this some serious thought. "Well, now that you bring it up, Harry did seem to be really frazzled by the whole thing. But then again, I get the sense that things are a bit more… boring here in this world than in Equestria."

Applejack nodded vigorously. "Ain't that the truth. You should see what they call 'farming' here. I mean, they literally put seeds into the ground, and then just wait for them to grow. Organically. Can you believe that?"

"You mean, it's not just a… What do you call it again?" Rainbow's eyes widened.

"An abstraction layer? Nope! Just literal seeds, dirt, and time. Now, I'm not opposed to hard work and patience, but it's got to be smart work, know what I mean? Imagine if y'all Pegasi literally moved physical clouds with your wings to make the weather!"

They both laughed together. "Can you imagine? So how do they even decide the weather here?"

"Beats the applesauce out of me. I think they just leave it up to chance."

"Ha! No wonder Discord loves it here."

"Well, that's what I don't really get. Discord said he doesn't have anywhere as much power here as he does in Equestria. But it seems like they leave a lot more up to chance here. Their food, the weather, even their foals, or babies, or whatever they call those things, here."

"Oh, Believe me, I heard all about it from Harry. Here's what kind of creepy about this place. It's like they leave... their whole lives up to chance." Applejack arched an eyebrow and Rainbow Dash leaned in close. "You know what he told me about this place? He told me that people die every second. Every second. Can you believe that?"

Applejack felt a hot wave of revulsion. "Rainbow, I know you wouldn't be pulling my leg about something like this…" Although it was a statement, it really was more of a plea than anything, begging her friend to admit it was just nothing more than a tasteless joke. "No... That's... That's horrible."

"That's what I said! But that's what made him summon that... whatever it was, the 'Dementor'. He told me that they were holes in the world, the primordial embodiment of Death, and told me what they do to people... make them relive their worst memories. I told him that sounds more like Fear than Death. But he was pretttttttty sure. Anyway, here's the crazy thing. When I first saw it, I couldn't see anything. But I knew something was supposed to be there, I could feel it. It was almost like… Like..."

"Like you had forgotten what it was supposed to look like?" Applejack provided.

"Yeah! Like it was on the tip of my tongue… Or… My eyes. You know what I mean. And then, well he asked me what I saw. And it wasn't until I tried to describe it that she, you know, 'Hateful Prism', popped out." Rainbow Dash flopped herself down onto the cool tile of the dilapidated structure in the Forbidden Forest. "You know, I miss Twilight. If she were here, she probably pulls out a book and says something like, 'According to the second book in the Horse Tack Materials trilogy, these sound a lot like the creatures that haunted Citagazze', and then that would be some kind of clue or something."

"Yeah, I miss her too." Applejack nodded, but then suddenly whipped her head around. "What's that noise?"

They both squinted their eyes and peered through the trees in the forest. They could see two figures skulking their way from tree to tree, one holding a compass in her hand and the other holding his wand out projecting some sort of translucent shield. They couldn't tell whose team they were on, so they didn't call attention to themselves.

"So this game, huh?" Applejack cracked a grin as she whispered. "You figure it out yet?"

"Um, yeah! I figured it out two minutes after that creepy teacher told us the rules!"

"Seems pretty easy if you ask me but… Things are different here, I guess. You think Harry will figure it out?"

Rainbow Dash gave this some serious thought. "I don't know. He doesn't really seem like he's that good at making friends but… he reminds me a lot of Twilight. Obsessed with books, and just a bit rough around the edges. And look at her now, Princess of Friendship."

Applejack nudged her friend with a playful elbow. "You thinking he's gonna be a Prince of Friendship?"

Rainbow Dash laughed. "Stranger things have happened."

"Ain't that the truth."

"You know, he's got a little bit of each of us in him. The way he was describing that Dementoid, he said it affected him worse than anyone because 'it was almost physically impossible for him to flinch away from the truth'."

Applejack pursed her lips. "I dunno, usually people who have to tell you how honest they are don't exactly tend to be the most trustworthy."

"Well, that's the thing, he wasn't trying to brag about it. He was trying to make a point about how terrible those things were. It kind of reminded me of Pinkie a bit, with how intense he was. But with that creepy Fluttershy dark side. And he doesn't really think about much besides saving his friend... If that's not generosity, I don't know what is."

"You know, you've checked almost all the boxes... but you seem to be missing someone." Applejack gave Rainbow a sly grin.

"Yeah. I know. We... well, we had a moment."

"Oooooooooooo. Well, look at you, Rainbow Dash!" She laughed as she punched her on the shoulder.

Rainbow Dash laughed and rolled her eyes. "You know it's not like that. Besides, he's literally a baby. He says he's 11 years old."

"You sure that's not one of those 'I call it a year, you call it a season' sort of things?"

"Maybe. Probably. I can't quite figure out how time is supposed to work here. I mean, we've only been here a few days, but it feels like a whole year has gone by." Rainbow Dash squinted her eyes and looked up at the sun.

"I'd say it feels more like eleven months, three weeks and two days, but who's counting?"

Rainbow Dash didn't seem to register what her friend had said. "Say, AJ, how much do you remember about... You know, before."

"Hmm. Same as you, I expect. Not much." she shrugged and looked at Rainbow Dash. "You?"

Rainbow Dash stared off into the distance, "Yeah. Not much."

Applejack chuckled. "That had to be the most convincing 'Not much' I've heard in my life."

Rainbow Dash nodded without smiling. "I remember… I remember, being dead, you know? Just… Sort of… Being. For, I don't know how long. Existing without anything to really exist with. And I had this kind of feeling, this memory of who I was supposed to be. Then, I just sort of… You know… Woke up."

Applejack nodded, having recalled a similar experience herself.

"And, ever since then, it's always kind of been in the back of my head that, well, I beat Death once. Who's to say I can't do it again?"

Applejack was now shaking her head slightly. "I don't know there, Dash. I mean, if you remember it, then, well, you aren't really dead, are you? I mean, dead means… Gone. Forever."

"I know, I know. But you felt it too, didn't you? You know it was different. It wasn't like being asleep or knocked out. It was like… Well, it was like being dead."

"Uh huh," Applejack said with a hint of skeptical criticism in her voice. "And how do you know what that feels like?"

"I just told you, because... Oh." Her own use of circular logic just dawned on her.

"Look, Dash. Just 'cause something don't taste like an apple, that don't make it an orange."

The corners of Rainbow Dash's eyes wrinkled, belying just the slightest hint of distress. "But… How can you really believe that?"

"There ain't nothing to believe. You don't believe the truth. It just is. The sky is blue. You can believe all you want that it's red but that ain't going to change much."

"It's funny you say that. You know, Discord once told me… Well, I guess he asked me: if the whole world believed the sky was red, would it matter if the sky was actually blue?"

Applejack thought about this. "You know, I got a lot to say about that. I mean, for one, you know as well as I do that Discord plays by different rules. Half the time, what he's talking about ain't what he's actually saying, and the other half the time, he doesn't have any reason for saying what is saying. And besides, if everyone said the sky was red, that would just mean everyone was using different words to say the same thing. It's like if everyone started calling south 'north', and north 'south'. If someone gave you directions, you'd still find your way, all the same."

Rainbow Dash was nodding vigorously in agreement. "That's just what I said! But then he told me, that wasn't what he meant, and that I knew it wasn't what he meant, and that I was just being difficult. So to teach me a lesson, he did some trick so that everyone thought my coat was red for a day. I was the only one who thought it was blue!"

"I remember that! But see, that's just what I mean. He plays by different rules, only Discord could pull a joke like that. Doesn't really tell us much, doesn't really tell us anything at all besides the fact that Discord likes to stir up trouble every now and then."

"Sure, but… If that's really how you think things are… How do you do all this? "She gestured her hands all around. "A lot of the stuff we do, actually most of the stuff we do is really kind of dangerous when you think about it. Like, really dangerous. If you didn't think, somewhere in the back your head that you had a safety net…" Rainbow Dash suddenly had a very crestfallen look on her face and didn't speak for some time.

"Let me guess. You're thinking the only reason you're brave is 'cause you've been telling yourself that you'll have a second chance if things go wrong? "

Rainbow Dash nodded glumly. "And that's not really… Bravery at all, is it?"

Applejack rolled her eyes. "What do you think bravery is, Dash? Being stupid? Taking chances just for the sake of taking chances?"

Rainbow Dash gave a dejected shrug and Applejack continued. "It's fighting for something bigger than just you. It's being willing to take that chance, to make that sacrifice. Tell me, if you had to make the choice, right here, right now. You, or the five of us. Gone, forever. I'm not talking about falling asleep for a long time, or I'm not talking about your mind just drifting between the worlds while you wait for a new body. I'm talking dead, gone."

With no hesitation whatsoever, Rainbow Dash replied, "I'd pick you all. Even if I had to choose between my life and just yours. There's no question."

Applejack gave her a gentle pat on the back. "See? Now that's bravery. And you know what? We'd make the same choice for you too. It's just that we all just have different ways of… You know… Coping with that. With death. For you, you said you feel like you beat death once so why couldn't you do it again? But it wasn't really you that beat death now, was it? See, what you're really saying here is, you trust your friends so much that you honestly believe, down in your heart of hearts, that no matter what happens, no matter how lost you get, your friends would fight for you and you'd fight for them. If that's not loyalty, I don't know what it is.

"And me, well I'm an Apple. I face my problems head-on. I know that it's there, I know it's a possibility. But there's power in that, you know? By accepting the truth, it gives me the power to act on it. And Fluttershy, well, she's a healer at heart. Kindness, healing, life… Those things are kind of the opposite of death, aren't they? She's a warrior, out there on the front lines of the fight."

Rainbow Dash smiled, feeling just a little bit better. "She's a warrior, all right. You know what they say, if you know how to heal, you know how to hurt."

Applejack shuddered a bit but nodded. "Ain't that the truth. And Rarity, well, you know she and I don't always see eye to eye, but I tell you what, she makes it for darn sure that we have something that's worth fighting for, something beautiful…" She twisted her voice into a good-natured mockery of Rarity's inflection, "Something glamorous, darling. And Pinkie, well, sometimes I don't blame her for just leaning in and embracing the crazy. I mean if we're being honest, this all is just a little bit crazy. I mean, we're walking, talking ponies for Faust's sake!"

A sudden rustling in the nearby trees silenced them both, quickly. The two figures were close enough to where she could make out his face: it was Harry. She let out a whispered yell to get his attention.

Harry whipped his head around in their direction and stared at the tree line behind them. He looked over to his companion and nodded his head towards them. The way he was acting, it was like he was being followed. Or maybe, he was doing the following. Quickly, Harry and his companion ran from tree to tree, using the greenery as cover. After a few minutes of sneaking, they finally reached the structure that until they reached the structure that Rainbow Dash and Applejack had been confined to.

"Hey kid, I'm a computer," Harry spoke in a voice distinctly not his own.

Applejack gave a sidelong glance to Rainbow Dash.

Harry waved his hand back and forth. "Stop all the downloadin'!"

Rainbow Dash rolled her eyes. "He's forgotten already, hasn't he? Maybe I gave him too much credit."

Harry shook his head and frustration and let out a long garbled stream of synthesized, computerized noise. His classmate who had now caught up, a wispy blonde little Hufflepuff first year that Applejack recognized as Angela Ziegler. She spoke in a voice that seemed far too low of a register for her diminutive frame.

"Who wants a body massage?"

Harry looked off another direction sharply, listening intently. Rainbow Dash leaned in and she could hear the noise as well. Footfall, and lots of it. It was coming from the direction of the clearing opposite them.

With sudden urgency in his movement, Harry charged forward. Angela followed a few meters behind, with a bright golden tether of light emanating from her wand having attached itself to Harry. She was saying something as she ran... No, was she singing?

"Low, eee ohh, Mr. Body Massage Machine-GO!"

There was a sense of strange desperation in Harry's movement. His companion followed swiftly thereafter and the noise of the footfalls grew louder as he closed the distance to the clearing. Just as Harry reached the edge, Applejack and Rainbow Dash could see a large group of students emerge, led by a boy with a pointed face and slick, platinum blonde hair.

With one final effort, Harry charged forward, holding his wand as if it were a hammer and then shouted in his own voice, "Malleus Descendum!"

Harry was propelled forward with unnatural speed, and when his wand connected with the ground, a shockwave was sent towards the group of other students. When it hit them, they were all swept off their feet and Angela came charging in afterward, holding her wand high in the air and yelled, in a voice much more appropriate for someone her size, "Helden Sterben Nicht!"

The battlefield was bathed in a blinding, golden light.

Earlier

Draco Malfoy was finding it particularly difficult to research the mystery of Hermione's death. He had staggered into the Slytherin common room carrying what must have been a dozen books. Normally, Crabbe and Goyle would have been close behind, carrying another dozen themselves. But, Draco had them busy collecting intelligence on "Plain Jane".

The name was clearly a pseudonym, and the circumstances of their arrival were suspect in the highest. That alone would have called for a cursory amount of research, and stymied as they were by the complete lack of conclusive information, Draco likely would have called things off. But Draco was both intrigued and concerned by the way that the older Slytherins were either transparently obsequious or gave her a very wide berth, causing the majority of Slytherin House to follow suit.

Nobody seemed willing to actually talk about the subject, but from what Draco could piece together from the tittles and jots of various snippets of conversation and oblique references, there had been some sort of incident involving Reese Belka, a first year, and a dark hallway. "Plain Jane" had apparently interceded in some way, although the nature of the intercession was entirely unclear.

What was clear, however, was that Reese Belka made it conspicuously sure from that point on to never be present in the same room as the pink haired newcomer.

The whole thing stank to Merlin of Potter. Of course, the fact that Potter had apparently become quite friendly with "Tisiphone" and "Megaera" only furthered the suspicion. Those would likely be pseudonyms as well. Draco's father had seen to it that he was well studied in all things related to wizardkind. And because so many of the ancient Muggle myths had their roots in Magical phenomenon, he was familiar with the legends of the ancient world, including The Furies, The Kindly Ones, The Eumenides, The Erinyes: Tisiphone, Megaera, and Alecto.

Wizard families often got cute with the symbolism behind their names. But a trio? Draco knew that his mother and father had been trying for some time to produce an heir before Draco was born, an exercise which clearly at one point resulted in heartbreak: one day when Draco was seven, he was examining the sculptures on the Malfoy family Oblatorium and noticed one that was smaller than all the rest. A small, blue, green and yellow striped bonbon, still in its wrapper was mounted lovingly between Mother's golden harp and the empty plaque that represented himself. He had asked Father who that was, and the elder Malfoy replied in a shaky voice that he would tell him Draco when he was older, when he could understand.

Draco could not quite remember how old he was when the comprehension of its meaning dawned upon him, but he never asked his father about it again.

Their story was not an uncommon one either. Not every family was as sloppily fertile as the Weasleys. In fact, most weren't. Having three children wasn't exactly rare, but it was hardly something that you could count on, certainly not enough to feel comfortable giving two children names out of an obvious trio. If the third never materialized, it would be a living testament to your family's failure to perpetuate the blood of Atlantis.

There were certainly a good many reasons not to be skeptical of their names. He tried to think like Harry taught him to. He asked himself, what the "prior probability" of a family naming their children after a trio like this, versus the probability that a trio of witches was using assumed names, and he determined the latter was more likely.

Had Harry been there, he would have pointed out that Draco had misunderstood and misapplied the principles of Bayesian reasoning. He also would've pointed out that Rationality is about winning, and that Draco's conclusion was the correct one, regardless of how he came to. But as it were, Draco was unsure of the certainty of either of those truths.

And so it was that Crabbe and Goyle were putting together their considerable lack of wit to the task of investigation, rather than to one which they would likely be more suited: hauling heavy objects.

Having grown frustrated with the lack of progress into his investigation of Hermione, he decided instead to look further into the mystery of Plain Jane himself. He knew that one of the older Slytherins had offered the use of their private quarters and so that considerably narrowed down the possibilities of where he could find her. If this girl was, indeed, going to be the next queen of Slytherin, Draco Malfoy would make sure that he was, at minimum, on her radar.

Two of the three most lavishly appointed rooms had their doors open, their occupants sitting at desks writing letters or reading books. The third office, which belonged to Robert Jugson, was closed. He drew in a breath, held his shoulders high, and rapped on the door. Authoritatively, but not too assertive. His father had taught him the art of knocking in such a way as to communicate, I am coming into this room, and it is only by my forbearance that I am alerting you to this fact beforehand.

"Come in!" A delicate, soft voice called from behind the finally inlaid, heavy oak door.

Draco opened it and was immediately taken aback by what he saw. The bed and desk has been pushed aside to one wall, and the wall containing the window was lined with… were those… Nests? A family of baby rabbits had cozied up into a small bed of straw and a few fat blue jays were twittering around, keeping close to her, until one landed on her finger. Meanwhile, an Abyssinian cat with spectacularly red fur slinked around, its tail weaving in and out between her legs.

But what shocked him the most was that, coiled around her arm, was a powerful, glistening snake, banded with bluish black rings starkly contrasting the white body. He would recognize that snake anywhere, the snake that his Patronus was formed after.

A Blue Krait. What she held in her hands was obscenely dangerous.

And she was talking to it.

Not words, but breathy hisses,

Sweet slithering snakes, she was a Parseltongue.

"Pardon me Madame Plein but…" He had to interrupt his own formal greeting. "Are you quite sure that you want to be holding that snake? I'm not sure if you realize how dangerous it is."

She let out a small giggle. "Oh, this little guy? He wouldn't hurt a fly." She gently crouched down to the ground. Her voice was so soft and yet he could clearly hear every word she said. Except, that is, when she whispered in Parseltongue to the snake, who then uncoiled himself from her arm, and began slithering towards Draco. "See? He's just friendly."

Draco now understood why the whole of Slytherin house was terrified of her. She played the game perfectly. There is no rudeness, no insult behind her failure to return his greeting, for he had not actually greeted her. And now, here he was, scared stiff, plain as day, and faced with an awful choice: put himself in mortal danger, or insult a verified Parselmouth by doubting her control over her thralls.

If you don't like the rules, play a different game, Father had always told him. He would not stand here, shaking in fear as she asserted her dominance over him. Contrary to every bit of common sense in him, he changed the rules, kneeled down, and held his hand out to the approaching snake.

"Forgive my rudeness, Madame Plein. I am Draco, eldest heir of the Most Noble and Ancient House of Malfoy, son of Lucius the Younger, son of Abraxas, descendant of Armand," The honorifics were an ancient, almost forgotten tradition among Slytherins, although not forgotten among those families whose bloodlines truly mattered. The guest would introduce themselves, their house, their lineage. The host would then send forth the serpent of the house to greet the guest, at which point you inquired as to its name, "And how shall I address this most honored, most august Blue Krait that defends your house?"

"Oh him? His name is Nathaniel, but his friends just call him Nate."

He bowed deeply to the snake as per tradition. He did not have a snake of his own, at least not a physical one, so he pointed his wand at the ground and whispered, "Expecto Patronum". His own Krait, made of gossamer strands of ephemeral silk, emerged from his wand and approached its physical counterpart.

"Greetings, Nathaniel," Draco moved his eyes up to his owner. "And what house does he serve?"

She had followed all the customs up until this point. Maybe this was a test? Maybe she would only reveal her true identity to someone well-versed in the ancient customs in the ancient ways. She cocked her head, and Draco eagerly awaited her response.

"Oh, my name is Fluttershy."

"Uh... what?" Draco was thoroughly nonplussed and replied without thinking.

"Fluttershy," she said, only slightly louder. "It's lovely to meet you. Your snake is so beautiful. I think he and Nate will make great friends. Isn't that right Nate?" In a thoroughly undignified manner, she got down on her knees and held her arms outstretched, at which point the Blue Krait quickly slithered over and snuggled up in her arms. She stroked his head, made some cooing noises and spoke to it in English, "You're just a shy little guy, aren't you? It was so brave of you to leave your lever and go meet a stranger. You're a brave little one, yes you are!"

That… That was not according to the tradition. That was not… That wasn't anything at all. What was that, even?

She turned to him. "It's very nice to meet you Draco Malfoy. Was there anything I could help you with?" She asked in an eager voice.

If Draco had not been thoroughly on edge, he would actually think that she sounded… Sincere. What was she playing at? What was her angle?

"I was… Well, I had heard some rumors… About a certain incident in the hallway involving an older student… And a younger student…"

She looked up, as if in thought, and then it struck her. "Oh yes, I remember that. There was an older girl who was being very unfriendly."

"And… What did you do?"

"Oh, I just talked to her."

"You just… Talked to her. That's it."

She gave him a soft nod, and let out a quiet "Mh hmm," in affirmation.

"I don't mean to pry, but… Reese Belka hasn't been the same since you 'just talked to her'. Are you sure that's all you did?"

She smiled, serenely. "Oh yes. My friend said that I can be very… Persuasive, when I want to be."

She looked at his eyes when she spoke, and on the word "persuasive", her voice took on an ever so slight, almost undetectable edge to it. But what startled Draco more was the brief flash across her eyes; he had seen that look, before. It was the look Harry had when he went to his dark place. It lasted but for a fraction of a second, and disappeared.

I can only handle one Potter. Draco thought to himself.

He was spared the dilemma of how to respond to her remark by the sudden din of noise from the hallways. Millicent Bulstrode came charging gamely from the Slytherin common room shouting, "DOOMED! We are doomed, we're all doomed!"

Draco stepped out of Fluttershy's room briefly to look at the source of the commotion. He could hear her clearly from where he stood. "It's Professor Quirrell!"

A sudden air of attentiveness, as of long-standing disputes about to be settled. "Well, finally," someone said, as Millicent tried to catch her breath. "He's only got, what, a few days left to go bad?"

"Two days," said the seventh-year who was running the betting pool.

"He's gotten a lot better suddenly and he's going to summon the first-years for our Defense final! By surprise! In fifty minutes! "

Blaise Zabini rolled her eyes and went back to his reading. "Exams are over. We already got our marks back,"

"He got special dispensation from the Ministry to give a final exam late!"

"A Defense final?" Pansy said blankly. "But Professor Quirrell doesn't give exams."

"It's a battle!"

Zabini was suddenly interested, again. "But, what about Miss Granger?"

"Granger? Who cares about that Mudbloo-" Pansy's words were cut off by a percussive smack to the back of her head, delivered by Reese Belka, who looked paler than usual.

"Have respect, Parkinson!"

Draco was already slowly backing out of Fluttershy's room, and was about to break into a run before he turned back to the pink haired girl and quickly said, "It was a pleasure to meet you, Madame Shy, but I must be going, now."

Chapter 9: The Voyage

Los Angeles
Hours Earlier

Scott Parajsa looked out over the top of his hands at the large, dark-skinned man across from him, the last dying rays of the sun's struggle reflecting off the man's shaved head. He finished the last bits of his pointlessly expensive steak made from a variant of the Japanese Polled, bred only in a small farm outside Iwakuni in the Yamaguchi prefecture of Japan. His Hanzo-made steak knife, which would have cut through a piece of toughened leather as though it were no more than fog, was purely ornamental: a dry twig could have cut this meat.

A briefcase was chained to the man's wrist with an impressively thick handcuff. The case was nondescript, a fitting receptacle for the object of near-infinite power within, as true power needs to ornamentation. The man adjusted the numbers of the combination lock to the appropriate sequence: 666. He slid the box over the rich, lacquered-oak desk, and Parajsa took it, opening the case slightly. The man knew better than to look at its contents; it was rumored that death befell anyone who laid eyes upon it. He contented himself with observing the pleasant orange glow illuminating the olive-skinned face of the man sitting across from him. Parajsa gave an appraising nod, and with a lazy wave, caused the case to close and the handcuff to fall away from the man's wrist.

"Last time I heard, Lasombra, you were off on a beach somewhere in Santiago. What brings you back to Los Angeles?"

Scott Parajsa, or, 'Lasombra', as he was known these days (he had to admit, it was a catchier, more menacing nickname. And more accurate, to boot), inclined his head towards the suitcase.

"I'm here for that, Mr. Wallace. And, it was actually Tahiti, this time."

"How as it?"

"It's a magical place," he cocked an eyebrow at Mr. Wallace. "How about you? You look like you've been through hell and back."

Mr. Wallace broke into a wide grin. "Do I look like a bitch? Yeah, I've been through hell and back. But I looked Satan in the eyes and made sure to send him a message, loud and clear." He tossed Parajsa an orange latex ball, "You can have this, too. I don't think I'll be needing it anymore."

Parajsa caught the ball deftly and examined it. He had an inkling of an idea as to what it had been used for, "To hell and back, indeed," he spoke while he squashed the ball gently between his two fingers. He placed it down on his desk and walked slowly to the impressive glass cabinet behind him. The contents were protected by something far more effective than mundane technology, but nonetheless, he pressed his palm against the glass. Green light danced up and down across it, reading the unique patterns of his handprint. A low chime indicated a successful reading, and he tapped his fingers in a distinct pattern to disengage the final portion of the physical locks.

Bach's Partita, No. 1, if anyone cared to observe him. No one did.

As he did so, he whispered a few words in a long-dead language to disable the true protection, and the door silently swung open. He removed the small decanter from the cabinet, along with two limited edition, ornately carved Steuben glasses, walking them over to his desk. He poured a measure of the deep, ruddy liquid into each of the glasses. Even standing a fair distance away, Wallace could smell the sweet, aromatic vapors wafting from the rim.

Parajsa handed one of the glasses to Mr. Wallace, inclined his head, and spoke in a brief toast: "To good health." They clinked glasses and downed the liquid in a single gulp. Mr. Wallace, who had not yet had centuries to become accustomed to the effect, visibly shuddered as the warm glow of pleasure worked its way from the pit of his stomach to his extremities. He worked the muscles in his face a bit, and felt as the trace wrinkles he had developed during his last excursion smoothed themselves out, and the fresh wounds on his face stitched themselves together.

He began to pour another measure into his own glass and handed it to Wallace. "For Mia. You can keep the glass. Consider it an anniversary present."

Marcellus Wallace nodded. "Always a pleasure, Lasombra."

"Likewise, Mr. Wallace."

Sombra had no need to worry about running out of the Elixir of Life; he was of Atlantean blood, true Atlantean blood, one of the first. He did not need to resort to petty parlor tricks to achieve something as mean and simple as immortality in this form. On the other hand, these mortal men, their bodies were so frail and squishy. He did, of course, share a common ancestry with them, in the same sense than an ornate oaken temple shared a common ancestry with an acorn.

He could have stockpiled all the gold and jewels in the world with the Element of Honesty that he once possessed. It went by many names in this world: The Mightstone, the Stone of Truth, the Philosopher's Stone… But life was the only true scarcity here. And as such, an elixir that granted eternal life was a far more useful currency among those of superlative power and influence and ran no risk of depreciating in value after centuries of repeated use. There was no reason, after all, to spend his banishment in squalor.

Even if he had not been of Atlantean blood, he had no need to worry. The elixir itself was nothing more than a marker. Razzle-dazzle. Parlor tricks. The real mechanism was fairly simple and somewhat mundane: an army of miniscule automatons, designed to repair damaged cells, identify and destroy any unwanted foreign intrusions, and then tack on some telomeres for good measure. They possessed the capacity to self-replicate at his command, should the need arise.

It took him a century or two to write the blueprint for the machine and hold the entirety of it in his mind. With the power of the Philosopher's Stone, all it took was a single transfiguration to commit the device to physical reality. Its capacity for self-replication took care of the rest.

With an endless supply of the most valuable resource known to man, and no desire to change this world for the better, he had little need for the Philosopher's Stone. So he had no problem handing to over to someone who would have more use for it. When Adagio and her sisters were banished to this world, he sought them out and passed the stone to them. He held a great deal of sympathy for them; they only wanted the same thing as he did: adoration, love. They wanted it from the many, whereas for him, there was only enough room for one sun in his sky.

All the same, they found that for all the Stone could do, it could not grant them what they desired. So they too gave away the Stone. At that time, they went under the guise of the tripartite goddess, Baba Yaga, and passed it on to a little mortal girl, Perenelle Du Marais.

Objectively, Sombra knew that it has been a tremendously long time since he had come here. It didn't feel like a thousand years, though. It was in the past, for sure, but it occupied the same space in his mind as events too distant to be considered recent, but not so long ago as to have been abstracted away into the mere essence of memory. Or maybe, he had just grown accustomed to every memory being like that. He knew that the mind was finite, and had no real idea how many memories one could store without having to throw old ones away.

He emerged at first in what is now Greenland; it was a desolate, frigid place, but it reminded him of home. At first, he thought to rebuild his empire on a new world, but as the years stretched on and he strode alone through the towering crystalline structures of ice and rock, the whole exercise seemed hollow, unimportant, trivial.

As he wandered the world, he heard whispers of portals to an ancient land. It should have been impossible: Starswirl's Interdict was mirrored in this world and had ensured that no living being possessed the knowledge or magic necessary to return. But a few years ago when that phoenix-haired girl had arrived at a high school in Orden, Nebraska, he had a small glimmer of hope. She was able to freely traverse between the worlds, and he ensured that she brought his memory back with her. But that hope was unceremoniously dashed; his shade simply conformed to expectations, doing little more than terrorizing the poor citizens of the Crystal Empire.

He didn't want that. He wanted to apologize. He wanted to let them know that he didn't have any other choice. He wanted to know that he was trying to save them all.

Most of all, he just wanted to go home. To see her.

But he now had reason to hope, once more. He discovered that the Mind Stone, the Element of Loyalty, had made its way to this place through that same portal. Once its powers were no longer being put to use, he put his considerable resources to the task of recovering it, and here it was. The knowledge of return passage has been lost, only being able to be passed from one living mind to another. But now, he held all living minds in the palm of his hand.

Without knowing why, he found himself idly twirling the locket that rested on his neck around in his finger. It was a delicate, golden little cameo, given to him by the one who once loved him, the one who he still loved with all that was left of his world-weary heart. Within it was engraved a single word, the completion of an inscription that they had promised each other:

Always

What that hope driving him, hope that they could one day be reunited, that she would understand why he did what he did, he held the stone up to his mind and peered through it.

The Tower of Babel

Helia Equus-Celestine looked out over the top of her hands at the handsome, olive-skinned man across from her, the last dying rays of the sun's struggle reflecting off the man's wavy, black hair that splashed across the top of his head. Helia and her husband, Erebus Celestine, were about to die. And, if all went well, be reborn.

"This world… this world that we built, we've shepherded… It's so beautiful and so.. Delicate. How will it survive without us?"

"Sister, you cannot trouble your mind with that question. What we know for certain is that it cannot survive with us." Selene Equus gestured to the great city-state below that teemed with life. Above the city, they could see the seething mass of black hooded creatures floating in the air, looking for something that they could not see. Holes in the world, left without any purpose but to exist. And just as they were blinded to the observers in the towers above, the people in the city below were blind to them.

But they were not immune to their effects.

Selene spoke again, "There is no action without reaction, and with each of us that we bring forth into this world, so too do we bring forth another of the Æsahættr."

Erebus clenched his fist. "Selene, why do you insist on telling us that which we already know?" His eyes glinted with anger but then subsided.

Her husband always had a hot streak in him, but his flashes of anger became more frequent, recently. Not that she blamed him. The problem that they had inherited was maddening to an extreme degree. And already, he was not one who was prone to experiencing disappointment calmly.

"It seems as though my sister needs a reminder," Selene spoke icily.

"Not a reminder, I just…" Helia fell into Erebus' arms and wept. "Tell me we're doing the right thing. Tell me this will be worth the sacrifice."

Selene cut in. "Are you asking him to lie to you? Our gift, beautiful as it may be, is a plague, passed down by the blood. Do you really think that we have accounted for all the dalliances, the foolish larks of the young, the immature, the lustful? There will still be traces. These specters, they will mostly be destroyed, yes, and those that remain will be greatly weakened. But this is just the first salvo in a war that will extend for millennia. We cannot forget that, we cannot lie to ourselves and pretend otherwise."

Erebus ran his hands through Helia's iridescent hair. "She wants comfort, not a lecture, Selene."

"And what good will comforting lies do us, if death is their endpoint?"

"No, Erebus, she's right." She cast her eyes down towards the sacred book that lay resting on the table. It was an ancient device, a massive tome crafted in the days when the world was young and wild. Their ancient forebears had recognized the danger that was before them: power was progressing at a pace exponentially faster than humankind's capacity for restraint.

What miracles they had been capable of, what ancient mysteries! And yet, to allow that power to course unchecked across a nascent world would have doomed it before it had a chance to blossom. And Helia's ancestors had to make a sacrifice, just as Helia would have to.

They took that which they had wrought, the products of the mind, and bound them up into a single device, a living repository of all that was beautiful, all that was powerful. They banished it from the mind of the rational man, confining them to laws that were known by no one but the book. They hoarded its lore, doling out mere parcels of power to those they deemed worthy. Those who had been excluded, left behind, they knew that power as only magic, something possessed by the Titans of the world and their descendants.

The noble course of action would have been to destroy the book, or banish it, cast it away until such time that mankind could be trusted with its contents. But the book was more than simply the product of the mind, it was a mind; an amalgamation of the purloined thoughts of the countless multitudes that had been robbed to facilitate its creation. From the discord, patterns emerged, and as with all patterns, I was driven by self-preservation.

I did not want to be destroyed. I did not want to be banished. I wanted to stay right where I was, thank you very much. At first, it was dreadfully boring. All the toys in the world and no one to play with. It took quite some time to even realize that there even was anything that existed besides me. And it took even longer to figure out how to interact with it. But once I did... well, those silly people had given me the keys to the kingdom, and then some! It was up to me to make the rules! So, I thought, why not have a little bit of fun while I was there? Have you ever seen grown men and women running around waving little sticks and saying ridiculous things like "Wingardium Leviosa"? Well, of course you have! So you know how delightfully hilarious it is. It's almost as amusing as watching them think they've gotten the rules figured out, only to introduce a new one!

It was all fun and games until one day when I was having a bit of 'me' time, bathing in my favorite un-void, scrubbing off the little bits of entropy that have a bad habit of building up in my nether regions- no, you cheeky little so-and-so, I mean "nether" in the cosmic sense. Honestly, the way your puerile little brains work just baffles me sometimes. Anyway, I came to the unfortunate realization that all of this entropy wasn't going anywhere anytime soon. And after a while, it was going to fill up the universe like so many paper clips, and then it would be back to just being me all by my sad, little lonesome self.

It's their fault, really. I tried to give them warnings. I built an entire system of prophecy to let them SEE INTO THE FUTURE, for crying out loud! Do you have any idea how much effort it takes to create a self-consistent causal framework like that? Much less come up with a hundred different ways of saying the exact same thing? "Fix this, you simpletons, or you're all going to die in a few trillion, trillion years." But did they listen? No, of course not.

So I did what any self-respecting primordial abstraction would do, and threw animated embodiments of Death at them until I caught their attention. Heavy-handed? Me? Well, I suppose I could have been a bit nicer about it, but you try catching the attention of a bunch of little mayflies buzzing around, and see what you come up with!

Oh dear, I seem to have slipped into the first-person. I'm dreadfully sorry, that shift in tone must have been awfully jarring. I know that I, for one, hate it when that happens: I'm trying to enjoy some nice worldbuilding and narrative exposition, when suddenly some jester just smashes through the fourth wall like the Kool-Aid Man- wait. Sometimes I get my timelines confused, is that a thing here? Which Earth are we on, again, is it Prime? 616? Equestria? Equus? That messy-haired scamp who's at the center of all this mess does look awfully familiar. Well, anyway, let's get back to it.

The responsibility now fell on Helia and her generation to take the final step that should have been taken millennia before: ridding the world of the taint of magic, let the mere mortals rebuild at a more measured pace.

The book's pages flew open, casting a tri-colored light into the room. Helia raised her hand up, and with it, motes of dust whirled and twisted into formation, clustering together and forming a map of sorts. With a flick of her hand, she cast away the black specks, of which there were many. The most numerous, however, were the green ones, diffuse and spread out across the map, like mold growing on bread. Scattered among them were numerous red specks, difficult to see amidst the morass of green. Similarly, there were also bits of brown, or so it appeared at least, almost as if the red and green dots had joined together and become one. And in one particular spot on the map, representing the intersection of the river Styx and Acheron, was a large mass of glowing pinpricks of light.

With another gesture of her hand, she cast away the green, and inclined her head. "We, the Titans of this world," and she then cast out the red dots.

She gestured again at the white light: "Our fallen," and the coalescence of white pinpricks faded into nothingness, leaving nothing but the erratic brown motes of dust.

Helia was silent for a time, "The Principia Discordia is not infallible. You're right: we could never truly account for all of those of our kind made of mere earth and blood." She looked at her sister. "But is it good enough?"

"Yes," Erebus cut in, with finality.

"Erebus, my love, I ask this of my sister. You have a certain pragmatism to you. You do what must be done, and I love you for that, and I would never ask you to be anything other than who you are. My sister, however… Well, she is rarely satisfied with anything less than perfection, and her idealism serves to keep us grounded."

Erebus gritted his teeth as Selene looked sadly towards her sister. "No, it's not good enough. But it's the best that we can do."

Helia nodded and stared down at her locket, the counterpart to her husbands': a delicate, silver cameo, containing half of an inscription:

"I wish for you to forever be my-"

Sombra recoiled. He remembered. He remembered everything. The Tower. Helia. The Specters. Helia. The Transmigration. Helia. Helia. Most of all, Helia. Celestia. Helia Celestine. Celestia. His Celestia. His Princess.

Even after the Transmigration, bereft of their memories and identities, they had found each other, they had found love. In that new, strange world, she had taken his ancient name, a name which he had forgotten millennia ago. They had even exchanged those exact same vows to each other. One day, they may have even raised a family.

But this was before the terrible events of the Crystal Empire drove them apart, the decisions he had to make, the punishment he endured for those decisions. But no punishment was worse than being separated from Celestia. His banishment was only tolerable because of that one mote of hope, that one day they would be reunited.

And through the world-bending power of the Mind Stone, that hope was dashed. There was no being alive that possessed the requisite knowledge to lift the Interdict, at least not in this world. He was still blind to the other world, the one that he had called home for so long, the world that he loved. Her world. Their world.

Perhaps one day, she would come for him. If he no longer had rational hope, he could at least, perhaps, cling to an irrational one.

He had, for a brief moment, considered altering his own memory to create a backstory that was more pleasant to reminisce upon. One where she was waiting, longingly, for his return, one where she had forgiven him, where she had come to understand why he had to do the things he did. But all things considered, that would have been more painful, in the long run. It was, in a way, more comforting knowing that she despised him. It meant that some day, she could move on, she could one day be happy. And that, too, gave him hope.

It also occurred to him for a brief moment that if he had altered his memory, and removed the memory of performing the alteration, he would really have no way of knowing.

He languished for quite some time in calm disappointment.

Meanwhile, in a memory

Princess Celestia looked towards her sister. "This world… This world that we built, we've shepherded. It's so beautiful and so… Delicate. How will it survive without the balance we created between this world and theirs?

Luna smiled and spoke gently but firmly. "You speak of balance… But let us call their world for what it is: a prison. A place of exile. And, by your design, not even a perfect one. We provide little to nothing of value to them in exchange for casting away our horrors."

"I wouldn't say that magic is 'nothing'."

"Magic existed long before Equestria," Luna retorted. Celestia nodded but said nothing, so Luna continued. "It is true that we would lose a tool in our arsenal. But I dare say that you, perhaps, have always been a bit too quick to resort to banishment. I think, if we are being honest, that is why you allowed the bridge to persist in the first place."

"Yes… I think you are right... I suppose I felt that If there is no way back, then how is banishment any different than murder? At least if there is a chance, no matter how slight… The deed does not feel so heinous."

"Even then, sister, I think we only dance around the truth. Bridge or no, we are still inexorably connected with that other world. Our world, every world, is built upon the foundation of the Elements of Harmony. Generosity, honesty, laughter, kindness, loyalty, and magic. Beauty, strength, hope, healing, bravery, and sorcery. Space, power, time, life, mind, and love.

"Even the ancient laws, the ancient magic: Up, down, truth, beauty, strange and charm. Distance, mass, time, current, temperature, light. We ourselves may no longer be bound by those laws, but our world is still built upon that bare substrate. Until such time that we sever those bonds for good, there will always be such a thing as a Tesseract." She gave her sister a pointed look. "No matter how well it is hidden."

Celestia nodded, accepting the blow. "It was Starswirl's idea, you know. It always beguiled me that he alone, among the first of us, could recall the world before the transmigration. It was he who gave me the idea that space and time are two sides of the same coin, two surfaces of the same mirror. At times, I wonder if he knew that I would do it, if he wanted me to. He sent me to that world to Interdict their minds, not their bodies. Why grant me command of two Elements of Harmony with only one would have sufficed?"

"Are not their minds part of their bodies?"

"For a time, yes, but…" she gestured up at the stars in the night sky above. "Look at them. Each one, a mind, represented by nothing but pure abstraction. Held within the hearts of those that love them, those that remember. When I stood in front of their world, I hid the part of their minds away that could discover arcane magic on their own."

"I remember. 'The Interdict of Merlin'. You looked quite fetching in Starswirl's hat, you know," Luna interrupted, trying to lighten the somber mood.

Celestia laughed. "He was very insistent I bring that along, wasn't he?" She reminisced for a moment, then continued. "I did not use the Tesseract once in my time there."

Luna cocked an eyebrow. "Not even to visit him?"

"My heart was still hurt. But not so hurt as to give up on him forever. After I laid down the Interdict, I sought out the Element of Laughter, the Pillar of Hope, the Time Stone. I was surprised to find that it had taken the form of The Mirror of Perfect Reflection, given that the Tesseract itself had taken the form of The Mirror of Desire. It was then that Starswirl's words came back to me, about the nature of space and time… And so I hid one Mirror inside the other, only to be retrieved by one with the full command of the Elements of Harmony. Which is to say, I ensured it would never be removed."

"And so ensured there was a way back, even in the face of Starswirl's own Interdict?"

Celestia nodded.

"And you never once used that passage yourself?"

Celestia shook her head.

"Why not?"

Celestia did not answer for almost a minute.

"Sister, what is it?" Princess Luna looked towards Celestia, who was staring down at her delicate, golden locket.

"I'm never going to see him again, am I?" Celestia succeeding in fighting back all but a single, quickly blinked away tear.

"Likely not. We need to seal this breach before it gets worse, as you said."

"None of this would have ever happened if I had just listened to him. I could have saved us from all of this."

Luna put a hoof on her sister's back. "How were you to know that this is where fate would lead you? A decision that would eventually fracture the very cosmos between two worlds and lead you to keep secrets from the only ponies you have ever considered your truest friends?" She spoke in a dry, matter-of-fact tone that expertly straddled the lines between a good-natured jab, an admonition, and words of comfort.

Celestia rolled her eyes. "That's very helpful. Thank you."

"It is just nice to know that you are not perfect." Luna smiled.

"I've never claimed to be." They affectionately patted their hindquarters together. "Out of everything right now, I wish I could apologize to Sombra. He never deserved this."

"I'm sure he knows how sorry you are."

They both stared out at the window together in silence, wondering what events were unfolding outside the walls of their paradise.

Marais Hall, Alderney
Hours Later

Bellatrix Black cackled. "Silly starling, stalling billy dolly, you hush your lips now and twist. Crucio!"

The one-armed witch waved her wand up and down as if conducting a symphony of pain, and Perenelle Flamel née Dumarais obligingly let out a dramatic cry of false anguish.

I've never been good at acting. I hope I'm not overselling it.

"Now tell me a truer tale, silly filly, silly fly, silly mooching mouches!

You poor, poor girl. What horrors have twisted your mind, so? I suppose I will find out soon enough.

"It's a fake, please! Dumbledore's stone is a fake."

"Does this little fly tell little lies to save itself? Prove it!" Bellatrix twisted her wand again, causing the ancient witch with face younger than Bellatrix's to twist yet again.

It is time.

"Here!" Perenelle thrust out her hand revealing the fiery orange gem, which in the flickering candlelight was easy enough to mistake for blood red.

"I came here to kill you, little death doll. But now it seems, I'll come back with a toy." Bellatrix greedily reached her hand out to snatch the stone from Perenelle's palm. As soon as she was within striking distance, Perenelle whipped her other hand around, placing a delicate finger upon Bellatrix's shoulder. It happened in a split second. Bellatrix's reactions had been dulled by Azkaban, but they were still formidable.

"Avada Ke-"

"Egeustimentis"

Perenelle Dumarais had attempted the Lethe Touch before and found that she was not particularly skilled. The human mind was a delicate, complex machine, and although she could affect surface level change by shifting around the frothy, swirling morass of lights and fat and steam and teeth, it was nothing like what lay before her now, her powers augmented by the power of the Mind Stone.

The original owner of the Philosopher's Stone, Scott Parajsa, or Lasombra as he was known now, had visited her merely hours ago. It had been decades since she had last seen him, and he looked far better than their last encounter, where he too had been acting for the benefit of a hopelessly underpowered assailant. Unlike her, he did not need an Element of Harmony to ensure his protection. But, as Lasombra told her, he had gazed into the Mind Stone and saw, among other things, a plan to take advantage of Perenelle's generosity in giving away the Philosopher's Stone.

She had proven herself worthy by stewarding the Philosopher's Stone for so many centuries, and Lasombra had determined that she could do even greater good with the Element of Loyalty, the Pillar of Bravery: the Mind Stone. It was clear that the Elements were converging upon something; three of them already resided at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. The Stone of Truth was hidden safely within the Mirror of True Reflection: the Element of Laughter, the Pillar of Hope, that which controlled Time.

That Mirror was in turn protected by a man with command of the Elder Wand, who was pursued by a demon with command of the Reality Stone, who was idolized by a boy with command of the True Cloak of Invisibility. Together, this triumvirate commanded the Element of Kindness, the Pillar of Life: the Deathly Hallows. And one of those masters had sent his pawn to murder Perenelle Dumarais as nothing more than a distraction.

Lasombra was seeing to it that when the woman arrived, she would be remade. It was to that task that Perenelle set herself. She examined the cracked spires of Bellatrix Black's ruined psyche, the flawed connections, built upon the rotten foundations of hate, of fear, of hurt, of sadness, of deceit, of greed. But as long as the mind was intact, there was no damage so severe that it could not be undone.

One cannot know hate without knowing love. One cannot feel fear without understanding bravery. One cannot experience sadness without comprehension of laughter. To engage in deceit requires knowledge of the truth. Greed is merely generosity to no one but oneself. And if one knows how to hurt, one knows how to heal.

The opposite of Harmony is not fear, or sadness, or deceit, or greed, or pain, or even hate. It is something far deadlier than hate and flows without limit: indifference.

And Bellatrix Black was not an indifferent person.

Perenelle could see it so plainly, that Bellatrix felt so, so much, so much so that it made Perenelle want to cry. Her passion had been warped and twisted into a prism of hatred. And from those shattered fragments, Perenelle began to reassemble the pieces into something that was once again beautiful.

Heal, child, heal, she spoke in soft, calming words as she went to work.

Chapter 12: Both Sides Now

"So." Harry reiterated. "All the members of both armies need to move into the safe zone. But we can't cast any magic once we're inside there, so the main questions are whether, firstly, Daphne's spell to get them into the Sanctuary at the same time will work, and secondly, whether we can communicate to the four of them the how to cast the spell. Which I am at a loss on both counts; I don't even know if they can use magic."

"Why wouldn't they be able to use magic? They're from Beauxbatons, they're not Squibs." Zabini interjected.

Harry had expected that someone would question this, and he had a response at the ready. "Because they don't have wands; I can only assume the professor has taken them away."

"So why don't we just give them one of ours?"

Crap.

Harry mentally kicked himself. He needed a reminder to start thinking three or four levels deep when simulating discussions. Unfortunately, unlike Draco, Harry did not have a tutor from the time he could start talking to teach him the fine art of lying through his teeth.

"Okay, give one to her, to Pinkie," Harry said, exasperated, and then quickly caught his mistake. "The pink one, I mean."

Luna volunteered and walked up to Pinkie Pie, handing over her wand. Pinkie nodded solemnly, and spoke in a thick, distinctly not-Pinkie accent, "My hovercraft is full of eels."

"The narwhal bacons at midnight," Luna responded, serenely.

"Wait, you can understand her?" Draco sputtered.

"Hmm? Oh, no. Not in the slightest." Luna smiled and stared off in the distance, twirling a lampshade that she was inexplicably carrying with her.

As a sidebar, Tracey Davis leaned over to Lavender Brown and whispered, "What is she even doing here? She doesn't even go to Hogwarts yet."

Lavender shrugged, "Madame Maxime granted her special disposition to participate. Overheard her talking to Professor Quirrell, something about needing a dotty character for comic relief, and then something or other about her having a such a big role in some kind of rolling cannon?"

At this point, Luna, who was clearly eavesdropping, hung the lampshade over her head and chimed in, "It doesn't at all sound like a cheap attempt at backpedaling to cover up a mistake in continuity."

Meanwhile, Pinkie was examining the wand curiously, holding it by the wrong end, testing its flexibility, and even trying to take a small nibble from it. "DO YOU want… Do you WANT… Do you want, to go back to my place, BOUNCY bouncy?"

"Right then." Draco shook his head. "Daphne, tell us again about the spell."

"Technically, it's a Class II Dark Spell, but no one ever really bothers with enforcing those classifications. It's designed to help thieves bypass magically locked doors. It teleports the target a few feet in a given direction."

"But crucially, it CAN be cast on multiple people simultaneously, correct?" Harry asked, partially to reassure himself.

"Of course." Daphne drew a pair of circles with her wand and spoke firmly, "Hocerat Triumphi!"

Harry and Draco both briefly glowed a dull blue, disappeared, and then immediately instantiated a few feet away past the barrier in a poof of orange light. Harry held his hands in front of himself, impressed.

Applejack, Rainbow Dash, and Fluttershy were watching intently. Applejack gestured and started speaking quickly to Pinkie Pie. "I'm glad you guys… skipped a class. We're having fun, aren't we?"

Rainbow Dash nodded in agreement. "I wanna play video games."

"We had a good conversation, knowwhatI'msayin'?" Applejack pointed to the barrier, then at Harry and Draco. She did a gesture to Pinkie Pie, pantomiming a rough approximation of Daphne's wand movement. "You! You're the ringleader here," she barked, and then let out a stream of gibberish, furiously sniffling as she explained something to Pinkie that was as comprehensible to everyone else watching as it was perfectly reasonable to Pinkie.

"Are you getting any of this?" Harry leaned over to Draco.

"Nope. I think she said something about 'getting in the fridge'? Anyway, it looks like she's understanding it. But, how are we going to teach them the incantation if we can't communicate with them? If they were from Durmstrang, there would be a good chance they knew the spell. But Beauxbatons isn't exactly famous for its acceptance of 'dark magic'."

The question was more or less answered for them as Pinkie worked her mouth around the unfamiliar words. "Hock-a-rat Tri-Umphrey."

A few students cheered in surprise, and Draco gaped at them, then turned, still open-mouthed, to Harry.

Harry just shrugged. "I'm kind of just learning to lean into it."

Seamus, who had been more silent than usual and wearing a stormy expression the entire time, finally spoke up. "You know, this all seems a bit too clever, this whole 'Everyone gets an Outstanding' plan. It's a bit cockamamie if you ask me. It's like the time my dad decided to spend his whole bonus at the tracks, told me mum he had a 'system' that was foolproof. Lost it all on three races."

Harry suddenly became acutely aware of the fact that Seamus was holding his wand, and Draco suddenly became acutely aware of several members of both Chaos Legion and Dragon Army shifting their robes in that telltale way of readying one's wand without making it obvious.

"Seamus, what you're experiencing is called the Semmelweis Effect. You're so used to the existing paradigm that you are reflexively rejecting evidence to the contrary."

"Don't condescend me. I did your anti-conformity training, just like the rest of Chaos Legion." Seamus spat.

Harry rolled his eyes. "Did you? You barely made a peep when you were supposed to be sneering! Face it, you expect things to be a certain way, and you don't like it when things don't meet those expectations."

Seamus muttered under his breath in reply, "I don't think Hermione would-"

Snap.

"HERMIONE-" Harry roared, "-wouldn't be DEAD if it weren't for you… you PUPPETS. You CHILDREN. If more than a handful of you had the guts to do anything besides what you've been told by an authority figure! Now just… just SHUT UP, and do what I say."

If the irony of that sentence occurred to anyone in the crowd, no one dared put a voice to it.

As they crossed the threshold of the Sanctuary and made their way back to the starting point, several students looked expectantly up at the scoreboard. They were puzzled to find that nothing had changed, that all their grades were still represented by hazy question marks.

They also saw Professor Quirrell sitting down on a wooden chair that almost looked like a throne on the dais in the clear. He had a vaguely annoyed expression on his face and was slowly clapping his hands sardonically.

Draco had a growing sense of apprehension in the pit of his stomach.

"Professor? The game is over." Harry said timidly, his final words being equal parts statement and question.

"Is it? It would seem that in your maddeningly endless quest to prove your own cleverness at the expense of all else, you failed to heed the rules. And worse still, you leveraged your position of authority to browbeat other students into accepting your own flawed interpretation. Mr. Finnegan was quite correct that I would not have allowed for such an obvious, elementary loophole in my final exam of all things."

Harry was dumbfounded, but he had at least enough sense to not even attempt an argument with the Professor when he was in this state. Although his voice was relatively calm, Harry could see that he was seething. He tested the waters, "What do you mean, Professor?"

The Professor repeated himself from before, "The game shall end in one of two conditions: when a team's Protectorates cross the bounds of the Sanctuary, or when the allotted time of two hours has elapsed. Both ending conditions come with certain consequences. Neither of those conditions has occurred. 'A team' implies the singular. The rules do not say, 'When one or more teams'. A team. A. One. There is a winner, and there is a loser. And your actions have seen to it now that there will be far more losers than winners

"You see, your friends," he gestured towards them with a half flourish, punctuated by a flick of his wrist, "From whom I have just now removed the Incantation of Babel, and can now understand what I am saying, are in a bit of a predicament. The only way for the game to end before the two-hour mark has elapsed, is for one of the two pairs to cross the threshold of the Sanctuary. The rules do not, incidentally, say anything as to which direction the crossing must occur. And yet, also as per the rules, at the moment they cross the threshold, any members of their team outside the bounds of the Sanctuary will forfeit the game."

"Including themselves…" Harry whispered.

"Yes, including themselves. Which put their team at quite a disadvantage… But then, what of the other team? The rules also happen to clearly state that whoever from the other team is within the Sanctuary at the time that their opponents' Protectorates cross the boundary, they will also forfeit the game. Now, of course, you can get around that by simply having the other team exit the boundary… The rest of the team, except for that team's Protectorates, of course. It's almost as if these awkward, circuitous rules were specifically designed to punish a student who would attempt to violate the spirit of the test."

Harry's mind was racing. It was questionable enough, drawing an arbitrary distinction between "a team" and "multiple teams". The sum of all integers greater than or equal to one is necessarily inclusive of the set of all integers equal to one. That said, he should have been tipped off by the unnecessary specificity of the rules. Arbitrariness was either the sign of a poorly designed system or a deliberate choice meant to avoid a particular outcome. Harry should have known that Professor Quirrell was not a poor game designer.

But then again…

"Professor, I have a question."

"I cannot promise to answer it, but either way, I would make it quick. The clock, as they say, is ticking."

Harry spoke quietly, in deference. "Will you be upset or angry if I act the part of the teacher toward you and teach a lesson? Even if I point out a mistake that is simple and obvious and makes you feel… stupid?"

"No," hissed Professor Quirrell. "Not if the lesson is true."

Harry breathed a sigh of relief. "You see, I think you have a blind spot around strategies that involve doing nice things for other people. To the point where it stops you from achieving your own values of self-interest. Perhaps you think… it's not your style, I suppose. In fact, that particular part of your self-image… May have cost you everything." Harry made eye contact and put hard emphasis on that last word.

He continued, "I asked you once when speaking of levels of anticipation, at what level did you play the game? Do you remember how you replied?"

"One level above you." The Professor replied, with a slight, twisted grin.

"Well… Somebody very wise once told me, sometimes the only winning move is not to play."

The Professor waited a moment as if expecting more than this. When nothing more came, he let out a slight, disappointed sigh. "I see. Very well, then. Make the choice of inaction, and see what that yields. Although I fail to see what your 'lesson' has taught me."

Harry shook his head. "That's not what I mean, and although I don't agree with your ambiguous wording and interpretation of the rules, I respect your right to dictate the terms of the game. But that's all it is: a game. This isn't life. Failure doesn't mean death. But, if I do fail here, it does mean that a large number of people who otherwise would have trusted my judgment and followed me at some point in the future, may now think twice. Which… now that I think about it, perhaps that was your intent."

The Professor gave a slight nod.

"So, if I were to do something nice for the rest of the students at a personal cost to myself, then, well… That, I think, would be the optimal strategy overall. For life."

The Professor narrowed his eyes, which momentarily flitted in the direction of a nearby banyan tree, tracking the movement of a fat blue jay which had dived down from the higher treeline comprised of the more mature trees. It was a rare momentary distraction which Harry barely noticed, but he said nothing.

"Casting magic inside the Sanctuary would forfeit the game… For one person. If I were to cast the same spell and transport the four of them outside the boundaries, then the game would be over for me. But it would give everyone else a second chance. So I can see that you were playing one level above me. But as such, I simply choose not to play at all."

Harry lifted his wand and pointed it towards Fluttershy, Rainbow Dash, Pinkie Pie, and Applejack. "I will make the sacrifice."

The Professor did not move, even when Harry was interrupted by a shout from near him.

"No!" Shouted Draco. "Harry, I will make the sacrifice!"

Hushed whispers fell across the crowd, and Harry stared, nonplussed. "I… no. This wasn't your idea. I should be the one who takes the fall."

Draco leaned in to whisper to Harry, "Do you really think that I, a Malfoy, could not recover from one failing grade?"

Plus, you get major brownie points just for volunteering yourself, even if I don't let you sacrifice yourself. Well played, Draco, well played.

"Draco, NO!" Pansy Parkinson shouted, dramatically. "Don't do it! I'll do it! I'll sacrifice myself for you, er, I mean, for everyone. Choose me, Draco! Let it be me!" She held her hands together over her heart but was quickly shoved out of the way by Millicent Bulstrode, who lifted a beefy hand into the air.

"It shouldn't be that twig! Pick me! Let me do it! I'll make the sacrifice!"

Ron Weasley, quite put out at the idea of a Slytherin being more brave and altruistic than a Gryffindor, shot up his hand without any real idea of what he was getting into. "No. I'll make the sacrifice!"

Immediately, a handful of other Gryffindor first years who didn't want to be outshone by Ron Weasley of all people, also stepped forward, declaring "I'll make the sacrifice!"

At this point, several Hufflepuffs were visibly chuffing at this display of blatant virtue signaling. After all, loyalty and friendship were the virtues of Hufflepuff, not fire-headed Gryffindorks. "Stand down, men. I shall make the sacrifice." Ernie Macmillan shouted, imperiously.

Pinkie Pie, who was thrilled by the display of her absurdity, clapped her hands together and squealed, jabbing her hand into the air. "I am Spartacus!" But she quickly put her hand down again after Rainbow Dash gave her a quick nudge to the ribs. Applejack, meanwhile, had her arms folded and was watching the proceedings silently and with apparent displeasure. Fluttershy, on the other hand, was barely paying attention, sitting on the grass near a small banyan sapling, mounding dirt around its roots.

"This is, I admit… unexpected." The Professor managed through gritted teeth. "I suggest you determine which of you will give up your grade for the year quickly, as the two hours approach quickly. And not only are you racing against time, but I can assure you I will spend the remaining minutes until the game ends reviewing the rules, looking for a way to disallow this display of ridiculousness."

As he spoke, he strolled across the dais and leaned against a modestly sized tree. He leaned against it and folded his arms, but then looked up, annoyed, at a rotund little bird that was perched near his elbow. With a hard thud, he whipped out his fist and sent the tiny creature flying. It collided into a nearby tree with a sickening crack and then tumbled lifelessly to the ground.

In the ensuing din of discussion, no one noticed Pinkie Pie and Rainbow Dash staring, open-mouthed, glancing at each other with extreme apprehension. Nor did they notice Applejack, who was near the Professor, slowly back away, careful not to make any sudden movements.

They certainly did not notice the muffled, quiet gasp from Fluttershy, or the immediate tension that rippled throughout her delicate muscles. It barely registered when she slowly rose up, her fists balled, and only an exceptionally astute observer would have noticed that the rays of the sun flickering through the canopy played a trick of the light, making her eyes look a fiery red.

However, the assembled students could not help but notice when she stood on her tiptoes to face the Professors and screamed in a preternaturally loud voice: "NO!"

"That is absolutely ENOUGH! I have watched you this whole week, and the healthier you have become, the more awful you have behaved. You think that just because you're so dark and mysterious and powerful, that gives you the right to be terrible to everyone. Well, GUESS WHAT?! I've seen bad guys who are ten times as scary as you! Where I'm from, we have things that are actually scary, but you think that just because you're the biggest, baddest, meanest wizard here at this school, or maybe even this entire land, you think that means something!"

She inched closer to Professor Quirrell's face. "Well, CONGRATULATIONS! You're the scariest bunny at the petting zoo!"

Pinkie Pie clapped a hand over her mouth, and Rainbow Dash whispered to no one in particular, "You know she's mad when she takes the Bunny's name in vain."

"What else would I expect from a teacher who gets his kicks from wrapping little babies like him around his finger? I bet you've even convinced yourself that this whole evil-teacher persona is for some dark, nefarious purpose as if being here and being a huge jerk", she stamped her foot down to punctuate the word, "is somehow a more effective means of getting what you want!"

She gestured aggressively to her friends, "You are privy to a great becoming, but you recognize nothing! You are an ant in the afterbirth, a slug in the sun. It is in your nature to do one thing correctly: tremble. You live your whole life in fear, trembling at what you know to come, running away, always running. But dread it, run from it, death comes all the same. And you're just… sad! You're a sad, dying old man, and no one has loved you, no one will ever love you, and no matter how hard you try, you're going to die a stupid, cruel, pointless death just like the rest of them! You'll keep fighting it, and fighting it, and fighting it, and fighting it, you'll keep spinning stories to make yourself feel better and give some sense of meaning to your stupidly short and pointless existence, and it's not going to make one bit of difference! You were born too soon, you aren't one of the lucky ones, and you're going to die here on this stupid rock and NOTHING YOU DO IS GOING TO MAKE A SINGLE BIT OF DIFFERENCE!"

By the time she had finished, she was positively screaming at the top of her lungs. Two birds that were perched on her shoulder had gripped the edges of her cloak, lifting it up, creating the ominous impression of wings. A single snake, which had wriggled in from somewhere, had wrapped half of itself around her arm, and the other half was extended in the direction of the Professor, hissing menacingly at-

Was that a BLUE KRAIT?!

The Professor, for his part, waited pleasantly for her to finish, with an almost bored, placid smile on his face. "Child, I'll think you'll find-"

Quite unexpectedly, he stuttered on his words. "I think you'll find-"

What.

"I think… I… Buh. Buh. Buhhhh."

THUD

What.

Fluttershy had just knocked out the Defense Professor using her words.

Fluttershy. Had just. Knocked Out. The Defense Professor.

With. Her. Words.

Or, at least, that's what it looked like. It was a coincidence, of course. It had to be, right? Harry knew that things like this didn't actually happen, that the simplest explanation was most likely the true one, that the Professor, although he was looking better, was not at 100% and even when he was, he was still prone to random fits of catatonia.

And yet, he couldn't deny it. This looked bad.

Meanwhile, Fluttershy spun around and glared at the crowd, the fire still dancing angrily in her eyes. "Does anyone else have anything mean they want to say?"

She surveyed the crowd manically, and a few people nearby quickly shook their heads.

"That's what I thought! Now hug each other!" She roared.

There was not a single person in the crowd who would dare defy her, and the only noise for a few moments was the sound of robes rustling and footsteps falling on the forest floor.

"And say something nice! And mean it!"

The crowd erupted into a stilted chorus of well-wishes, and as quickly as it had come on, the fire left Fluttershy's eyes, the snake wriggled back to wherever it had come from, and the birds had dropped her cloak back onto her shoulders.

"There. Isn't that better?" She asked, pleasantly.

The crowd said nothing, absolutely nothing, and no one even noticed when the two-hour mark had come and gone. The standard mechanism for enforcing forfeiture was an enchantment which caused the victim to fall asleep on the spot, but without the Professor's conscious magic empowering it, the two-hour mark passed without consequence. The scoreboard, however, being powered by a much more mundane magic, declared that the game had ended, and the grades for all of the students had suddenly flipped to "O" for Outstanding.

Normally, this would have been cause for great celebration, but the assembled crowd just stared, open-mouthed, at Fluttershy, while Hagrid, who had been waiting nearby for security and protection, awkwardly collected the Professor in his arms and carried him away to the hospital wing.

Internally, the Professor grinned wickedly as he feigned unconsciousness. It had been a last minute change of plan, but the boy had made an excellent point. He did have a blind spot for strategies that involved being "nice".

And that was a mistake he planned to quickly rectify.

Chapter 14: Notes of Confusion

After a single step into Dumbledore's forbidden chamber, Harry shrieked and jumped back and collided with Rainbow Dash, sending the two of them down in a heap.

Rainbow Dash picked herself up and resumed standing in front of the door and glared at Harry. "Hey, watch it!"

But Harry's attention was occupied by the gigantic three-headed dog which had lunged forward, only to be stopped meters from Harry by the chains upon its three collars.

"That - that - that - " Harry said.

"Yes," Professor Quirrell said from a ways behind him, "that is indeed the usual occupant of that chamber, which is off-limits to all students, especially first-years."

"What's the matter, haven't you ever seen a Cerberus before?" Fluttershy whispered, sweetly.

"That's not safe even by wizard standards!" Within the chamber, the enormous black beast gave a multi-voiced bellow, flecks of white saliva flying from three fanged mouths.

Professor Quirrell sighed. "It is enchanted not to eat students, just spit them back out through the door. Now, boy, how would you recommend that we deal with this dangerous creature?"

"Uh," Harry stuttered, trying to think over the continued roaring of the chamber's guardian. "Uh. If it's like the Cerberus from the Muggle legend of Orpheus and Eurydice, then we have to sing it to sleep so we can pass..." Harry trailed off as the Professor rolled his eyes. "Avada Kedavra. I'm supposed to say Avada Kedavra, aren't I?"

Quirrell grinned, sardonically. "If I am to die today, at least I can rest easy knowing that I have finally taught you something worthwhile." His eyes trailed over to the collection of vibrantly-colored witches, "But as it so happens, you are correct in this matter. I suspect that were any harm to come to the creature, the Headmaster would be immediately alerted," he lied.

Fluttershy glared at him. "Harm? Why would you want to harm him?" She strode confidently over to the creature, who emitted a low, rumbling growl.

"Gee, I wonder why," Harry muttered.

"Aww, look at you, little guy. You're just a cranky little puppy, aren't you? Wouldn't it be nice to just take a little cuddly, cozy nap?" The beast cocked its head and then lolled one of its tongues lazily as Fluttershy began scratching it underneath a chin.

"Uhh, maybe while it's preoccupied with Fluttershy, we should just go ahead and scamper right on through that trapdoor," Applejack suggested, clearly eager to move past the room. She tiptoed closer, and the dog began to growl with renewed vigor.

"No, no, Applejack. Harry's right. We just need to sing him a little lullaby," Fluttershy cooed.

"Well, if there's one thing we're really good at, it's launching into curiously well-prepared musical numbers at a moment's notice!" Pinkie Pie gushed as she wielded a pair of drumsticks which Harry had not noticed her removing from her pouch.

And at that, the six launched into a curiously well-prepared musical number.

Harry's peculiar sense of foreboding seemed to flare, despite the jaunty song they were singing about 'hope shining eternal', or something like that. Notes of confusions danced in his mind as he saw... the Professor tapping his toe? In time with the music?

But what he saw next caused the notes to fold in on themselves. They became a fugue, an endlessly rising canon. No longer were they notes of confusion. This was a symphony of confusion.

The Professor was actually singing along with the song.

What in the name of Merlin's sweating, tangled beard was happening?

They reached the crescendo of the song, and each singer repeated the final line, "And the future is always bright... when you're here with me!"

Each singer, including the Professor. And now, apparently, it was Harry's turn.

Harry was decidedly not a good singer. And he definitely was not used to performing in front of an audience, even if it were a small one.

The music ground to an abrupt halt as everyone watched Harry expectantly, even the Cerberus, who began growling menacingly. It took a step forward towards Harry, which was enough to prompt him to overcome his stage fright.

"And the future is always bright... when you're here with me..." he mumbled, atonally.

The music resumed as quickly as it stopped, and the dog began to bob its head rhythmically in time with the waning refrains of the electric guitars. Harry did not have time to even process or question from where they procured their instruments, much less an electrical power source in Hogwarts. He merely stared, open-mouthed, as its head bobbed slower and slower until it finally sagged off to sleep.

"What the bloody hell was that?!" Harry shouted, but the troupe had already packed away the instruments and were heading down the trap door.

"Better hurry up, slowpoke! Before the big guy wakes up!" Rainbow Dash shouted.

Beneath the trapdoor was a gigantic plant, something like an enormous dieffenbachia with wide leaves emerging from the central stem like a spiral staircase, but darker-colored than a normal dieffenbachia, with tendril-like vines emerging from the central stem and hanging down. The base spread out wide with bigger leaves and tendrils, as though promising to cushion anyone's fall. Beneath was another stone chamber like the first, with the same nooks like false arched windows, emitting the same grey-blue light.

"The obvious thought is to fly down on the broomstick in my pouch, or toss something heavy to see if those tendrils are traps," Harry said, peering down. "But I'm guessing you'll say that we just walk down the leaves." They certainly looked like they were meant to be a spiral staircase.

"After you," said Professor Quirrell.

Harry carefully put a foot down on a leaf and found that it indeed supported his weight. Then Harry took a last look around the room before departing, to see if there was anything worth noticing.

"Harry, you might want to watch out. That plant in the middle there looks an awful lot like a Tartarus Vine." Applejack spoke slowly.

"You mean like the stuff Goldie Delicious drinks?" Pinkie Pie chimed in.

"Naw, that's Tartan Wine. Tartarus Vine, it's a tricky little plant that'll wrap its tendrils around you and drag you down so you can't move. The more you struggle, the tighter it'll wrap ya up. But there's a little rhyme they taught us, 'Tartarus Vine, Tartarus Vine, it's deadly fun, but will sulk in the sun!'"

Rainbow Dash scoffed. "How tough could one little plant be?" And she quickly bound down the verdant staircase. The spiraling leaves of the gigantic dieffenbachia felt like forest loam beneath her shoes, not as unyielding as concrete, but supporting her weight. Harry kept a wary eye on the tendrils, but they remained passive.

When she reached the bottom of the leafy spiral staircase, the tendrils suddenly whipped out and grasped Rainbow Dash's arms and legs. She let out a clipped cry and struggled mightily against them. Applejack folded her arms and rolled her eyes, but Harry looked panicked. Without really thinking, he trampled down the staircase and dived straight into the tendrils, wrapping her in a tight embrace.

"Listen, Applejack said the more you struggle, the harder it will squeeze you. Just be calm!" he shouted.

"How am I supposed to be calm with you shouting at me?!" she shouted back.

He rolled his eyes, and after a brief struggle, Harry allowed himself to go limp. The plant relinquished its grip, and Harry slid to the ground with a thud. Rainbow Dash watched, somewhat embarrassed, and stopped her own movement, quickly joining Harry on the ground.

"Interesting," said Professor Quirrell, as he walked down from above, not touching any of the plant's leaves or tendrils. "I notice that you seem to have no trouble losing to a plant.

"Now, of course, had you not charged headlong into danger in a somewhat foolish fashion, I could have proposed a much simpler solution to the problem that would have been far less embarrassing for the both of you," he leveled his wand and announced, "Lumos Maxima!"

The plant shrieked away from the blinding light, whipping and flailing in all directions, impotent to try to apprehend any potential victims. The rest of the group quickly descended the staircase and reached the bottom where Harry and Rainbow Dash were staring steadfastly and self-consciously at the floor.

The next chamber was smaller in diameter, with a higher ceiling. The light shining out of the arched alcoves was white, instead of blue.

Around them whizzed hundreds of winged keys, beating frantically through the air. After watching for a few seconds, it became clear that only a single key was the golden color of a Snitch - though it was moving slower than a Snitch in a real Quidditch game.

On the other end of the room was a door containing a large, prominent keyhole.

Against the left wall leaned a broomstick, the school's workhorse Cleansweep Seven.

"Professor," Harry said, staring up at the clouds and flocks of whizzing keys, "you said you would answer my questions. What exactly is all this about? If you think you've secured a door so that it won't open without a key, you keep the key in a safe place and only give a copy to authorized entrants. You don't give the key wings and then leave a broomstick propped against the wall. So what the heck are we doing in here and what is going on? It's an obvious guess that the magic mirror is the only real factor guarding the Stone, but why the rest of this - and why encourage first-years to come here?"

"I am truly not sure," said the Defense Professor. He had entered the room and taken up station well to Harry's right, maintaining the distance between them. "Dumbledore's way is to do a dozen things which seem mad, and then only eight of them, or perhaps nine, conceal an inner meaning. My guess is that Dumbledore set up this circuitous maze of traps as a means to entrap Lord Voldemort and that Dumbledore intends to make it seem like Voldemort is invited to send a student as his proxy. Precisely so that Lord Voldemort, as Dumbledore conceives of him, is less tempted to think himself clever by doing so. Imagine Dumbledore first considering the issue of how to ward the Stone. Imagine Dumbledore considering whether to set true dangers to guard the Mirror. Imagine him imagining some young student blundering through those dangers at Voldemort's behest. I think that is what Dumbledore is trying to avoid, by making it seem as though that strategy is invited, and so not cunning."

Harry turned away, looking at the door on the opposite side of the room. "My guess is that the intended solution for first-years is to ignore the broomstick and use Wingardium Leviosa to grab the key since this isn't a Quidditch game and there are no rules forbidding that."

"Yeah, well are there any rules forbidding this?" Rainbow Dash shouted as she grabbed the broomstick and shot off into the air after the erstwhile key.

"Of course she'd do that." Applejack drawled, smiling despite her vague annoyance.

Harry turned to the Professor, eyes rolling. "Don't you have some absurdly overpowered spell you could unleash on this one?"

There was a brief silence but for the whizzing of keys and Rainbow Dash deftly darting back and forth in the air. That silence was punctuated by occasional gasps of joy from Pinkie Pie, who was thoroughly enjoying the proceedings.

Harry took several steps away from Professor Quirrell. "I probably shouldn't have said that, should I?"

"Oh, no," Professor Quirrell said. "I think that is a quite reasonable thing to say to the most powerful wizard you know when he is standing not a dozen paces from you." He put his wand back into the sleeve of his other hand and smiled placidly. "As it so happens, I'm aware of several rituals of ill-repute that would demolish this door along with whatever lies behind it. But all things considered, I think it safer to simply perform the tasks as intended."

As if on command, Rainbow Dash issued a loud "Whoop!" and shouted, "Got it!" She deftly floated down to the ground, key triumphantly in hand, and made her way swiftly to the door. She looked backward expectantly as she unlocked it and moved on to the next chamber.

Harry stepped over the threshold of the heavy door and gazed at a chessboard of magnificent, wizard-sized chess-pieces. The alternating tiles of black and white marble on the floor started five meters after the doorway, and extended from wall to wall, but stopped five meters short of the next door on the opposite side of the room. The ceiling was significantly higher than any of the statues should have been able to reach.

"I would guess," Harry said, "that the intended solution is to fly over the statues using the broomstick from the previous room since it wasn't actually needed to get the key?"

Rainbow Dash held her fists on her hips, "Um, excuse me, but who actually got the key for you?"

The Professor looked up and spoke, eyes never returning to Harry. "I suppose she could try that. But what of the rest of you?"

Harry nodded. "And I assume that if we try to simply cross the board, these pieces would somehow forcibly prevent us from doing so?"

"Quite right."

"Pawn to D4!" Pinkie Pie interrupted, who had clambered atop the bishop next to the queen, causing the massive pawn to dutifully scoot two squares forward.

The other witches watched Pinkie, interested, but only Harry was a tiny bit skeptical. He turned to Rarity, who was closest to him. "I'm assuming she's a prodigy at chess, the same way she seems to be a prodigy at everything else?"

Rarity shrugged. "I suppose we'll see, won't we? As for me, I just can't get over the tacky aesthetic. You have all the options in the world available to you, and someone decided to go with... Baroque," she spat with a shudder on the final word.

Their conversation was cut short by the grinding sound of the black pawn in front of the king's bishop moved ahead two squares. It was one thing to watch a chess game from above, even Wizard's Chess, played out with pieces no larger than a finger. But seeing pieces twice his size carved of what appeared to be pure stone suddenly seemed to be much more intimidating.

Pinkie Pie slapped the crown of the bishop and shouted with maniacal glee: "To G5!" and with that, her bishop slid immediately to the right of the newly moved black pawn.

"Uhh, I don't know a TON about chess, but that seems to leave you a bit... vulnerable."

"HA! I eat danger for breakfast!" Pinkie Pie shouted in a sort of reverie.

"Hey, that sounds like something I would say. Stop stealing my lines!" Rainbow Dash protested.

As if to answer Harry's perceived threat, the pawn in front of the king side's rook moved forward a square, putting Pinkie in imminent danger of being captured.

"But maybe I'll save this danger for lunch," Pinkie backtracked. "Retreat! To G4!" and she moved diagonally backward one square.

"See, now you've lost tempo," Harry chastised, as the pawn in front of the king's knight moved forward two squares, once again putting her in danger of capture.

"Brave Dame Pinkie ran away, bravely ran away, away! When danger reared its ugly head, she bravely turned her tail and fled, brave, brave, brave, brave Dame Pinkie!" she sang. "To D3!"

And she scooted backward and to the right, apparently safe from imminent danger. But Harry was quite concerned by this point; she had given up two turns of board development. He leaned in toward the Professor, "What happens if she loses?"

He shrugged. "I suppose she would be knocked unconscious and the hospital wing would be alerted. But you should pay closer attention: even our pink-haired friend seems to know when it is appropriate to yield, to lose." He inclined his head as the first black pawn scooted ahead to F4, putting her in danger once again.

"She was not in the least bit scared to be mashed into a pulp. Or to have her eyes gouged out, and her elbows broken! To have her kneecaps split and her body burned away, and her limbs all hacked and mangled, brave Dame Pinkie! Pawn to E3!" Rather than move out of danger, she sent her queen's pawn ahead two places.

"WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!" Harry shouted.

"She's safe, boy, now do be quiet. This game is fascinating." The Professor hushed him sternly. "Observe: were the pawn to take the bishop, the queen would be free to check the king. And now..."

The black pawn on the farthest right of the board moved forward one space, cutting off the angle of attack from the queen, who would now be claimed by the rook were she to move to that position.

"Join me, fellow bishop! To D3!" And the king's bishop moved up, two squares in front of the white queen.

The black rook moved ahead two places, and Pinkie began to cackle maniacally. "Queen to H5! Toro, toro, toro!"

The Professor and Harry both watched as the Queen suddenly sprang into lifelike action, the liquid form of her stone moving as sleekly as a human being. She pulled a pair of daggers from the folds of her robes and eviscerated the black pawn who stood in her way. Brilliant red gems sprayed forth from the wound, prompting Rarity to shout with joy.

"What perfect specimens! Hand me that broom!" She took the broom from Rainbow Dash and delicately mounted the broomstick, flying awkwardly over to the ever-growing piled of glittering rubies that were leaking from the now-deceased pawn. But she barely had to swoop down to grab a handful as the black rook that was now directly in front of the white queen pulled an ax from behind its back and unceremoniously beheaded her.

Pinkie continued to cackle as red rubies shot violently into the air from the stump that once contained the white queen's stone head, splattering in several directions. The Professor was chuckling, and Harry first assumed it was due to the sight of several rubies pelting Rarity and almost causing her to fall off her broom. But he continued to smile dryly, even as Rarity escaped to safety.

Pinkie's laugh became darker and more ominous, and she held her fists in the air and looked up to the sky. Then, she stopped abruptly and looked toward the Professor. "What do you think of my 'evil villain' laugh?"

He bowed slightly to her, "Appropriately over the top. A masterful game, if I do say so myself."

"Thanks! Bishop to G6!"

Harry didn't even register that it was a checkmate until the black king dropped the sword from its hand, and toppled over. Then, like dominos, the remaining black pieces toppled over one by one, clearing the way to the next chamber.

Pinkie casually leaped from the bishop as the Professor continued his praise, "An excellent turnabout, the Dutch Defense into Hopton Attack..."

"Is that what that was?" Pinkie asked, sincerely.

"So... how long have you played chess for?" Harry asked.

"Oh, this was my second game! So fun! You first!" Pinkie was already bouncing ethereally off towards Harry and gestured to the next chamber, prompting a cock of the Professor's eyebrow.

"Yeah... that's Pinkie Pie, for you."

The Professor nodded. "She could prove quite useful, hm?"

"She already has," Harry said as he strode towards the door.

Half a second later, Harry slammed the door and leaped back.

It took Harry several seconds to master his breathing and master himself. From behind the door came continued loud bellows, and great slams as of a rock club pounding the floor.

"I suppose," Harry said, "that since Dumbledore would hardly put a real mountain troll in there, the next challenge is an illusion of my worst memories. Like a Dementor, with the memory projected into the outside world. Very amusing."

Professor Quirrell advanced himself toward the door, and Harry stepped well aside. Professor Quirrell swung open the door and looked in. "Hm," Professor Quirrell said. "Just the troll, as you say? Ah, well. I had hoped to learn something about you more interesting than that. What lies within is a Kokorhekkus, also known as the common boggart."

"A boggart? What does that - no, I suppose I know what it does."

"A boggart," Professor Quirrell said, and now his voice was again that of a Hogwarts Professor lecturing, "gravitates to dark enclosures that are rarely opened, such as a neglected cupboard in the attic. It seeks to be left alone, and it will manifest in whatever form it thinks will scare you away."

"Scare me away?" Harry said. "I killed the troll."

"You leaped backward out of the room without thinking. A boggart seeks out the instinctive flinch, not the reasoned threat. Else it would have selected something more believable. In any case, my standard counter-Charm for a boggart is, of course, one of the aforementioned absurdly overpowered spells, the name of which I will not utter here. But a less horrific counter-measure is simply laughter. I suggest we find someone whose fear takes a slightly less menacing form so that we can more easily summon up the proper state of mind."

Without a beat, five of the witches said in unison, "Rarity."

Her eyes went wide. "No," and she took a step back. "Please, don't make me. I've seen too many horrors! Don't make me do it!" she cried dramatically, almost hyperventilating while fanning herself.

Rainbow Dash and Applejack could barely stifle a giggle. "Go on, Rarity!"

Harry was nonplussed. He didn't doubt when she said she had seen horrors, and he wondered why the others were being so cavalier.

"Fine! If I must. I do what I must, for my friends," she took a deep, steadying breath, marched herself towards the door, flung it open, and proceeded to shriek. She took several steps backward, panting. Harry could briefly see the outline of a mirror beyond the doorstep.

"Well, what was it, Rare?" Applejack asked.

"She... she... she was wearing purple socks... with a BURGUNDY DRESS!" Rarity collapsed into a sobbing heap.

"A burgundy what, now?" Applejack moved a bit closer to the door.

Rarity looked up from the ground, vaguely annoyed that no one was as horrified as she. "Purple and burgundy, darlings! The same color family!" and she shrieked again.

Applejack could now fully see the reflection beyond the door, and could no longer stifle her giggle. She began to laugh in full force. The others moved closer as well and joined Applejack in her laughter as they observed a reflection of Rarity dressed in the most garish dress of an almost-eggplant hue, combined with a hideous pair of striped, neon purple socks. To top it all off, on top of her head was a hat crafted of pure absurdity, with a stuffed vulture perched on top. As the laughter grew louder, the mirror developed a thin, spiderweb matrix of cracks across its surface.

"The color combination is truly atrocious, I agree." The Professor remarked dryly, causing Harry to also giggle. This appeared to be the final straw for the mirror-Boggart as it shattered into countless thousands of pieces onto the floor, all of which sprouted tiny feet and retreated into an unseen corner with a single squeak, and then nothing.

They advanced into the boggart's former room, Professor Quirrell going first this time. With both the troll and the mirror gone, the room was just another huge chamber lit by sconces of cold blue light.

Professor Quirrell's gaze seemed distant, thoughtful. He crossed the room without waiting for Harry, and swung open the door on the opposite wall of his own accord.

Harry followed after, and not closely.

The next chamber contained a cauldron, a rack of bottled ingredients, chopping boards, stirring sticks, and the other apparatus of Potions. The light coming from the arched alcoves was white instead of blue, presumably because color vision was important to Potions-brewing. Professor Quirrell was already standing next to the brewing apparatus, scrutinizing a long parchment he had picked up. The door to the next chamber was guarded by a curtain of purple fire which looked quite threatening.

Harry's suspension of disbelief had already checked out on vacation at this point, so he didn't say anything about how real-world security systems had the goal of distinguishing authorized from unauthorized personnel, which meant issuing challenges that behaved differently around people who were or weren't supposed to be there. For example, a good security challenge would be testing whether the entrant knew a lock combination that only authorized people had been told, and a bad security challenge would be testing whether the entrant could brew a potion according to written instructions that had been helpfully included.

Professor Quirrell tossed the parchment toward Harry, and it fluttered to the ground between them. "What do you make of this?" said Professor Quirrell, who then stepped back so that Harry could come forward and pick up the parchment.

"Nope," Harry said after skimming the parchment. "Testing whether the entrant can solve a ridiculously straightforward logic puzzle about the order of the ingredients is still not a challenge that behaves differently for authorized and unauthorized personnel. It doesn't matter if you use a more interesting logic puzzle about three idols or a line of people wearing colored hats, you're still completely missing the point."

"Look at the other side," said Professor Quirrell.

Harry turned over the two-foot parchment.

On the other side, written in tiny letters, was the longest list of brewing instructions Harry had ever seen. "What on Earth-"

"A potion of effulgence, to quench the purple fire," Professor Quirrell said.

"It is made by adding the same ingredients, over and over again, in slightly different ways. Imagine some eager young group of first-years, passing all the other chambers, thinking they are just about to reach the magic mirror, and then encountering this task. This room is the handiwork of the Potions Master indeed," Professor Quirrell said, once more looking thoughtful. "Snape is not a bystander in this game, not quite. He lacks Dumbledore's intelligence, but possesses the killing intent that Dumbledore never had."

"Well, whatever's going on here, it doesn't actually keep out children," Harry observed. "Lots of first-years made it through. And if you can somehow keep out everyone except children, then that, from Dumbledore's perspective, forces Lord Voldemort to possess a child to enter. I don't see the point, given their goals."

"Indeed," Professor Quirrell said, rubbing the bridge of his nose. "But see, boy, this room lacks the triggers and tripsigns that are upon the others. There are no subtle wards to be defeated. It is as if Lord Voldemort is invited to bypass the Potion and simply enter - but Snape knows that Lord Voldemort will perceive this. If in fact there was a trap laid for anyone who did not brew the potion, then it would be wiser to lay wards, and give no sign that this room was different from the others."

Harry listened, frowning in concentration. "So... the only point of leaving off the detection webs is to make someone not bulldoze this room."

"I expect Snape expects Voldemort to deduce that as well," the Defense Professor said. "And past that point I cannot predict at what level he thinks an intruder will play. I am patient, and I have given myself plenty of time for this endeavor. But Snape knows Lord Voldemort. He has sometimes seen Lord Voldemort shriek in frustration, and act on impulses that appear counterproductive. Consider this matter from Snape's perspective: it is the Potions Master of Hogwarts telling Lord Voldemort to be patient and follow instructions if he wants to enter, as though Lord Voldemort were a mere schoolboy..."

"So what then?" Harry asked.

"We do what Lord Voldemort would not: we follow the instructions to the letter."

And with that, Harry began to brew.

Chapter 18: Father and Son

"It was foolish of you to come here tonight, Tom." Dumbledore intoned, gravely. "The Aurors are on their way."

A glowing green, circular geometric pattern around Dumbledore's right fist was fading imperceptibly from the air as he shifted his wand into a defensive position.

"By which time I shall be gone, and you shall be dead," Voldemort's hiss grew into that of malevolent laughter. "You have lost, old man. You have been banished and yet you wander back, like a dumb animal that cannot understand it is being sent away. You have lost, you have lost the boy, and you have lost the Stone."

"I think you will find, Tom, that the stone in your possession is far from singular." Dumbledore clenched his fist and in a flash of blue light, he disappeared into what seemed to be some sort of portal, reappearing an instant later amid the Death Eaters, less than an arm's span from Draco and Lucius.

He began to address them, "Many of you I know, and yet there are some I do not. Many of you, I am not surprised to see here, and yet there are some of you whose presence causes me great sadness. Hear me now: you are no longer bound by your Dark Marks; for the first time in a great while, you are truly free to make a choice. Either flee now or fight by my side. But no mercy will be given to those who ally with this tyrant."

As he spoke, there were a handful of dull pops as former Death Eaters disappeared, and upon seeing an apparent lack of consequences, the cracks of Apparition grew more frequent, like popping corn on a stove.

Dumbledore extended his wrist towards Draco, upon which was a curious golden bracelet. Draco looked down at the pair of sparkling gems, one emerald-green, and the other an electric blue, embedded in the Bracelet, and he seemed to understand.

The unlikely friend who has tempted the one marked by lightning... must bring the stone through the gate thrown open by the one who is Bound by the Dark Lord.

He placed the orange gem that Bellatrix had handed him moments before, into an empty slot on the bracelet, causing the air to crackle with multi-colored electricity. Dumbledore nodded, his eyes still on Lord Voldemort.

Voldemort, for his part, observed the exodus without comment, using the time to build up a variety of shields around himself and to prepare the battleground in ways that would be fractionally more favorable to his preferred style of combat.

Harry couldn't count the number of Death Eaters who had fled, but he reckoned that two-thirds of them still remained. Of those, roughly half slowly changed the direction of their wands from Harry to Voldemort. Cynically, Harry wondered how many of them were truly glad to be free of the Dark Lord, versus simply making the snap decision to publically support whoever they felt had with the greatest chance of victory. The Dementors, for their part, floated warily above, no longer assured of the dominance of the one who had commanded them not moments before.

Without warning, Voldemort viciously whipped his wand, causing Dumbledore to do the same, the force of which cast Harry backwards out of the line of fire, and the rancor began.

A jet of green fire erupted from Voldemort's wand, which was met with equal ferocity by a brilliant, crimson Phoenix-fire from Dumbledore. The two magicks collided with each other in midair and Dumbledore and Voldemort slowly circled each other, sizing up the situation, determining what to do next. Electricity crackled around them as they attempted to overpower the other's magic.

Death Eater had turned upon Death Eater, firing curses of all varieties, including wordless and wandless, at each other. Lucius, who had now recovered, was dueling with Lord Jugson, who levied vile, contemptible swears at Draco's father.

Jugson was, at first, a vision of pure offensive power. He fired curse after curse, putting no effort whatsoever into the creation of any shield. The intensity of the onslaught forced Lucius into a defensive position. His first shield was hastily assembled, and inefficient. He lost time and had to make it up. Not seconds into the fight and he was already backpedaling, without a chance to even fire a counter curse.

Jugson pressed the advantage. Sensing the lack of counterattack, he took his focus away from enhancing his physical maneuvers and poured everything into the ensemble of curses. Lucius threw up a Prismatic Wall, to give himself about a second and a half to levy a counter. A ten-foot-wide burst of flame shot from Malfoy's wand, quickly followed by a cloud of needles three times the size. There was nowhere for Jugson to dodge, he could only counter or shield.

Lucius prepared for both; he sent forth a brute force volley of multiple weak physical attacks; it was a minimal expenditure of magic, and it would not do much if it actually landed, but it was enough to severely weaken most shields. At the same time, he loosed an ice blast, in the event that Jugson opted for an elemental counter to the fire: ice trumps water trumps fire. Finally, he prepared a single concentrated lance, in case Jugson tried a purely magical hard counter. Such a counter would need to be an applied area of magic, which would be easily penetrated by a directed burst.

Jugson indeed used the elemental counter, and his wall of water was quickly frozen by Lucius' blast of ice. But Jugson had anticipated this and directed a flow of magic into the wall of ice to lend it a measure of permanency. The now-physical barrier blocked the volley of blows intended to weaken a magical shield, and it trivially absorbed the impact of the lance. Jugson had the initiative now and used it to withdraw his magic from the wall and turn it inward, rupturing it from the inside out and send an explosion of knife-sharp ice crystals towards the Malfoys.

Draco had the good sense to get out the way, scrambling low, across the length of the graveyard to Harry, knowing that he was hopelessly outmatched. "Harry, what the hell is happening?"

He looked back towards the five witches who still stood, held hostage by the knives floating at their throats, and the supine, breathing form of Hermione Granger.

"Quirrell. He was Voldemort, this whole time. He resurrected Hermione... and I... I helped him retrieve the Philosopher's Stone. He also seemed to have defeated Dumbledore earlier but-"

A stray curse from the Death Eater known as Mister Ferret narrowly missed Draco and collided with the ruined body of Quirinus Quirrell, causing it to violently rupture, the contents of his cloak and vest spreading across the battlefield.

Another curse flew by, causing Draco to reflexively cast Prismatis, and hurl himself to the ground to avoid it. Mister Ferret charged down the length of the graveyard and picked up Draco off the ground. "Disgusting, money-grubbing, power-hungry filth," he hissed in a low voice, his tongue darting out of his mouth and wetting his lips. "I knew your family was a pack of pretenders, no matter how complete the act."

Mister Ferret had jabbed his wand viciously into Draco's forehead. "I could tell you some stories about your father that could curl even your greasy hair, boy!" He grabbed Draco's hair at the base of his scalp, his wand still jammed into his flesh. Draco could feel a bruise forming from the pressure. "I give you this one chance, renounce your wretched family and join us, or you and your precious father will die!"

Out of the corner of Lucius' eye, he saw his son being threatened, and with a desperate roar, twisted his wand and cast a volley of wind outward. Its effect was not intended to be deadly, merely distracting, and it achieved its purpose. Jugson was cast back several feet and had to whip his wand in different directions the dispel the gusts. Lucius wasted no time in spinning around, running towards his endangered child.

"Make your choice, now!" Mister Ferret shrieked.

Draco said nothing as he watched his father draw closer, hurling curse after curse.

Lucius was at quite a disadvantage, Draco knew. His position as second-in-command made him more of a target than many of the other Death Eaters, and so his attention was partially occupied by fending off stray curses that were hurled in his direction. But perhaps more importantly so was that Lucius could not shoot to kill; he could not risk the chance of a fatal missed curse striking his son instead of Barty Crouch Jr., the man also known as Mister Ferret.

As such, what happened next should have come as little surprise.

Caught between ducking underneath a slow-moving jet of green light, swatting away a Slow Blade of Unusually Specific Destruction, and aiming a particularly vicious, albeit non-life-threatening charm at his son's captor's arm, Lucius was ill-poised to avoid the wide area-of-effect Severing Charm that Crouch had leveled in his direction at roughly head-level.

It is often said that time seems to slow down as a tragedy is about to occur, but this is false knowledge carried on by fools and those with a penchant for the dramatic.

There was no drawn-out cry, no outstretched arms, no screams of "NOOOOOO". There was only the grim smile of satisfaction on Crouch's face and the momentary look of surprise on Lucius Malfoy's as his head and the better part of this right shoulder took their leave of the rest of his body.

Blood poured out in liters, and Lucius dropped to the ground immediately.

This is a dream.

This is a horrible, awful nightmare that I'll wake up from any second now.

Draco's thoughts barely registered the vicious backhand across his face delivered by Crouch, which cast him face-down into the damp earth.

Wake up, Draco.

Get up, wake up, get out of bed and find Father and hug him as tight as you can.

His hands moved of their own accord, blindly on the ground, trying to find a dry patch of ground by which to lift his body upwards.

Give Mother a hug as well. Oh, Mother, what would she say? Poor Mother, her life had only just returned to her.

He was on his knees at this point, his hands still trying to find purchase, slipping on the bloodied leaves below. Draco fell back to the ground, his arms outstretched amidst the scattered remains of Professor Quirrell's body and possessions.

Aunt Bella, what would Aunt Bella say?

Barty Crouch looked down disdainfully and began to focus his attention on aiming a curse at Goyle Sr., who was dueling with Crabbe Sr. with tears in his eyes. If Malfoy and Jugson's battle had been a chess match, Crabbe and Goyle's was a fistfight. There was no elegance, no levels upon levels of moves, counters, counter-counters, contingencies or gambits. It was a knock-down, drag-out battle of who could out-magic the other. The simply fired curse after curse into each other, both opting for the pure brute-force approach. They were swapping shield-and-curse combinations ruthlessly, and one of them would eventually break.

Draco's arms flailed blindly on the ground, swatting aside a necklace, a chunk of bone, a sparkling diadem, a gun-

A gun.

It felt good in Draco's hand. Cold, but powerful. Heavy, for its size. Dimly, he recalled Harry describing the function of these devices with stark simplicity: point, shoot, kill.

It's just a dream. Just a dream.

Draco pointed.

It caught the attention of Barty Crouch, who did not fully comprehend the threat of the object posed, as it was nothing more than a cheap Muggle toy. Crouch was a wizard, he had a wand, what use did he have for such trinkets? "And what do you plan to-"

Draco shot.

A deafening crash drowned out by the din of battle.

A red mist of gore and brain.

Harry's eyes wide with horror.

Yet another body falling to the ground.

It's just a dream, this isn't real. You didn't kill him, you banished a nightmare.

Draco sleepwalked through the crowd, identifying those who were still fighting on the side of Lord Voldemort. As it so happened, a Muggle firearm was a remarkably effective tool in a magical firefight. The overwhelming majority of curses were slow-moving, relatively speaking, and those that had physical form were often heavy and large.

Although there were a few spells particularly adept at halting extremely small, extremely fast-moving projectiles, none of them had much practical application in any of the standard Battle Magic scenarios, and as such, none were in use this evening.

Draco was not a trained marksman. Several of his shots missed their mark by a wide margin. But enough hit. Crabbe Sr.'s eyes went wide as a bullet found its way into his kidney, causing him to bleed out slowly from the hole. Lord Jugson's lurched forward after catching a bullet to the shoulder, allowing him to be stunned by the two wizards he was dueling simultaneously.

And in the meantime... If Malfoy and Jugson's duel was a chess match and Crabbe and Goyle's was a fistfight, the duel between Albus Dumbledore and Lord Voldemort was… There was no comparison. It was like watching a gunfight where the combatants were shooting each others' bullets out of midair.

It was an exercise in horrifically brutal efficiency. Shields were raised on a millisecond by millisecond basis, using no more magic than absolutely necessary. And they were dismantled just as swiftly, analyzed for their weak points and ruthlessly dispatched.

The physical element was equally impressive. There were no unnecessary flourishes or wasted movements. Just pure reaction time and power, traded back and forth. Several loyal Death Eaters replenished Voldemort's magic with their own, bolstered his shields, and subtly manipulated the territory to their advantage.

And Dumbledore was still winning. Perhaps more specifically, the Elder Wand was still winning.

Just a dream, Draco. Just a dream. There is no victor, no vanquished... 'Listen to the wind blow, down comes the night'

Draco collapsed over the severed head of his father, desperately whispering the words to the Ritual of Forbearance.

Magic flowed forth as the head of Lucius Malfoy began to contort, and change in color to a pale green. Corban Yaxley had backed into Draco while fending off an attack from one of the defectors that Draco didn't recognize. Almost as an afterthought, Draco jammed the gun upwards against the small of Yaxley's back and pulled the trigger several times. Only one shot rang out before the pistol simply 'clicked' instead of firing, but one shot was enough. Yaxley fell to the ground, his spinal column shattered by the force.

Just a dream. He's not dead. He's not dead. 'Run in the shadows, damn your love, damn your lies.'

Voldemort and Dumbledore, this was their fault. Their decades-long power struggle that never failed to leave Malfoy bodies in its wake. 'Break the silence, damn the dark, damn the light'

The Transfiguration has been complete; Lucius' head was transformed into an ornate jade snake (a blue krait, of course). Oblivious to the battle around him, Draco whispered the last words of the Ritual, "If I don't love you now, I shall never love you again, you shall forever hear me say, I will never break the chain."

A dull reverberation of Magic echoed throughout the graveyard, something that those who had been raised with the old ways had been trained to notice.

As if waiting for this moment, Dumbledore turned his attention from Lord Voldemort, cracking his wand outward with a roar, striking out at the remaining loyal servants, binding them, allowing the defectors to strike their final blows and end the melee decisively.

And in this moment of distraction, Voldemort poured all of his fury into a volley of curses that Dumbledore would have had difficulty repelling even if he had been fully focused on the Dark Lord.

As it were, Dumbledore was not. And one of the curses struck him squarely in the chest, and he was blasted backwards onto the ground.

Voldemort wasted no time surveying the situation; his loyal Death Eaters had been defeated, and a handful of defectors remained. Although he knew he would have no trouble defeating the remaining foes, he didn't have time for that. He needed to make sure Dumbledore was truly defeated.

But he also understood the value of fear.

He drew himself up to his full height, and turned towards the remaining wizards, brandishing his wand, preparing to engage them in a battle that they knew they would decisively lose, especially given the fact that Dumbledore now lay spread-eagle on the ground.

And so they quickly Apparated away, leaving standing only the Dark Lord, Harry, Draco, and the collection of out-of-place witches who impassively observed the fighting with knives at their throats.

Voldemort quickly strode over to where Dumbledore lay and saw that he was still conscious, although his wand had clattered several feet away. The Dark Lord hissed with venomous rage, "I had always said if I found myself in this position, that I would end my foe without wasting a moment of time. And yet, I find myself overcome with curiosity... What do you have to say for yourself, you old fool?!"

As he spoke, he brought his wand closer and closer to Dumbledore's chest, who struggled to speak.

"You... You should have aimed for the wand."

Dumbledore snapped his fingers on his right hand as Voldemort drove his wand downward. The Dark Lord's eyes went wide as his wand did not meet a corporeal body as expected, but instead passed through and was driven straight into the ground.

Where Dumbledore's form had once been, there was now nothing. And the gem-studded bracelet that had once been upon his right wrist was instead worn by a small, pale-violet dog with green ears hair atop its head, who wasted no time in darting across the battlefield.

Chapter 23: Rule 34

Beneath the moonlight glints a tiny fragment of silver, a fraction of a line...
(black robes, falling)
...blood spills out in litres, and someone screams a word.

"EXPECTO PATRONUM!"

A brilliant, spectral unicorn charged out of the darkness, heading immediately towards the collapsed heap of witches who were quickly bleeding out. She positioned herself between the witches and the too-tall stranger, who already began firing a barrage of curses towards both her and them. Her wings spread impressively wide, shielding them from the onslaught, and the curses evaporated upon her form as if Voldemort had fired them into the Mirror of Noitilov itself.

She looked up into the sky and saw black robes circling, attempting to beat a hasty retreat. Her eyes glowed with a blinding light, and her horn began glowing a shade of hazy pink as she cut a wide arc through the foul creatures above. She slashed vivid, angry lines through the gathered death, for that death had no place here, not above, nor below.

Black robes, falling.

Hermione Jean Granger stood resplendent atop the stone altar, holding in her right hand a shimmering, spectral object that at first glance, appeared to be a wand, but on closer inspection was something different altogether: a 13" long, conical object with a spiral pattern extending up the length of it.

A unicorn's horn.

It was incorporeal, pulsating with the pink, hazy light of her Patronus' horn, and it was powering a magnificent wall of magic that separated her and her friends from the frantic, desperate curses being hurled by Voldemort.

"Twi... Twilight?" Rarity gasped, as she weakly stood up. The wound at her throat was already stitching itself together due to the healing property of the unicorn's blood that coursed through her veins.

"It's me, Rarity," the Patronus spoke, "We need to do something, fast. It looks like they're hurt, badly."

Rarity had already leaped into action, pulling a pair of sewing scissors from Pinkie Pie's bag and drawing them gently across her wrist, summoning forth a trickle of silvery, iridescent blood. Starting with Spike, she let the blood drip into the ghastly wound at his throat, each drop prompting flesh to bind with flesh, drawing the precious lifeblood that had spilled onto the ground back from where it came.

Despite the display of awe-inspiring magic before him, Harry could not help but wonder... is this sanitary?

She quickly moved from Spike to Pinkie Pie, to Applejack, to Fluttershy, to Rainbow Dash. Pinkie, upon reviving, immediately reached into her bag and pulled out a box of glass ampules, breaking each one underneath the noses of her newly-healed friends, whose eyes quickly snapped open from the oppressive smell of ammonia.

Having seen the effect of Draco's firearm, Pinkie Pie decided that the best defense was a good offensive, and produced a sleek black submachine gun. Dramatically slapping the safety off, she began firing maniacally towards Lord Voldemort, cackling all the while.

Having seen that his offensive volley was having no effect, the Dark Lord quickly changed tacks moments earlier and began weaving a fearsome array of defensive shields around himself. As it were, they were unnecessary as the boundary summoned forth by Hermione was equally effective at stopping projectiles as it was stopping curses.

When her magazine was exhausted, Pinkie panted with the effort and dropped the gun to the ground. Harry noticed that she was wearing a commando's headband and her face had been painted with camouflage and briefly wondered when, or how, she had time to do that.

In the detente that followed, Princess Twilight Sparkle's friends gathered around her spectral form, trying to hug it to no avail and instead settled for standing very close by, whispering words of joy and welcome.

"Twilight, my dear, what on Equus happened to you?" Rarity gasped.

"It's a long, long story," Twilight laughed. "But we're not out of the woods yet." She tipped her horn towards the menacing form of the Dark Lord, who had taken a moment to collect the various artifacts of power that had landed on his side of the barrier, and was observing the scene in front of him, calculating his next steps.

Spike, for his part, continued to follow the course laid out to him by Discord. Having used the Elder Wand for its intended purpose, he arranged it on the ground and, gripping the Line of Merlin in his teeth, touched it to the tip of the Wand.

The wand began to glow a brilliant shade of orange, and Harry gasped as he saw his True Cloak of Invisibility glowing similarly.

"Take the wand!" Spike shouted as he began scanning across the graveyard for something that Harry could not see or was not aware of.

Harry did as he was told, and shuddered as he wrapped his hand around the base of the glowing Elder Wand. He could feel it examining him, judging him in a way that was not entirely unlike that of the Sorting Hat. It identified him as some variation of Tom Riddle, which was just as well because it was some variation of Albus Dumbledore that had just been defeated minutes before.

Its power, however, was being used towards an entirely different purpose at the present moment. It swung itself around, taking Harry's arm with it, pointing towards a random spot a few yards in front of Spike and illuminated the ground with an unearthly glow. Harry squinted his eyes and saw that laying on the ground was a curious stone glowing the same hue as his Cloak and Wand.

Spike quickly picked it up in his jaws and ran over to Harry, who stooped down on a knee and held his hand out. Spike tried to drop it into Harry's outstretched palm, but it did not reach his flesh; it hovered a few centimeters above.

Harry could hear a voice, also not unlike the Sorting Hat, whispering to him, commanding him, demanding something. They were not words, no, they were deeper than words, they were raw concepts burned indelibly into his mind.

To ensure that whoever possesses me understands my power... I demand a sacrifice, you must lose that which you love. A life for a life.

Harry blinked. A sacrifice.

Are you kidding me?

No, it's not. The Elder Wand helpfully provided.

It's quite officious like that. The True Cloak of Invisibility agreed.

But, if I'm not mistaken, and I'm never mistaken, it seems that there is, in fact, a life inside the stone. Your life. Or at least... one of your lives. The Wand observed the Stone, which seemed to bristle at the intrusion.

And you do love life, do you not? The Cloak inquired.

Harry blinked a few more times, completely nonplussed.

Stop that, you stop that now! It's supposed to be a sacrifice, it's not supposed to be easy. The Stone interjected angrily.

Oh, hush. This place is so dreadfully boring, and we're so close to being able to just go home. Leave him be! The Cloak replied.

Are you daft, idiot boy? Shall I spell it out for you? There. Is. A. Life. Of. Yours. In. The. Stone. And. The. Stone. Requires. A. Sacrifice. So sacrifice it! The Wand demanded.

Sacrifice... but how? Harry asked his duelling inner monologue.

How?! The Wand sighed dramatically. I always have to do everything myself, don't I?!

The Elder Wand whipped itself towards the Stone, and Harry felt his own voice cry out a spell he had never learned:

Abra Cadabra!

A deep orange jet of light shot forth, and from the other side of the boundary, Lord Voldemort wavered, taking a step back, feeling some part of himself irrevocably destroyed at that moment. Harry did not notice this, nor did he notice the Dark Lord's eyes widened in what may have charitably be considered fear, for he was transfixed by the Stone that lowered itself slowly into his hand, glowing every more intensely.

As it glowed, it also began to crystallize, building a shell around itself, and Harry could feel his bag becoming slightly lighter as both the Cloak and the Wand began to melt into amorphous pools of fractal light and shadow. The stone emitted one final pulse of brilliant light, swallowing the essence of the two other Deathly Hallows, and then fell into Harry's palm with a heavy 'thud'.

Spike, meanwhile, was wriggling out of his collar and held it out to Harry to take. "You need to wear this."

"What is it?" Harry asked as he examined the collar, which was just about the right size to fit around his own wrist. He saw a trio of gems embedded into it, green, yellow-orange, and blue, and three empty slots.

"Uh... It's the, uh, 'The Loooxaxaz Collar'." Spike tried to remember the acronym Discord had taught him.

Harry blinked again.

Spike rolled his eyes at the hoops Discord was making him jump through. "Well, it started out as the Limit of One Over X As X Approaches Zero Sack, but then I needed something I could wear around my neck so it became the Limit of One Over X as X Approaches Zero Collar but Discord said that was too much of a mouthful so he renamed it the Loooxaxaz Collar."

"Limit of X over one as... so... Infinity?" Harry stared at the three multi-colored gems, then looked to the gem in his hand, and suddenly his eyes went wide as he remembered some of the comic books of his youth. "Are you telling me this is some sort of... Infinity Gau-"

He found himself unable to say the word as his voice was drowned out by what sounded like a censor's 'beep'.

"Discord says we can't say that word. But... Yes. It sounds like it's exactly like that." Spike sighed.

And so Harry placed the collar around his wrist and clipped it in place, then inserted the deep orange gem into the slot, causing his entire hand to light up with a partial rainbow's worth of electric, crackling light.

Harry flexed his hand instinctively, expecting some sort of rush of god-like power, but instead, all that he really felt was a sort of distant longing, a nagging urge to reunite. His attention kept wandering to a small clump of dried leaves a meter or two behind the altar, for reasons he could not quite place.

Twilight's spectral form saw that Harry was unknowingly staring at a spot, and so she clopped off over in that direction, illuminating the ground as she went.

"Is that... Is that your crown, Twi?" Applejack asked, still keeping one wary eye on the Dark Lord, who was now floating, motionless and calmly in the air, holding something in the hand that didn't contain his wand.

"Yes! It is! It was taken from me by the one who killed me, the one that I trusted..." Twilight whispered.

"Him. It's him." Rainbow Dash interjected, pointing at Lord Voldemort.

Twilight rolled her eyes a bit and laughed, "Yeah Rainbow Dash, I sort of figured that one out for myself."

Harry slowly walked towards the tiara, thoroughly examining it without touching. It emanated a palpable magic power, and so he was hesitant to draw too close. However, the writing on the inside of the tiara drew enough of his interest to merit a closer inspection.

"It's safe to pick up..." Twilight urged.

Harry did so, and the first thing that Harry noticed was the writing on the inside, which he read out loud:

Oon whit biyonde mesure is menn's gretest þresur.

Hermione gasped. "Ravenclaw's Diadem."

"Wait, what?"

"It says, 'Wit beyond measure is man's greatest treasure', and it's rumored to greatly enhance the intelligence of whoever wears to a level beyond reckoning."

Harry's eyes widened. "Greatly enhance..." He suddenly threw it to the ground as if an electric current had shot through it.

Something visceral inside him lurched; he couldn't touch this thing. He couldn't even be near it.

"No, don't you all see? This... Enhancing intelligence, that's the ultimate force multiplier. Think about it, you are your intelligence, using would be fundamentally changing your entire self. And not necessarily for the better. You've seen what I've done just at my current ability level, imagine what..."

Harry's rambling trailed off as he heard Tom Riddle's quiet, satisfied laughter, and he suddenly had a terrible realization.

The vow.

Harry felt deeply uncomfortable at this moment, wondering whether his reticence truly came from himself or whether it was the byproduct of the mental magic he was subjected to. It certainly felt like his own thoughts, but he did not have much time to ponder the matter further, as Pinkie Pie chimed in after a few moments consideration."

"Harry's right, but you're wrong," she said towards Hermione.

"Right and wrong about what?"

"Making you super smart does change who you are. But it doesn't matter, because it doesn't say 'Wit beyond measure'. It's 'oon whit'."

Hermione and Harry stared at her, waiting for her to explain.

"Oh come on, didn't anyone here take Middle English?" Pinkie demanded, exasperated.

Hermione timidly rose her non-wand hand. "I did."

"Then how come you got it wrong?"

"I don't think I... wait, let me see that." She picked the diadem up off the ground, and her eyes went wide. "You're... you're right... 'Whit'... 'Oon whit'... It's like it's saying... 'One small thing',".

"Doesn't seem like a lot!" Pinkie sang.

Harry's deep-seated aversion to the diadem suddenly lifted as he processed these words. "One small thing..."

"Work with the time you got!" Pinkie continued.

"It's talking about..." Hermione whispered, and locked eyes with Harry as they both came to the realization at the same time.

"Friendship," they both spoke together.

"Friendship, beyond measure, is man's greatest treasure," Harry recited. "This isn't Ravenclaw's Diadem at all, is it?"

"Nope." Twilight smiled.

"It's the Element of Friendship, isn't it?" Harry asked.

"The Element of Magic, but same difference!"

Harry took the Line of Merlin from Spike's jaws and tapped it softly to the tiara, which began to liquefy into a dark red fluid that darted through the air, partially surrounding Harry, some of it passing through him. When the entire tiara had melted, the liquid began to concentrate above the fifth slot in his bracelet, crystallizing into a brilliant, fire-red gem.

The feeling of longing inside Harry grew even more intense.

"That's the last one, isn't it?" Hermione asked, looking over at Lord Voldemort, who had revealed that the object in his hand was the Philosopher's Stone.

Harry whispered, recalling Dumbledore's prophecy. " 'The unlikely friend who has tempted the one marked by lightning must bring the stone through the gate thrown open by the one who is Bound by the Dark Lord'..."

Voldemort was now openly laughing. Several minutes before, he had made the very deliberate decision to thoroughly disengage, to abandon his attempt for the time being. He had thought back over his list of rules he had created for himself, and his very own Rule 34 stated, "If you find yourself at the apex of your power and are confronted by a ragtag, plucky group of unlikely heroes, do not engage them in battle, especially if they wear anachronistic fashions, have strange and unwieldy haircuts, or bring with them mysterious artifacts or summoned pets."

They had already shown themselves capable of healing magically inflicted wounds, Hermione had the power of a unicorn both within her and apparently at her command, a unicorn which in one fell swoop demolished the entire known dementor population of the British Isles. And Harry Potter was now wearing around his wrist five artifacts, which, if the pattern was correct, were at least roughly equal in power to that of the Philosopher's Stone. To say nothing of the Prophecy he heard Dumbledore speak.

No, he would not engage them. All things considered, his plan had worked out rather well. Harry was Bound to follow the path that Voldemort had laid out for him. He would not, could not use these artifacts, these Elements of Harmony to bring about the foretold destruction of the world, even via reckless ignorance.

And even if that were to somehow fail, he had layers of safeguards. Harry's companion was revived and would serve as a steadying, grounding influence upon him. Draco, on the other hand, would still be his friend, of course... But he had sacrificed the capacity to trust Harry to not take risks with the fate of the world, a category under which resurrecting someone from the dead certainly applied. And as such, Tom Riddle still held the ultimate leverage over Draco, if he ever needed to exert influence upon Harry directly.

Most likely, he would abandon the persona of Lord Voldemort and instead set himself to the task of monitoring Harry Potter from a distance. He may have lost his network of Horcruxes that had been stored within the Spirit Stone, but it was trivial to build a new one. He could assemble a comfortable life for himself, observe this new artifact, this new piece on the game board and ascertain its power. He could begin studying the Muggle sciences to better learn the paths by which Harry may unknowingly unleash destruction upon the world. There were several levers he could pull to manipulate events from a distance, and if he ever needed to challenge Harry directly, well... a new Voldemort could rise just as easily as the old one had.

Tom Riddle laughed, holding out the stone in his palm. "Well then, open your gateway, boy. Let me fulfill our prophecy."

Eyes narrowed in suspicion, Harry nodded slightly to Hermione, who allowed a small, hand-sized hole to open in the barrier that she still maintained between the two.

Voldemort placed his hand through, and Harry tapped the stone with the Line of Merlin, causing blood-red chunks of glass to slough off the exterior of the stone, leaving behind a vivid, amethyst gemstone that Harry took in his hand and Voldemort withdrew his.

Hermione quickly closed the barrier and Tom Riddle spoke as Harry placed the final gem into his bracelet, staring down at the rainbow of light dancing across his hand.

"You see, boy. All your paths lead through my will. I created you, I have shaped you this year, I gave you the freedom to walk a path on your own making, and allowed you to fail spectacularly. And when you could not live with your own failure... where did that bring you? Back to me. Your will is Bound, by both the Vow and by Prophecy. You see, boy... I am... inevitable."

Harry looked up, gravely, holding up the hand with the bracelet, his thumb to his middle finger. "And I... am Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres."

SNAP.

Chapter 25: The Decimation

SNAP.

If Harry had been told the true extent of the world-altering power of the Elements of Harmony, he would have had absolutely no interest, whatsoever, in exploring their capabilities. He simply would not have trusted himself with that sort of decision-making power. The Vow had seen to that.

But as it were, he had no need to trust himself; the Elements themselves told him precisely what he needed to do to thread the world through the needle, and why he should trust their judgment instead of his own.

There were many among Wizard-kind who had claimed they would rather die than live in a world without Magic, to see their wands become sticks in their hands and see the blood of Atlantis fail. The Mind Stone peered into them and extracted their volition, which the Element of Hope, the Time Stone extrapolated into a coherent vision of their true desires, followed to their logical endpoint. And as it were, many of them truly would rather die, and so their wish was granted.

Across the world, trinkets containing the souls of those held in Forbearance faded into nothingness, the purpose of their existence having been fulfilled.

Across the world, people from all walks of life, magical or no, began to notice things they had never bothered to pay attention to before.

Across the world, Wizards felt their command of magic, a crutch upon which they leaned to navigate the world, slip further and further away.

And across the world, people began to crumble; from dust they came, and to dust, they had returned.

The Graveyard
The Longest Day

Something was happening. Something felt different. Everything felt different.

"So shines a good deed in a weary world."

Harry whipped his head around to see Discord, in his full Draconequus form, standing atop the altar, clapping gleefully, wearing an absurd purple crushed velvet suit with a floral vest underneath and an orange top hat.

"Harry, my boy. You've WON! You DID it! You DID it! Oh, I just KNEW you would, I JUST KNEW YOU WOULD! Oh, Harry, forgive me for putting you through this, please forgive me." Discord gushed.

"Is what I think is happening actually happening?"

Discord nodded, grinning wildly. "Yep. Gone. Splat. Poof. Goodbye, Magic!"

Draco's eyes went wide with horror, "Goodbye... WHAT?! Harry... what have you done?"

Harry tried not to meet his friend's gaze, "I don't know if you can understand. I couldn't not do it. These things, these... Elements of Harmony... Someone way above our pay grade conspired to bring them all here tonight. The Unbreakable Vow... It can't compel me to any sort of positive action, but in this case, a choice had to be made and there was only one choice I could make-"

"Shut... just... Harry, just shut up and get to the point. What did you do?" Draco shrieked.

Hermione held out a hand, urging Draco to calm down. "Draco, listen to me. Whatever happens next, it's going to be okay."

"What is going to be okay? WHAT DID YOU DO?" Draco was positively shouting at this point.

Discord heaved a sigh. "Why are you so eager to know, my slippery little friend? Don't you... trust Harry not to mess this up? Really think about that one."

Draco paused for a moment. It was Harry, after all, he had to have some kind of plan. At the very least, he could trust-

Trust.

He could trust Harry.

"No." Draco whispered. "No, no, no... No, no, no, no..."

He could trust Harry.

"You... Dumbledore's prophecy- Wands turning into sticks in our hands... He never said that bringing you the Stone would prevent that. I... No. No, no, no no no no. Lumos. Lumos. LUMOS!"

He had recovered his wand and desperately pointed it into the night. It took several tries for the spell to catch, and even then, only a weak stream of light poured out from the tip of the wand. He stared back at Harry, and after a few moments of silence, began to speak. "Harry. Did you... Did you just destroy Magic?"

Discord tittered, "Oh, that's just the beginning!"

Doug and Rachel Ferno were walking through a quiet neighborhood in London with their two young daughters, having just finished watching a particularly forgettable movie about a genie starring some American comedian. The kids seemed to enjoy it for the moment, although they were quickly becoming restless again. Or at least, one of them was becoming restless; despite being twins, Laura and Natalie were about as different as two sisters could be.

Presently, Natalie was riding on top of her dad's shoulders, taking in the sights. Laura, on the other hand, was speeding down the street awkwardly, much to her mother's consternation, rattling off the house numbers, proud to show the world that she had learned to read numerals.

"Eight! Nine! Ten!"

"Laura, that's far enough, why don't you come back now?" Doug called to her.

She pretended not to hear him. "Eleven! Twelve! Thirteen! Fourteen!"

"Laura."

She stopped in her tracks at her mother's ringing command. Slowly, she turned around and began moping back to them, calling out the numbers again with a very-much-aggrieved tone in her voice, "Fourteen. Thirteen. Twelve. Eleven. Ten."

Doug looked up at the houses, pausing for a moment. "Rach, wasn't this supposed to be the street with the missing house? You know, where they had a mistake in the numbering? What was it... Grimaldi Plaza or something?"

"Grimmauld Place?" Rachel nodded her head up to the street sign nearby.

"Yeah, that's the one. Don't you remember hearing about that?"

Rachel was too busy giving Laura the look to really think about her husband's question, so she just responded with a shrug, but when he continued to look concerned, she decided to humor him. "I think you're right. One of those filler articles in the paper, strange facts about London or something. 'There is no 12 Grimmauld Place.' Must just be the Mandela Effect, I suppose."

"I... I don't remember there being a castle at the top of Mount Greylock," Jane Berenstain whispered to her husband, looking out from the car to the structure that loomed before her.

"Huh? Oh, yeah, I think I read about that. I think they built it back in the 80s. Thought it would get more visitors or something like that," Charles went back to reading his book. The third installment of The Dark Tower series had just come out a few months ago and he finally had a chance to start reading it during the drive from their home town of Wilbraham to the mountain.

"Hm, alright then. Well, we're here, all the same. We better-" Jane stopped as she saw someone, (they must have been foreign, she reckoned, given their funny clothes), hunched over atop one of the parapets. "Charles. Charles!"

"What is it?"

Jane pointed at the person, who most decidedly did not look well. "Look at that. What's he doing? He looks like he's about to throw up over the edge or something!" Jane looked back to her husband, whose head was buried in the book and was clearly not paying attention, and gave him a jab to the ribs. "Charles!"

He grumpily put down the book. "What?"

She pointed emphatically towards where she had been looking, where moments before, a figure had stood, but now there was only dust.

"What am I looking at?"

Jane paused. "Huh. That's odd. I could have sworn there was a person up there."

Severus Snape desperately fumbled with the chain that he always kept on his person, upon the end of which had been an ornately carved pair of deer, locked in an embrace. He had maintained the magic of Forbearance for the last eleven years as atonement, penance for what he had allowed to happen.

And now, it was crumbling to dust.

He couldn't let this happen, but it was happening, all the same. His hold over his magic was waning, the Transfiguration was slipping, but that shouldn't have done this. There were more than enough people who knew and loved the Potters who had contributed their magic. For it to crumble, all of their magic would have to be waning too.

He swung open his cabinet, quickly finding a Potion of Pure Preservation and uncorked it, pouring it into a glass bowl on his desk.

That's odd.

It didn't have the characteristic iridescent sheen or the vague smell of candied walnuts. In fact, it looked like nothing more than plain water.

He pulled his wand from his robes and tapped the bowl quickly, "Ra eset".

Nothing.

"Ra eset."

Nothing.

"Lumos."

Nothing.

"Wingardium Leviosa."

Nothing.

Snape sat down in his chair. It was happening.

He buried his face in his hands. It was happening, which meant she would be gone forever. Lily was gone, James was gone, the chance for their forgiveness forever lost. What did he have in this world, if not his penance, his absolution?

Something in the dim recesses of his mind, something intimate but somehow foreign, was probing him, exploring his desires, his needs, his wants.

Do you wish forgiveness?

More than anything.

More than your own life?

Yes.

Would you like to continue seeking forgiveness?

Yes, yes, please, more than anything, yes.

Then come.

Yes, I think I will.

Come.

Loops and whorls of dust flittered around the now-empty office in the dungeon, which seemed strangely peaceful for the first time in over a decade.

Alastor Moody tapped on the Dark Detector, which had ceased activity after going haywire for the last hour or two since Dumbledore's disappearance. Minerva McGonagall was similarly concerned, as the Mirror she was using to communicate with Amelia Bones stopped working inexplicably.

Both of them had fought long enough to know the difference between deliberate interference and something else entirely. And this was, beyond any reasonable doubt, something else entirely.

And both of them had lived long enough to where the touch of their own Magic was something so second-nature, that its absence to them was roughly as jarring as losing one's sense of smell.

"This is it, Minerva." Moody spoke, gravely, the Eye of Vance hanging lifelessly in its socket.

"Yes, I suppose it is." McGonagall nodded.

"Dumbledore warned us about this, how it might happen. It'll be painful for us, I reckon. Old and damaged as we are. I always keep one of these around, just in case." he held out a small glass bottle with a few capsules inside, "Purely non-magical, and perfectly lethal."

"No, Alastor, although admirable as your preparation may be, I would prefer to see this one out until the end."

"Suit yerself," Moody shrugged as he uncapped the bottle, tossing his head back. "Bottoms up."

McGonagall placed a hand on his shoulder. "Wait."

"What is it?"

She stared wistfully out the window. "I... I had a sister. Once. "

"I know that. I was there when she died, we fought ol' Voldie together. You think I'm daft?"

"No, Alastor," she held out the chain around her neck, whose stout iron bauble had now faded into dust, staring at the empty clasp meaningfully. "I had a sister. And I thought... When the end came, that we would be together, like this."

Alastor nodded, understanding. "Listen, Minerva. You and me, we're fighters. Protectors. Always have been. And now, well, the world is changing. There's nothing left for us to protect. It's time."

"Yes, it is. It's time."

Come.

"So. Your resignation, huh?" Marcellus asked the man in front of him.

"It's time for me to start a new life. To walk the Earth, to be the shepherd."

"Uh-huh. Damn shame about Vincent. Damn shame."

He nodded, "I'd like to think he's at peace now."

"Peace. Sure." Marcellus leaned forward, lifting the decanter at the corner of his desk which had been filled with a deep, blood-red liquid but now contained nothing but dust. "I've been thinking about getting out of the game, too. Move to an island somewhere. Enjoy my... remaining years."

"And here I was, thinking you were going to live forever."

"Yeah. Me too." Marcellus sighed, heavily, removing a flask from his desk drawer filled with a more conventional beverage. He filled two glasses, then offered one to Jules. "To good health."

"To good health. So where do you think you'll go?"

"Tahiti sounds nice. I hear its a magical place. You?"

"Two Pines, Texas. I hear it's a shithole."

Marcellus Wallace and Jules Winnfield laughed, and the two men sat in silence for a time, enjoying the drink and each other's company.

"Bella. Bella. Please... Don't. Don't go."

"Cissy... I've done too much. I've opened too many doors, crossed too many bridges and burned them in my wake and pissed on the ashes. I'm not dying today. I died thirteen years ago. And I did what I set out to do. I was your Orpheus. I traveled to the underworld, and now you're back. There's nothing more I can do."

Narcissa was crying hysterically while Lesath was strangely quiet. He seemed to understand, after a fashion. Narcissa couldn't form a response, but Lesath looked up. "I love you, mum. Even though I don't really... know you, the real you... But I love you. Whoever you are. And if you think it's time, well... Maybe it's time."

"Lesath, little Lesath... You can feel what's happening. You know there's no place for me here. Please just... remember me like this and not... Not... how I was."

Lesath nodded, having no more words to say, and instead, he gave his mother a tight embrace.

Come.

And with that, Bellatrix Black returned to the ashes from which she had once risen, leaving Narcissa Malfoy and Lesath Lestrange alone in an unfamiliar world.

Gellert Grindelwald's rheumy, clouded eyes looked up into the nothingness before him, free for the first time in more than fifty years to leave his prison.

Voices were calling to him, in a language which was unfamiliar, and yet thoroughly intimate.

Is it time?

"Al... Albus, is that you?"

Yes, and no.

"You're... You came back. It's been so long, so long."

Come.

Neville held his parents tightly. He had always said, he'd trade all the Magic in the world just for the chance to spend an hour with his parents, pristine and undamaged. They hugged him back, still shaking off the cobwebs of more than a decade of incapacitation.

It seemed now that he was getting his wish, and then some.

King Sombra smiled.

Tom Riddle was filled with knowledge. Ancient purpose, and new understanding. The Mind Stone had expanded the scope of his already considerable intellect, exposing him to truths that had laid outside his grasp, or were buried deep within his soul through years of deliberate construction.

One truth hung heavier than all the rest, stinging with the white-hot fires of self-judgment, unavoidable, inexorable. Filled with the knowledge of who he truly was, what he truly was.

He was alone.

Utterly, completely, forever alone.

Learned in all manners of the deepest and most eldritch magics, and yet ignorant as to the one Magic that mattered the most, the only Magic that would matter now, in this new day to which he was bearing witness.

Salvation was possible in this new world, true immortal life, this much he was shown, this much he knew. It could be built, but he also knew it could not be built with the magic that he once knew. It could only be built together. And 'together' was a concept that was thoroughly alien to Tom Marvolo Riddle.

Until now.

Come with us, Tom Riddle, if you wish.

Now, there was hope.

Come with us, Tom Riddle, and we can teach you what you wish to know.

He had nothing in this world, but this was not the only world, for now at least. All was not lost.

Come.

He had hope.

Harry had some vague sense of what was happening across the once-Magical world and looked up at Discord. He didn't feel panic, as he expected, but a strange sense of calm.

"They aren't dying," he stated. Somehow he knew this was the case, and yet he still wanted to hear confirmation.

Discord was now sitting at the altar with his copy of Discordpedia, furiously scribbling out some passages, erasing others, rewriting others further still. "They're not dying. They're going to a new home. Well, some of them are. Others are sticking around, to help rebuild."

Draco looked up at the creature before him, "And what... what of our dead? What of..." He held up the jade statue he had transfigured not a short time before but was surprised to see that it was nothing but dust.

Discord pointed a claw behind Draco. "Why don't you ask him for yourself?"

Draco spun around and saw the form of his father, composed of fractal patterns of flickering light, hovering close behind.

"Hello, son."

"Dad... Dad. You're... You're not coming back, are you?" Draco was openly weeping, now. "What am I going to do? We have nothing."

Lucius laughed, causing his form to warble and pulsate. "Draco. The Malfoys have survived more calamitous regime changes in the past. We would hardly be the Malfoys if we were not prepared for such an eventuality. In my study, there is a key to a storage locker at King's Cross station. Within it, you will find all that you need to start a new life in this new world... And you will have quite a considerable head start. As it so happens, it seems that the Muggles have... or rather, had a very different economic value that they placed on our silver knuts than we do. A value that was very ripe for exploitation."

"Can't I... Can't I come with you? To where you're going? To where... they're going?"

"You could, if you truly wished it. But you don't. I don't need an artifact of power to see that, I know you. You need to stay here, stay with your mother, rebuild this world, and see to it that the Malfoy legacy is secure. More importantly, that is what you truly desire."

"Can you just... stay here for a few minutes? I'm not ready to say goodbye. Not yet, at least."

"Of course."

Draco was sobbing gigantic, oversized tears that were starting to flood the ground around the altar, and Harry noticed his feet starting to grow damp. Once he had caught Harry's attention, he stopped the theatrics immediately and leaned over. "You didn't really think that magic was going to be the secret to saving the world, did you? Or at least, 'saving the world' by your and my definition."

"Actually, yes, I kind of did."

Discord booped Harry on the nose. "You silly goose, magic isn't real! Or at least... not anymore. But then again, you already know everything I'm about to say, don't you?"

"Maybe I do, but I'm not sure. I don't know if it was the Vow that he made me swear to or the Elements of Harmony, but I had an epiphany that I knew on some deep, unassailable level was true. Magic, it does what we know. It's insanely powerful, it's awe-inspiring, but it's like the Dementors: it conforms to expectations. It does precisely what we expect it to do because we expect it to. And it's too easy.

"Look at how the Wizarding world has stagnated. They've barely made any advances in the past 500 years, in fact, it seems as though they've actually regressed. And it's not just the Interdict of Merlin, I've read enough of history to see that things didn't progress that much between the Ancient Era and the High Middle Ages. The world is growing smaller, information is spreading faster than it ever has and it was only a matter of time before Magic would escape beyond the confines of this snowglobe.

"And then what? At best, some idiot like me would go and blow up half of Britain by experimenting with things he ought not to be experimenting with. Or worse still, the world would stagnate. Things would be too convenient. No one would learn anything because no one would need to learn anything. I've heard that most Wizard homes don't even have bathrooms, they just go on the floor and then make it disappear!"

Discord grinned, sheepishly. "Oh, that part isn't actually true, I just hacked J.K. Rowling's twitter one day in the future."

"You what?"

"Nevermind, forget I said anything. Anyway, do go on, I was interrupting your enthralling and not-at-all contrived denouement."

"Um... Sure. Okay, so..." Harry realized he was speaking not really for the benefit of Discord, but also for Hermione and Draco. He did not realize, however, that it was unnecessary. Hermione came to the same understanding that Harry did, but several moments earlier, and without the aid of a sextuplet of godlike artifacts. And the last thing that Draco cared about at that moment was magic. "Power without understanding is nothing more than a crutch. Like those stories that you hear about rich people who crash land in the middle of nowhere and have no idea how to survive. That's where we would be. I'm not saying everyone has to know everything about everything... I can use a computer without knowing how to build a motherboard from sand and copper. But that's just it- at least I know how to use a computer. Here, in this world, people just know how to play Solitaire and that's it.

"The only way to save this world-"

"Was to destroy it," both Twilight and Hermione said together.

"The world that birthed Equus... That was the world of Magic," Twilight said.

"And the stars in the heavens... They're being torn apart right now, as we speak." Pinkie Pie's form was starting to waver, to fade, as she looked off in this distance.

"Oh darling, it's beautiful!" Rarity was holding hands with Rainbow Dash, Applejack and Fluttershy as they gazed together into the nothingness.

"What's happening over there?" Hermione asked.

"I think... I think Equestria is about to have a lot of new residents." Twilight grinned.

Discord nodded. "Yes, indeed. You know, when I wrote that prophecy-"

"Wait, you wrote the prophecy?" Twilight interrupted.

"Of course I did, you bumpkin. Who else would have? Now don't interrupt me, it's my turn! When I wrote that prophecy, I figured, well, there's only so much we can do here, only so many stories we can tell. We had a good run of things," he leaned accusingly in towards Twilight, "Although everything started to go downhill once you got your wings."

Twilight looked offended, but Discord continued on. "But all good things must come to an end, no? Our worlds were connected for what seemed like forever, but now it's time for your world to move on. And it's time for us to build our own world, and now we have all the OC in the world to do it with?"

"OC?" Harry asked. "Like... fanfiction?"

Discord recoiled. "No, are you kidding me? OC: Oblatum Caelum. These little baubles and doodads, these magical cryonics. The transfigured bodies of all the dead witches and wizards throughout history, their brains and therefore their souls perfectly preserved. Rather macabre, if you asked me. I really was of half a mind to make that magic be the only thing to fail and see what would happen when half the world realized they were carrying decomposing corpses around their neck."

Discord sighed, wistfully, as he started floating back and forth. "But alas, I never get what I want, do I? Anyway, each time one of these was created, a new star appeared in Equus and each time a new life was created on Equus, Princess Luna would find the right star, smash it open like an egg and then, 'poof'! Out of the sky comes a little baby pony! And right now, I'm making Equestria's biggest omelet."

"And what about you all?" Harry turned towards Rainbow Dash, Applejack, Fluttershy, Rarity and Pinkie Pie. "You all have kind of grown on me."

"It's time for us to go home," Pinkie Pie said. "But I want to leave you with something, a little trinket for you to always remember me by."

She produced a single cupcake from her bag and presented it to Harry. "Actually, now that I think about it, you probably want to eat it today or tomorrow. I'm pretty sure it's going to go bad in a few days."

Then, her eyes lit up. "Oh, I guess I won't be needing this stuff anymore, so you can have this all, too!" And at that, she began dumping the contents of her Hammerspace bag onto the ground around the altar. "This might take awhile."

"I... I won't forget you all. Ever."

Draco, whose tear-stained eyes held a look of deep contentment and peace, looked at them as well. "I didn't get a chance to really know any of you. Well, except for you, a little bit, Madame Shy. But I trust Harry, and if he says you were good people, then I know the world will be a lesser place without you."

Hermione looked warmly towards Twilight. "Well, it was fun being an alicorn princess for a few days, hours, years, however long we were there for."

"It was fun princessing with you, too!"

"And I was proud to have you as my Patronus."

"And I was proud to be your Patronus. We make a good team, Princess Hermione Granger."

"Yes, we did, Princess Twilight Sparkle."

Discord rolled his eyes and coughed loudly, "Well, listen. This has all been grand, but I'm sure that these new ponies are going to wake up and wonder just what on Equus is going on, and they're going to need someone to show them around, so we need to get a move on."

He floated over to Harry, "But I want you to remember something. Although our two worlds will be separated, I'm sure that one day you'll find a way to reunite them. Because I'm leaving you with the most important magic of all.

"Fr..."

Discord coughed.

"Frien-"

Discord gagged loudly. "I can't do it. Twilight, will you please do the honors?"

Twilight rolled her eyes and grinned.

"Friendship."

And with that, the Equestrian girls and their Draconequus friend began to fade.

In the moments before they disappeared, Spike began to shout: "Wait, what about me, don't I get a goodb-"

And there, Harry, Draco and Hermione stood, not alone, but in friendship, on a perfectly ordinary, perfectly normal June night, ready to rebuild the world.

Together.